Why is your YouTube channel working so well
व्हाई इज योर YouTube चैनल वर्किंग सो वेल
in 2025? people think that this is an overnight
इन 2025? पीपल थिंक दैट दिस इज एन ओवरनाइट
success that i got 3 million subscribers
सक्सेस कि आई गट 3 मिलियन सब्सक्राइबर्स
In just a year of doing YouTube? no it
इन जस्ट अ ईयर ऑफ़ डूइंग YouTube? नो इट्स
Very difficult to do what I am doing. it's
वेरी डिफिकल्ट टू डू व्हाट आई डूइंग। इट्स
One of the best content creators in the
वन ऑफ़ द बेस्ट कंटेंट क्रिएटर्स इन द
Country Today. Very grateful to be here.
कंट्री टुडे। वैरी ग्रेटफुल टू बी हियर।
I feel you can go to any place and capture the
आई फील यू कैन गो टू प्लेस एंड कैप्चर दी
essence very well and translate it into
एसेंस वेरी वेल एंड ट्रांसलेट इट इंटू
Screen. what I do is not at all
स्क्रीन। व्हाट आई डू इज नॉट एट आल
ReplicaCable. We Allocate at Rs 1.5 Lakh
रेप्लिककेबल। वी एलोकेट 1.5 लाख पर
Video. you need to be a little crazy too
वीडियो। यू नीड टू बी लिटिल क्रेजी टू
Grow as a content creator.
ग्रो एस अ कंटेंट क्रिएट।
Video of Imagine India's Biggest Desert
इमेजिन इंडियास बिगेस्ट डेजर्ट की वीडियो
are doing it. literally the temperature said 50
कर रहे हैं। लिटरली द टेंपरेचर सेड 50
Degrees and we were on the ground. Worked
डिग्रीज एंड वी वर ऑन द ग्राउंड। वर्क्ड
On videos which are like wettest place.
ऑन वीडियोस व्हिच आर लाइक वेटेस्ट प्लेस।
We went to Dharavi. we spend five days
वी वेंट टू धारावी। वी स्पेंड फाइव डेज़
There and every day we realise that.
देयर एंड एवरी डे वी रिलाइज डेट।
Feel you are able to get the soul of your place
फील यू आर एबल टू गेट द सोल ऑफ़ योर प्लेस
Transferred into your videos. I Wood Se
ट्रांसफर्ड इंटू योर वीडियोज़। आई वुड से
Don't.
डोंट।
You face trouble? Yes. a lot of the times you
यू फेस ट्रबल? यस। अ लॉट ऑफ़ द टाइम्स यू
Who's gone on the field? five men came started
हू गॉन ऑन फील्ड। फाइव मेन केम स्टार्टेड
deleting all the videos and started
डिलीटिंग ऑल द वीडियोस एंड स्टार्टेड
Beating the shoot out of my videographer. only
बीटिंग द शूट आउट ऑफ़ माय वीडियोग्राफर। ही
Was a man. which i also think is the
वाज़ अ मैन। व्हिच आय आल्सो थिंक इज द
Barriers to entry for a lot of women
बैरियर टू एंट्री फॉर अ लॉट ऑफ़ वीमेन
Because doing that isn't easy. I Just Fear
बिकॉज़ डूइंग दैट इज नॉट इज़। आई जस्ट फियर
that there will be a day, where everything will
दैट देयर विल बी अ डे, वेयर एववरीथिंग विल
Break down, and that's a deep fear I have
ब्रेक डाउन, एंड दैट्स अ डीप फियर आई हाव
because i derive a lot of my senses of
बिकॉज़ आई डिराइव अ लॉट ऑफ़ माय सेंस ऑफ़
Identity from my work.
आइडेंटिटी फ्रॉम माय वर्क।
[music]
[संगीत]
every single year we do one isolated
एव्री सिंगल ईयर वी डू वन आइसोलेटेड
Podcast with a content creator on The Ranveer
पॉडकास्ट वि अ कंटेंट क्रिएटर ऑन द रणवीर
Show and every year content creation as a
शो एंड एव्री ईयर कंटेंट क्रिएशन एज अ
The subject keeps evolving the guess today is
सब्जेक्ट कीप्स इवॉल्विंग द गेस टुडे इज
One of the best content creators in our
वन ऑफ द बेस्ट कंटेंट क्रिएटर्स इन आवर
Country in 2025 She Goes by the Name of
कंट्री इन 2025 शी गोज़ बाय द नेम ऑफ़
Kavya Karnataka and KK Creates I Believe
काव्या कर्नाटक और केके क्रिएट्स आई बिलीव
That She Understands Modern Day Social
दैट शी अंडरस्टैंड्स मॉडर्न डे सोशल
The media is better than everyone else from this
मीडिया बेटर देन एवरीवन एल्स फ्रॉम दिस
Current Generation of Content Creators in Saying
करंट जनरेशन ऑफ कंटेंट क्रिएटर्स इन सेइंग
saying that this particular episode is
सेइंग दैट दिस पर्टिकुलर एपिसोड इज
Created for content creators all over the
क्रिएटेड फॉर कंटेंट क्रिएटर्स ऑल ओवर द
World. kavya karnataka is india's best
वर्ल्ड। काव्या कर्नाटक इज़ इंडियास बेस्ट
Young Content Creator In My Eyes. Mother
यंग कंटेंट क्रिएटर इन माई आईज। माई
Personal Favorite Thing About Her Is That She
पर्सनल फेवरेट थिंग अबाउट हर इज़ ड्यात शी
Is Incredible When It Comes to the Business
इज़ इनक्रेडिबल व्हेन इट कम्स टू द बिज़नेस
That side of things is well. personally over the
साइड ऑफ़ थिंग्स एस वेल। पर्सनली ओवर द
Last 10 years of this job. I have
लास्ट 10 इयर्स ऑफ़ दिस जॉब। आई हैव
Created five businesses myself. and I
क्रिएटेड फाइव बिज़नेसेस माइसेल्फ। एंड आई
I am actively involved in all of these
एम एक्टिवली इनवॉल्व्ड इन ऑल ऑफ़ दोज़
Businesses. Across all these businesses, we have
बिज़नेसेस। अक्रॉस ऑल दीज बिज़नेसेस, वी हैव
A team of over 300 people, managing that many
अ टीम ऑफ ओवर 300 पीपल, मैनेजिंग दैट मेनी
people, all these operations, keeping all these
पीपल, ऑल दीज़ ऑपरेशंस, कीपिंग ऑल दीज़
Goals in mind while also being a fool
गोल्स इन माइंड व्हाइल आल्सो बीइंग अ फुल
Time Creator. That's the challenge. But
टाइम क्रिएटर। दैट्स द चैलेंज। बट
Businesses are an important part of the long term
बिज़नेसेस आर एन इंपॉर्टेंट पार्ट ऑफ लॉन्ग
Term Content Creation and Businesses Don't Run
टर्म कंटेंट क्रिएशन एंड बिज़नेसेस डोंट रन
On Creativity Alone. HR, CRM,
ऑन क्रिएटिविटी अलोन। एचआर, सीआरएम,
Inventory, Signatures, Sales Tracking,
इन्वेंटरी, सिग्नेचर्स, सेल ट्रैकिंग,
Website Management. all this back and work
वेबसाइट मैनेजमेंट। ऑल दिस बैक एंड वर्क
Needs to function smoothly. and that's where
नीड्स टू फंक्शन स्मूथली। एंड दैट्स वेयर
I'm going to recommend an app that I use
आई एम गोइंग टू रेकमेंड एन ऐप दैट आई यूज
Myself Across My Businesses. it is called
मसेल्फ अक्रॉस माय बिनेसेस। इट्स कॉल्ड
Odoo and it completely changed the game for us
ओडu एंड इट्स कंप्लीटली चेंज द गेम फॉर अस
In our journey. Odoo is a powerful all in one
इन आवर जर्नी। ओडू इज अ पावरफुल ऑल इन वन
ERP Software with More Than 45
इआरपी सॉफ्टवेयर विथ मोर देन 45
Applications that help you manage everything
एप्लीकेशनेशंस दैट हेल्प यू मैनेज एव्री
Part of your business in one place. so weather
पार्ट ऑफ़ योर बिज़नेस इन वन प्लेस। सो वेदर
It's Building Your Website, Handling
इट्स बिल्डिंग योर वेबसाइट, हैंडलिंग
HR, Signing Documents, Tracking
एचआर, साइनिंग डॉक्यूमेंट्स, ट्रैकिंग
Sales and Managing Inventory. uduu max
सेल्स और मैनेजिंग इन्वेंटरी। uduू मेक्स
It's simple and scalable. click on the link
इट सिंपल एंड स्केलेबल। क्लिक ऑन द लिंक
Down below check out uDo and remember your
डाउन बिलो चेक आउट uडू एंड रिमेंबर योर
First App is Free for Life with Unlimited
फर्स्ट एप इज फ्री फॉर लाइफ विद अनलिमिटेड
Hosting and support highly recommended for
होस्टिंग एंड सपोर्ट हाइली रेकमेंडेड फॉर
Every entrepreneur is out there. For
एव्री एंटरप्रेन्योर आउट देर। फॉर
Creators Remember I'm Recommending Ode
क्रिएटर्स रिमेंबर आई एम रेकमेंडिंग ओडu
Because I can focus on being a creator.
बिकॉज़ आय कैन फोकस ऑन बीइंग अ क्रिएटर।
And Odoo Helps My Team Handle My
एंड ओडू हेल्प्स माई टीम हैंडल माई
Operations in my back end smoothly
ऑपरेशंस इन माइ बैक एंड स्मूथली एंड
Efficacy. so if you're building something
एफ्फिसली। सो इफ यू आर बिल्डिंग समथिंग
Whether you are a solopreneur or whether you
वेदर यू आर अ सोलोप्रेन्योर ओर वेदर यू
Scaling. Odoo is the toolkit that everyone
स्केलिंग। ओडू इज द टूलकिट दैट एव्री
Modern Day Entrepreneur Needs. Big
मॉडर्न डे एंटरप्रेन्योर नीड्स। बिग
Thanks to Odoo for powering this
थैंक्स टू ओडू फॉर पावरिंग दिस
Entrepreneurship Special on The Ranveer Show.
एंटरप्रेन्योरशिप स्पेशल ऑन द रणवीर शो।
let's begin this very very special
लेट्स बिगिन दिस वेरी वेरीरी स्पेशल
Episodes with my modern day favorite content
एपिसोड विथ माय मॉडर्न डे फेवरेट कंटेंट
Creator Kavya Karnataka.
क्रिएटर काव्या कर्नाटक।
[music]
[संगीत]
with one of the best content creators in the
विथ वन ऑफ़ द बेस्ट कंटेंट क्रिएटर्स इन द
Country
कंट्री
today sorry for starting on that note how
टुडे सॉरी फॉर स्टार्टिंग ऑन दैट नोट हाउ
are you kk creates kavya a i would want
आर यू केके क्रिएट्स काव्या अ आई वुड वांट
to say that i am very peaceful very calm but
टू से दैट आई एम वेरी पीसफुल वेरी काम बट
To be honest he should be scared very very hard
टू बी ऑनेस्ट हिम शुड स्केर्ड वेरी वेरीरी
nervous very very very very
नर्वस वेरी वेरीरी वैरी
Restless and very grateful to be here is
रेस्टलेस एंड वैरी ग्रेटफुल टू बी हियर इज
this is your first podcast yes and
दिस योर फर्स्ट पडकास्ट यस एंड
this means a lot means a lot because as i
दिस मीन्स अ लॉट मीन्स अ लॉट बिकॉज़ एज आई
was telling you i think i have been
वास टेलिंग यू आई थिंक आई हाव बीन
consuming you in some form and the other for
कंज्यूमिंग यू इन सम फॉर्म और दी अदर फॉर
The Past 10 More Than 10 Years. you were one of
द पास्ट 10 मोर देन 10 इयर्स। यू वर वन ऑफ
The First Creators in the Education
द फर्स्ट क्रिएटर्स इन दी एजुकेशन
Information Segment. I have seen you in your
इनफॉरमेशन सेग्म। आई हैव सीन यू इन योर
Long videos, short videos.
लॉन्ग वीडियोस, शार्ट वीडियोस।
On Instagram, on YouTube. I have seen you
ऑन Instagram, ऑन YouTube. आई हैव सीन यू
Creating a Space for Influencers
क्रिएटिंग अ स्पेस फॉर इन्फ्लुएंसर
Marketing. I have seen you also train
मार्केटिंग। आई हैव सीन यू आल्सो ट्रेन
Young talents as your courses. so you have
यंग टैलेंट्स एस योर कोर्सेज। सो यू हैव
Just done everything. you have also been a
जस्ट डन एवरीथिंग। यू हैव आल्सो बीन अ
Part of a lot of memes. been a part of
पार्ट ऑफ़ अ लॉट ऑफ़ मीम्स। बीन अ पार्ट ऑफ़
Channel hacking. But Juv Sted. So, means a
चैनल हैकिंग। बट युव स्टेड। तो, मीन्स अ
Lot to be here. thank you so much for calling
लोट टू बी हियर। थैंक यू सो मच फॉर कॉलिंग
me here. genuinely very happy to have you
मी हियर। जेनुइनली वैरी हैप्पी टु हैव यू
here. ah i have to tell you this at the
हियर। अह आई हैव टू टेल यू दिस एट द
Start of this podcast to be watched by
स्टार्ट ऑफ दिस पॉडकास्ट टू बी वॉच्ड बाई
an indian audience in india while you are
एन इंडियन ऑडियंस इन इंडिया व्हाइल यू आर
Doing Hindi content is some other level of a
डूइंग हिंदी कंटेंट इज सम अदर लेवल ऑफ अ
Social Media Achievement So For Anyone Who Is Not
सोशल मीडिया अचीवमेंट सो फॉर एनीवन हू नॉट
Seen your channel I love for you to explain
सीन योर चैनल आई लव फॉर यू टू एक्सप्लेन
In short what you try covering and why
इन शोर्ट व्हाट यू ट्राई कवरिंग एंड व्हाई
you think that some of the most rich and
यू थिंक दैट सम ऑफ़ द मोस्ट रिच एंड
Powerful people in the country actually
पावरफुल पीपल इन द कंट्री एक्चुअली
Consuming your content. Thank You for Giving
कंजूमिंग योर कंटेंट। थैंक यू फॉर गिविंग
Me that question. in one line if i
मी दैट क्वेश्चन। इन वन लाइन इफ आई
describe what kk created does that is
डिस्क्राइब व्हाट केके क्रिएट डस इज दैट
We make the most viewed videos on social
वी मेक द मोस्ट व्यू वीडियोस ऑन सोशल
Realities of India. we do that across
रियलिटीज़ ऑफ़ इंडिया। वी डू दैट अक्रॉस
Across Platforms and We Do That
प्लेटफॉर्म्स एंड वी डू दैट अक्रॉस
Formats. Weather it is long or short,
फॉर्मेट्स। वेदर इट इज लॉन्ग ओर शार्ट,
Weather it's Instagram and YouTube. what do
वेदर इट्स Instagram ओर YouTube. व्हाट डू
I mean when I say that we try to talk
आई मीन व्हेन आई से दैट वी ट्राई टू टॉक
about social realities is that sin
अबाउट सोशल रियलिटीज़ इज दैट सिंस
Childhood, what we have been taught is very
चाइल्डहुड, व्हाट वी हैव बीन टॉट इज वेरी
Grey is very black and white. Sins
ग्रे इज वेरी ब्लैक एंड वाइट। सिंस
Childhood: What We've Been Taught Is Very
चाइल्डहुड व्हाट वी हैव बीन टॉट इज़ वेरी
Black and white. there is a good kid and a
ब्लैक एंड वाइट। देयर इज़ अ गुड किड एंड अ
Bad kid. There's a boy, there's a girl.
बैड किड। देयर इज़ अ बॉय, देयर इज़ अ गर्ल।
Pink is for girls, blue is for boys.
पिंक इज फॉर गर्ल्स, ब्लू इज फॉर बॉयज।
there is
देयर इज
there is rich and there is poor there is right
रिच एंड देयर इज पुअर देयर इज राइट
the ideology there is left
आईडियोलॉजी देयर इज लेफ्ट
ideology but my education my the people i
आईडियोलॉजी बट माय एजुकेशन माय द पीपल आई
got surrounded will told me that the world is
गॉट सराउंडेड विल टोल्ड मी दैट वर्ल्ड इज़
Not that black and white world is so grey
नॉट दैट ब्लैक एंड वाइट वर्ल्ड इज़ ग्रे सो
what i want to do with my channel is that
व्हाट आई वांट टू डू विद माय चैनल इज़ दैट
I want to cover each and every district
आई वांट टू कवर ईच एंड एव्री डिस्ट्रिक्ट
of india give the mic to the people in those
ऑफ़ इंडिया गिव द माइक टू द पीपल इन दोज़
Districts and Let Them Tell There
डिस्ट्रिक्ट्स एंड लेट देम टेल देयर
Stories like for example one of the
स्टोरीज लाइक फॉर एग्जांपल वन ऑफ़ द
Videos That We Made Which Has Now 10
वीडियोस दैट वी मेड व्हिच हैज़ नाउ 10
Million plus plus views which is insane to
मिलियन प्लस प्लस व्यूज व्हिच इज़ इनसेन टू
Think about to have in this category that does
थिंक अबाउट टू हैव इन दिस कैटेगरी दैट दोज़
many number of views in just two months of
मेनी नंबर ऑफ़ व्यूज इन जस्ट टू मंथ्स ऑफ़
It's releasing. We went to dharavi which
इट्स रिलीज़िंग। वी वेंट टू धारावी व्हिच
Is the world's biggest slum. We Spend
इज़ द वर्ल्ड्स बिगेस्ट स्लम। वी स्पेंड
Five days there and every day we realize that
फाइव डेज़ देयर एंड एवरी डे वी रियलाइज़ दैट
there are so many stories to be told
देयर आर सो मेनी स्टोरीज़ टू बी टोल्ड
here. There is a story of a woman who has
हियर। देयर इज़ अ स्टोरी ऑफ़ अ वूमन हु हैज़
come from a village and living in this big
कम फ्रॉम अ गांव एंड लिविंग इन दिस बिग
House. Literally this big house. and there are
हाउस। लिटरली दिस बिग हाउस। एंड देयर आर
20 People Living With Her in This Bigger House.
20 पीपल लिविंग विद हर इन दिस बिगगर हाउस।
imagine like this studio which is i
इमेजिन लाइक दिस स्टूडियो व्हिच इज़ आई
think three times the size of this woman
थिंक थ्री टाइम्स द साइज ऑफ़ दिस दैट वूमंस
The house is one third the size and there are 20
हाउस इज़ वन थर्ड द साइज़ एंड देयर आर 20
People Living in That House. That's Dharavi
पीपल लिविंग इन दैट हाउस। दैट्स धारावी
For you. but dharavi is also india's
फॉर यू। बट धारावी इज़ आल्सो इंडियास
Biggest leather producing market. it's
बिगेस्ट लेदर प्रोड्यूसिंग मार्केट। इट्स
also the biggest plastic recycling
आल्सो द बिगेस्ट प्लास्टिक रिसाइक्लिंग
Industries of Mumbai. it's a lot of
इंडस्ट्री ऑफ़ मुंबई। इट्स वेयर अ लॉट ऑफ़
Rappers Are Born With. like gully boy
रैपर्स आर बोर्न विथ। गली बॉय जैसी
The stories come from there. So
स्टोरीज वहां से निकल के आती हैं। तो
What I want to do with my videos is
व्हाट आई वांट टू डू विद माय वीडियोस इज
Make the stories about the social realities of
मेक द स्टोरीज अबाउट सोशल रियलिटीज ऑफ
India, Culture of India, Geography of
इंडिया, कल्चर ऑफ इंडिया, ज्योग्राफी ऑफ
India. I should make it in such a way that everyone can see it.
इंडिया। ऐसे बनाऊं कि सब लोग देखें उसको।
so you are right that our what we make
तो आपने सही कहा कि हमारी जो व्हाट वी मेक
is being consumed by people in Bangalore,
इज़ बीइंग कंज्यूम्ड बाय पीपल इन बैंगलोर,
Mumbai, Delhi. but at the same time it’s
मुंबई, दिल्ली। बट एट द सेम टाइम इट्स
also being consumed by people in patna,
आल्सो बीइंग कंज्यूम्ड बाय पीपल इन पटना,
In an Allahabad, in Hyderabad, in all the tears
इन अ इलाहाबाद, इन हैदराबाद, इन ऑल द टिएर
One and Tier Two City. it is being
वन एंड टिएर टू सिटी। इट्स बीइंग
Consumed by people. it is being consumed
कंज्यूम्ड बाय पीपल। इट्स बीइंग कंज्यूम्ड
Bye students who use their parents' phones
बाय स्टूडेंट्स जो अपने पेरेंट्स के फोन
You are watching our content from. it's
से अपना हमारा कंटेंट देख रहे हैं। इट्स
Been consumed by teachers. it is being
बीन कंज्यूम्ड बाय टीचर्स। इट्स बीइंग
Consumed by aspirants. it is being
कंज्यूम्ड बाय एस्पिरेंट्स। इट्स बीइंग
Consumed by travel bloggers. Enjoying it
कंज्यूम्ड बाय ट्रैवल ब्लॉगर्स। मजा आ रहा
I mean this is a very exciting journey. Or
है मतलब बहुत एक्साइटिंग जर्नी है ये। या
I told you this outside. but as a content
आई टोल्ड यू दिस आउटसाइड। बट एज अ कंटेंट
Creator. I'm Inspired to Do the Kind
क्रिएटर। आई एम इंस्पायर्ड टू डू द काइंड
of content you are doing. by actually
ऑफ़ कंटेंट यू आर डूइंग। बाय एक्चुअली
Going out on the field. and i love this
गोइंग आउट ऑन द फील्ड। एंड आई लव दिस
Medium. also i think it's got its own
मीडियम। आल्सो आई थिंक इट्स गॉट इट्स ओन
Ahhh
अह
Fruits. But I miss going out in the field,
फ्रूट्स। बट आई मिस गोइंग आउट इन द फील्ड,
Recording the Real Experience of Real
रिकॉर्डिंग द रियल एक्सपीरियंस ऑफ़ रियल
Human Beings. also as a content
ह्यूमन बीइंग्स। आल्सो एज़ अ कंटेंट
Creator I feel you are able to get the soul of
क्रिएटर आई फील यू आर एबल टू गेट द सोल ऑफ़
Your place transferred into your videos.
योर प्लेस ट्रांसफर्ड इनटू योर वीडियोस।
Hmm. I Wood Se
हम्म। आई वुड से
Don't. I wouldn't say that. Like face trouble?
डोंट। आई वुड से डोंट। लाइक फेस ट्रबल?
Yes. there is no procedure when you go on
यस। देयर इज नो प्रोसीजर व्हेन यू गो ऑन
Ground. there are so many factors that
ग्राउंड। देयर आर सो मेनी फैक्टर्स दैट
Can go that are not in your control. I
कैन गो दैट आर नॉट इन योर कंट्रोल। आई
Wanna say one thing before you. I Actually
वांट से वन थिंग बिफोर यू। आई एक्चुअली
Think you are one of the most talented content
थिंक यू आर वन ऑफ द मोस्ट टैलेंटेड कंटेंट
Creators have seen it in the last 10 years of
क्रिएटर्स हैव सीन इन द लास्ट 10 इयर्स ऑफ
Being in this industry and you are hard
बीइंग इन दिस इंडस्ट्री एंड यू आर हार्ड
Working along with the talent. because i have
वर्किंग अलोंग विथ द टैलेंट। बिकॉज़ आई हैव
Seen a lot of talented content creators
सीन अ लॉट ऑफ़ टैलेंटेड कॉन्टेंट क्रिएटर्स
Not actually a take on the long form. and I
नॉट एक्चुअली टेक ऑन लॉन्ग फॉर्म। एंड आई
don't think that's the average person
डोंट थिंक दैट दी एवरेज पर्सन
understands how difficult it is to
अंडरस्टैंड्स हाउ डिफिकल्ट इट इज टू
Create a 10, 15, 20 minute video, and keep it
क्रिएट अ 10, 15, 20 मिनट वीडियो, एंड कीप
The Audience's Retention in the Age of Short
दी ऑडियंसेस रिटेंशन इन दी एज ऑफ़ शार्ट
Form content. so what are you doing is
फॉर्म कंटेंट। सो व्हाट यू आर डूइंग इज
Very intric and its very real content
वेरी इंट्रिक एंड इट्स वेरी रियल कंटेंट
And you are getting the views. so you are
एंड यू आर गेटिंग द व्यूज। सो यू आर
Hitting too many marks. i hope that everybody
हिटिंग टू मेनी मार्क्स। आय होप दैट एव्री
Content creation on the country sees this
कंटेंट क्रिएट ऑन द कंट्री सीज़ दिस
Episode. so you are the prototype that i
एपिसोड। सो यू आर द प्रोटोटाइप दैट आई
present in front of a lot of young and
प्रेजेंट इन फ्रंट ऑफ अ लॉट ऑफ़ यंग एंड
Older content creators. So Figuring Long
ओल्डर कंटेंट क्रिएटर्स। सो फिगरिंग लॉन्ग
Form. ah but very few people are able to do this
फॉर्म। अह बट वेरी फ्यू पीपल आर एबल टू डू
what you do. now i love you to break
व्हाट यू डू। नाउ आई लव फॉर यू टू ब्रेक
Down. perfect. so a lot of things to
डाउन। परफेक्ट। सो अ लॉट ऑफ़ थिंग्स टू
Break down late. it's only been two years
ब्रेक डाउन देर। इट्स बीन ओनली टू इयर्स
Since I started content creation on my
सिंस आई स्टार्टेड कंटेंट क्रिएशन ऑन माय
On. The first year was entirely focused on
ओन। फर्स्ट ईयर वास एंटायरली फोकस्ड ऑन
Short form. In 10 Months We Could Gain 1.2
शॉर्ट फॉर्म। इन 10 मंथ्स वी कुड गेन 1.2
Million Followers on Instagram Geography
मिलियन फॉलोवर्स ऑन Instagram ज्योग्राफी
yes we focused around geography and second
यस वी फोकस्ड अराउंड ज्योग्राफी एंड सेकंड
Year we pivoted we didn't pivot. Wee Broad
ईयर वी पिवेटेड वी डिडन्ट पिवट। वी ब्रॉड
Our Scope to Culture. hmm and thats it
आवर स्कोप टू कल्चर। हम्म एंड दैट्स
Exactly a year ago in March 2024 is
एक्जेक्टली अ ईयर एगो इन मार्च 2024 इज़
When We Started Our YouTube Long
व्हेन वी स्टार्टेड आवर YouTube लॉन्ग
Format.
फॉर्मेट।
when i
व्हेन आई
started i new for sure that there were
स्टार्टेड आई न्यू फॉर श्योर दैट देयर वर
100 more than 100 people going to say that
100 मोर देन 100 पीपल गोइंग टू से दैट
Short Form Creators Can't Do Long
शॉर्ट फॉर्म क्रिएटर्स कांट डू लॉन्ग
Form like if you are a shorts creator you
फॉर्म लाइक इफ यू आर अ शार्ट्स क्रिएटर यू
can not do long format also the space
कैन नॉट डू लॉन्ग फॉर्मेट आल्सो द स्पेस
was so saturated because there was already a
वाज़ सो सैचुरेटेड बिकॉज़ देयर वाज़ ऑलरेडी अ
lots of established figures who are sitting in
लॉट ऑफ़ एस्टैब्लिश फिगर्स हू आर सिटींग इन
their houses breaking anything that was
देयर हाउसेस ब्रेकिंग एनीथिंग दैट वाज़
Happening Weather It Is Geopolitical Weather
हैप्पेनिंग वेदर इट इज़ जिओपॉलिटिक्स वेदर
it is a finance weather it is a anything in
इट इज़ अ फाइनेंस वेदर इट इज़ अ एनीथिंग इन
the news news people wood sill sit they had a
द न्यूज़ न्यूज़ पीपल वुड सिल सिट दे हैड अ
team of 20 people already and they wood break
टीम ऑफ़ 20 पीपल ऑलरेडी एंड दे वुड ब्रेक
down that same news after reading four five
डाउन दैट सेम न्यूज़ आफ्टर रीडिंग फोर फाइव
Six Research Papers. so when we begin
सिक्स रिसर्च पेपर्स। सो व्हेन वी बिगेन
YouTube I wanted to know that I wanted to
YouTube आई वांटेड टू नो दैट आई वांटेड टू
do it in the education rail but i didn't want to
डू इट इन द एजुकेशन रेल बट आई डिडंट वांट
To sit at home and do it. because there was
टू सीट एट होम एंड डू इट। बिकॉज़ देयर वाज़
so many people doing it
सो मेनी पीपल डूइंग इट
Already. And when I vented out I saw a new eye
ऑलरेडी। एंड व्हेन आई वेंट आउट आई न्यू आई
new that this short haired girl is thin
न्यू दैट यह छोटे से बालों वाली लड़की पतली
C will go to such tough places. this is peepal
सी ऐसे टफ जगहों में जाएगी। ये तो पीपल
will think that this is itself an
विल थिंक दैट दिस इज़ इटसेल्फ एन
interesting story s well right like you
इंटरेस्टिंग स्टोरी एस वेल राइट लाइक यू
are a character exactly i am the
आर अ कैरेक्टर एक्जेक्टली आई एम द
Character So Many Women So Many Men Also
कैरेक्टर सो मेनी वुमेन सो मेनी मेन आल्सो
relate to that character then when so the
रिलेट टू दैट कैरेक्टर देन व्हेन सो द
the premise was decided that we would go to each
प्रेमिस वाज़ डिसाइडेड दैट वी विल गो टू ईच
Districts of India tell the story
डिस्ट्रिक्ट ऑफ़ इंडिया टेल द टेल द स्टोरी
through my lens and while at the same time
थ्रू माय लेंस एंड व्हाइल एट द सेम टाइम
that was the basic thing everything we
दैट वाज़ द बेसिक थिंग एवरीथिंग वी
perfected dude like we spend so much till the
परफेक्टेड डूड लाइक वी स्पेंड सो मच टिल द
The day I began two years ago on the day I came
डे आई बिगेन टू इयर्स एगो ऑन द डे आई आई
Begin till today. I have all the data fed by
बिगेन टिल टुडे। आई हैव ऑल द डेटा फेड बाय
My own hands. How many views did you get on the first day?
माय ओन हैंड्स। कितने व्यूज आए फर्स्ट डे
Pay? How many views did you get on the seventh day? How many?
पे? कितने व्यूज आए सेवंथ डे पे? कितने
Did you get views on the 30th day? How many likes did you get,
व्यूज आए 30थ डे पे? कितने लाइक्स आए,
How many shares came? how many what comments
कितने शेयर्स आए? कितने क्या कमेंट्स का
type was it? what was the audience that was
टाइप था? व्हाट वास द ऑडियंस दैट वास
watching it? what was the ctr on the
वाचिंग इट? व्हाट वास द सीटीआर ऑन द
First day, seventh day, 30th day. I Come
फर्स्ट डे, सेवेंथ डे, 30थ डे। आई कम
From a mother who is a maths teacher. we sleep
फ्रॉम अ मदर हु इज अ मैथ्स टीचर। हम सो
That love for data, that love for analysis
दैट लव फॉर डेटा, दैट लव फॉर एनालिसिस
Comes from her. Yes. so, the second thing that
कम्स फ्रॉम हर। यस। सो, द सेकंड थिंग दैट
We did respect the platform. So We
वी डिड वाज़ रेस्पेक्ट द प्लेटफार्म। सो वी
Figure out the niche that we want to enter into
फिगर आउट द नीश दैट वी वांट टू एंटर इंटू
And that's the way that we are going to enter into. The
एंड द वे दैट वी आर गोइंग टू एंटर इंटू। द
the second thing i did was we respected the
सेकंड थिंग आय डीड वाज़ वी रेस्पेक्टेड द
Platform. What does YouTube want before
प्लेटफार्म। व्हाट डस YouTube वांट बिफोर
Even if you make the best story you will give
इवन इफ यू मेक द बेस्ट स्टोरी यू विल गेव
To get people to click on it. Right? Like
टू गेट पीपल टू क्लिक ऑन इट। राइट? लाइक
as you also said, you still spend a lot
एज़ यू आल्सो सेड, यू स्टिल स्पेंड अ लॉट
of your time thinking about the thumbnail and the
ऑफ़ योर टाइम थिंकिंग अबाउट द थंबनेल एंड द
Title. i also spend a lot of my time
टाइटल। आई आल्सो स्पेंड अ लॉट ऑफ़ माय टाइम
Packaging It. then once they have clicked it the
पैकेजिंग इट। देन वंस दे हैव क्लिक इट द
15 Seconds You Have to Be the Best
15 सेकंड्स हैव टू बी हैव टू बी द बेस्ट
of your video till today i am the one who
ऑफ योर वीडियो टिल टुडे आई एम द वन हु
seats at the end of the day once the video has
सीट्स एट द एंड ऑफ़ द डे वंस द वीडियो हैज़
Been edited I still sit with it for three
बीन एडिटेड आई स्टिल सिट विथ इट फॉर थ्री
Days on my own editing table I spend full
डेज़ ऑन माई ओन एडिटिंग टेबल आई स्पेंड फुल
Three Days Without Sleeping and Thinking About It
थ्री डेज़ विथाउट स्लीपिंग एंड थिंक अबाउट
What is the 15 seconds. how are we making it
व्हाट इज़ द 15 सेकंड्स। हाउ आर वी मेकिंग
the best 15 seconds
द 15 सेकंड्स द बेस्ट
Possible.
पॉसिबल।
And ah not just 15 seconds. 15 seconds
एंड अह नॉट जस्ट 15 सेकंड्स। 15 सेकंड्स
This is the beginning of it. if you don't give
इज़ द बिगनिंग ऑफ़ इट। इफ यू डोंट गिव
something new for after every 30 seconds,
समथिंग न्यू फॉर आफ्टर एव्री 30 सेकंड्स,
You are going to lose your audience. and it
यू आर गोइंग टू लूज़ योर ऑडियंस। एंड इट
Sounds very capitalistic. it sounds
साउंड्स वैरी कैपिटलिस्टिक। इट साउंड्स
very scathing that
वैरी स्केैटिक देट
Oh there are tricks and tricks of
ओह देर आर ट्रिक्स एंड ट्रिक्स ऑफ
Detaining the audience. but it's important,
डिटेनिंग दी ऑडियंस। बट इट्स इंपॉर्टेंट,
Right? like these are stories that should reach so
राइट? लाइक दीज़ आर स्टोरीज दैट शुड रीच सो
Many people. If we are spending so much money,
मेनी पीपल। इफ वी आर स्पेंडिंग सो मच मनी,
So much time, so much energy in making those
सो मच टाइम, सो मच एनर्जी इन मेकिंग दोज़
Stories. Why Not Spend Time in Making
स्टोरीज। व्हाई नॉट स्पेंड टाइम इन मेकिंग
Sure people watch it. More and More People Watch
श्योरट पीपल वॉच इट। मोर एंड मोर पीपल वाच
It's over, people watch it till the end. I also
इट एंड पीपल वॉच इट टिल दी एंड। आय आल्सो
think you are doing the job that journalists are
थिंक यू आर डूइंग द जॉब देट जर्नलिस्ट आर
Paid to do. For sure. we get so many
पेड टू डू। फॉर श्योर। वी गेट सो मेनी
Governments saying this is what I want
गवर्मेंट्स सेइंग दिस इस व्हाट आई वांट
Journalism to be. why is media houses
जर्नलिज्म टू बी। व्हाई इज मीडिया हाउसेस
Not covering it. a lot of people this is this
नॉट कवरिंग इट। अ लॉट ऑफ़ पीपल दिस इज़ दिस
Happened not by design. this happened i
हैपेंड नॉट बाइ डिजाइन। दिस हैपेंड आई
Think because of my education. what did you
थिंक बिकॉज़ ऑफ़ माई एजुकेशन। व्हाट डीड यू
Study? ah i went to first a womans
स्टडी? अह आई वेंट टू फर्स्ट अ वूमस
College. I did my bachelors from lady
कॉलेज। आई डीड माई बैचलर्स फ्रॉम लेडी
Shri Ram College. and Ranveer A Women's College
श्रीराम कॉलेज। एंड रणवीर अ वूमंस कॉलेज
is the best space to be for any female.
इज द बेस्ट स्पेस टू बी फॉर एनी फीमेल।
Because that space is freeing. it freezes
बिकॉज़ दैट स्पेस इज़ अ फ्रीिंग। इट फ्रीज़
You up. you can dance walk talk in whatever
यू अप। यू कैन डांस वॉक टॉक इन व्हाटएवर
the way you want
वे यू वांट
Two. So I went to a women's college. i did
टू। सो आई वेंट टू अ वूमस कॉलेज। आई डिड
My under graduation in english honours. But
माई अंडर ग्रेजुएशन इन इंग्लिश ऑनर्स। बट
during those three years of being in a
ड्यूरिंग दोज़ थ्री इयर्स ऑफ़ बीइंग इन अ
women's college, i was also involved
वुममेंस कॉलेज, आई वास आल्सो इन्वॉल्व्ड
In Theatre. for three years, every year we
इन थिएटर। फॉर थ्री इयर्स, एव्री ईयर वी
Wood Do 300 Performances on Ground. So,
वुड डू 300 परफॉरमेंसेस ऑन ग्राउंड। सो,
people think that this is an overnight success
पीपल थिंक दैट दिस इस एन ओवरनाइट सक्सेस
that i got 3 million subscribers in just
कि आई गॉट 3 मिलियन सब्सक्राइबर्स इन जस्ट
A Year of Doing YouTube. no, i also did
अ ईयर ऑफ़ डूइंग YouTube। नो, आई आल्सो डीड
Three Years of Street Theatre Where We Were
थ्री इयर्स ऑफ़ स्ट्रीट थिएटर वेयर वी वर
Writing our own scripts. We are the best
राइटिंग आवर ओन स्क्रिप्ट्स। वी वर
Directing That Play. we were also
डायरेक्टिंग दैट प्ले। वी वर आल्सो
Acting in it. We were also making the
एक्टिंग इन इट। वी वर आल्सो मेकिंग द
music of those who play and think about it
म्यूजिक ऑफ़ दोज़ प्लेज़ एंड थिंक अबाउट लाइक
This is the area where Imtiaz Ali has come
दिस इज़ द एरिया वेयर इम्तियाज़ अली हैज़ कम
From. this is the area where a lot of our
फ्रॉम। दिस इज़ द एरिया वेयर अ लॉट ऑफ़ आवर
Directors have come from. So The Talent
डायरेक्टर्स हैव कम फ्रॉम। सो द टैलेंट
There is very rich. and then i did my
देयर इज़ वेरी रिच। एंड देन आई डिड माय
Masters from India's Best Social Science
मास्टर्स फ्रॉम इंडियास बेस्ट सोशल साइंस
Institute. So Sir Ratan Tata has built
इंस्टीट्यूट। सो सर रतन टाटा हैज़ बिल्ट
This college called Tata Institute of Social
दिस कॉलेज कॉल्ड टाटा इंस्टीट्यूट ऑफ़ सोशल
Science which is in Mumbai only where I
साइंस व्हिच इज़ इन मुंबई ओनली व्हेयर आई
Learned how to make documentaries. I slept
लर्नड हाउ टू मेक डॉक्यूमेंट्रीज़। सो आई
Learned how to hold the camera at what fps
लर्नड हाउ टू होल्ड द कैमरा व्हाट एफपीएस
Aperture Balancing Rule of Thirds All the
अपर्चर बैलेंसिंग रूल ऑफ थर्ड्स ऑल द
Technicalities That Only Videographers Know
टेक्निकिटीज दैट ओनली वीडियोग्राफर्स नो
is what I learned there I also learned how
इज व्हाट आई लर्नड देयर आई आल्सो लर्न हाउ
How to Edit in Premiere Pro
टू डू एडिटिंग प्रीमियर प्रो में हम लोग
used to sit and they were so old like those
बैठते थे और वो इतने पुराने लाइक दोज़
machines was so old ranvir to render a 15
मशीनंस वास सो ओल्ड रणवीर टू रेंडर अ 15
second clip it would take us like 3 hours
सेकंड क्लिप इट वुड टेक अस 3 आवर्स लाइक
we would put that on render go out have tea
वी वुड पुट दैट ऑन रेंडर गो आउट हैव चाय
have dinner then come back from plate so i learnt
हैव डिनर देन कम बैक देन प्लेट सो आई लर्न
Through the hard way that how do you edit? how do
थ्रू द हार्डवे कि हाउ डू यू एडिट? हाउ डू
you put the camera and then we were sent on
यू पुट द कैमरा एंड देन वी वर सेंट ऑन
Ground. so during that time there was a
ग्राउंड। सो ड्यूरिंग दैट टाइम देयर वाज़ अ
Protest happening in Mumbai wherever they are
प्रोटेस्ट हैप्पेनिंग इन मुंबई वेर दे वर
Clearing the R A Forest. i spend a
क्लियरिंग द आर ए फॉरेस्ट। आई स्पेंड अ
month later documenting just the journey of the
मंथ देर डॉक्यूमेंटिंग जस्ट द जर्नी ऑफ़ द
Tribals who were living there. who's life was
ट्राइबल्स हु वर लिविंग देर। हुज़ लाइफ वाज़
Going to get affected.
गोइंग टू गेट अफेक्टेड।
so skip to now when a lot of people
सो स्किप टू नाउ व्हेन अ लॉट ऑफ पीपल
Comment saying this was true journalism is
कमेंट सेइंग दिस इस वास ट्रू जर्नलिज्म इज
it comes because of my education in guys
इट कम्स बिकॉज़ ऑफ माई एजुकेशन इन दोस
Areas. when i was breaking down this
एरियाज। व्हेन आई वाज ब्रेकिंग डाउन दिस
Podcast with a friend don't be a big fan. V
पॉडकास्ट विथ अ फ्रेंड डोन अ बिग फैन। वी
both came to conclude that you are very good
बोथ केम टू कंक्लूजन दैट यू आर वैरी गुड
With people. and that's what helps you in
विथ पीपल। एंड दैट्स व्हाट हेल्प्स यू इन
Your Content Creation Journey. like you're able to
योर कंटेंट क्रिएशन जर्नी। लाइक यू एबल टू
Connect very easily to people. Right? Or. I
कनेक्ट वैरी इजीली टू पीपल। राइट? या। आई
Think I am and like anyone. anybody in this
थिंक आई एम एंड लाइक एनीवन। एनीवन इन दिस
Life is a combination of their parents.
लाइफ इज अ कॉम्बिनेशन ऑफ देयर पेरेंट्स।
Right? like a lot of you is defined by who
राइट? लाइक अ लॉट ऑफ यू इज़ डिफाइंड बाय हु
Your parents are. my mother has been a teacher
योर पेरेंट्स आर। माय मदर हैज़ बीन अ टीचर
For the Past 25 Years. every day i have seen
फॉर द पास्ट 25 इयर्स। एवरी डे आई हैव सीन
That woman who goes to school at 7:00 am. Less
दैट वूमेन हु गो टू स्कूल एट 7:00 am. कम
Back at 4:00 p.m. again teach for two hours
बैक एट 4:00 पी.m. अगेन टीच फॉर टू आवर्स
Tuition in home. and then at night check
ट्यूशन इन होम। एंड देन एट नाइट चेक
Papers and then repeat that. for 25 years
पेपर्स एंड देन रिपीट दैट। फॉर 25 इयर्स
She has been teaching the same subject. End
शी हैज़ बीन टीचिंग द सेम सब्जेक्ट। एंड
My father is the complete opposite. he will do
माय फादर इस द कंप्लीट ऑपोजिट। ही विल डू
The Bare Minimum in His Office. he loves to
द बेयर मिनिमम इन हिज़ ऑफिस। ही लवस टू
Travel. Am I the one who loves to talk to people. he is
ट्रैवल। अम ही लव्स टू टॉक टू पीपल। ही इज़
The One Who Most Likes Fathers to Say in Your Social
द वन हु लाइक मोस्ट फादर्स से योर सोशल
Friends are your biggest currency. nothing
फ्रेंड्स आर युवर बिगेस्ट करेंसी। नथिंग
Everything Else Matters in Life. so i am a
एल्स मैटर्स इन लाइफ। सो आई एम अ
Combination of my mother. who knows hard
कॉम्बिनेशन ऑफ़ माय मदर। हु नोज़ हार्ड
work. who knows everyday doing the same thing
वर्क। हु नोस एवरीडे डूइंग द सेम थिंग
Again and again till you have perfected it.
अगेन एंड अगेन टिल यू हैव परफेक्टेड इट।
And then doing it in some way other than that.
एंड देन डूइंग इट इन सम वे अदर देन दैट।
And my father is a very social person likes
एंड माय फादर इज अ वेरी सोशल पर्सन लाइक्स
to travel get new
टू ट्रैवल गेट न्यू
Experiences. So Brilliant Parenting
एक्सपीरियंसेस। सो ब्रिलियंट पेरेंटिंग
bro do they will understand what you are
ब्रो डू दे विल अंडरस्टैंड व्हाट यू आर
Doing it completely? they don't even understand
डूइंग कंप्लीटली? दे डोंट अंडरस्टैंड इवन
one thing that has been happening in my
वन थिंग दैट हैज़ बीन हैप्पेनिंग इन माय
Journey but they have been the biggest supporter.
जर्नी बट दे हैव बीन द बिगेस्ट सपोर्टर।
My Mother Understands Business. even two hum
माय मदर अंडरस्टैंड्स बिज़नेस। इवन दो हम
There are hills. I had never thought that at 27
पहाड़ी हैं। आई हैड नेवर थॉट दैट एट 27
years of my age i would leave my job, do
इयर्स ऑफ़ माय एज आय वुड लीव माय जॉब, डू
My own business, I have a private limited at
माय ओन बिज़नेस, हैव अ प्राइवेट लिमिटेड एट
My name. Be Employing 27 Young
माय नेम। बी एम्प्लॉयंग 27 यंग
Individuals in a Country Wear
इंडिविजुअल्स इन अ कंट्री वेयर
Employment is really a big issue. and be a
एंप्लॉयमेंट इज़ सच अ बिग इशू। एंड बी अ
Profitable. this is, and at the same time
प्रॉफिटेबल। दिस इज़, एंड एट द सेम टाइम
Tell stories. which no one in this country
टेल स्टोरीज। व्हिच नो वन इन दिस कंट्री
Is Telling and Getting Views, in the Long
इज़ टेलिंग एंड गेटिंग व्यूज़, इन लॉन्ग
Form at 10 million, it's unimaginable.
फॉर्म एट 10 मिलियन, इट्स अनइमेजिनेबल।
So, of course, it's unimaginable for them
तो, ऑफ़ कोर्स, इट्स अनइमेजिनेबल फॉर देम
Also. are parents also we have to be a
आल्सो। आर पेरेंट्स आल्सो वी हैव टू बी अ
Little kind to them. They are a generation
लिटिल काइंड टू देम। दे आर अ जनरेशन हु
Went from Writing Letters to Then Getting
वेंट फ्रॉम राइटिंग लेटर्स टू देन गेटिंग
telephone to then getting telephone to then getting
टेलीफोन टू देन गेटिंग फोन टू देन गेटिंग
5G now child GPT then AI. they have seen
5G नाउ चाइल्ड जीपीटी देन एआई। दे हैव सीन
A lot in these small years of being.
अ लॉट इन दिस देयर स्मॉल इयर्स ऑफ बीइंग।
hmm but yet why i say my parents
हम् बट येट व्हाई आई से माय पेरेंट्स
supported me is because when i left my
सपोर्टेड मी इज बिकॉज़ व्हेन आई लेफ्ट माय
Job. my mother was the first one who said if
जॉब। माय मदर वास द फर्स्ट वन हु सेड इफ
you are going to do this do this seriously you
यू आर गोइंग टू डू दिस डू दिस सीरियसली यू
Don't have to take anyone's approval, you will be
डोंट हैव टू टेक एनीवनस अप्रूवल यू विल बी
Great at what you want to do and
ग्रेट एट व्हाट यू वांट टू डू एंड
she hum log ne to Ranveer you started 10
शी हम लोग ने तो रणवीर यू स्टार्टेड 10
Years Ago My Mother Had a YouTube Channel 12
इयर्स एगो माय मदर हैड अ YouTube चैनल 12
Years ago she was teaching maths in her
इयर्स एगो शी वास टीचिंग मैथ्स इन हर
YouTube Channel My Mother in Her Job Uses AI
YouTube चैनल माय मदर इन हर जॉब यूजस एआई
my mother doesn't work anywhere fancy but she is
माय मदर डजंट वर्क एनीवेयर फैंसी बट शी इज़
Just Learning Evolving Try to Know New
जस्ट लर्निंग इवॉल्विंग ट्राइ टू नो न्यू
Things Anytime Our Followers Grow By
थिंग्स एनी टाइम आवर फॉलोअर्स ग्रो बाय
When two of 100 is 2.1. Two of 2.2
100 के जब टू का 2.1 होता है। टू का 2.2
It happens. They are the first one. Whether he
होता है। दे आर द फर्स्ट वन। चाहे वो
It is 12:00 o'clock or 1:00 in the night. they are the
12:00 बजे हो रात के 1:00 बजे हो। दे आर द
first one who will be clicking a
फर्स्ट वंस हु विल बी क्लिकिंग अ
Screenshot sending it to the group.
स्क्रीनशॉट सेंडिंग इट टू द ग्रुप।
Congratulations. Let's have a party. My
कांग्रेचुलेशंस। आओ पार्टी करते हैं। माय
Father Recently Took Me to His Boss and Said
फादर रिसेंटली टूक मी टू हिस बॉस एंड सेड
This is my daughter. She is Forbes 30 Under 30.
दिस इस माय डॉटर। शी इज फोब्स 30 अंडर 30.
he didn't know what forbes 30 under 30
ही डिडन्ट नो व्हाट फोब्स 30 अंडर 30
Means. But he still said it to his boss. Give
मीन्स। बट ही स्टिल सेड इट टू हिज बॉस। दे
You are very very proud, excited, loving
आर वेरी वेरी प्राउड, एक्साइटेड, लविंग
Parents. you know, i am asking you this
पेरेंट्स। यू नो, आय एम आस्किंग यू दिस
Question? because i actually feel you saw the
क्वेश्चन? बिकॉज़ आई एक्चुअली फील यू सीन द
Realities of our country, considering the
रियलिटीज़ ऑफ़ आवर कंट्री, कंसीडरिंग द
Places You Visit for Your
प्लेसेस यू विजिट फॉर योर
Documentaries. and you also meet
डॉक्यूमेंट्रीज। एंड यू आल्सो मीट
People in South Bombay, South Delhi etc.
पीपल इन साउथ बॉम्बे, साउथ दिल्ली वगैरह।
keeping all those audiences in mind, what
कीपिंग ऑल दोज़ ऑडियंसेस इन माइंड, व्हाट
Do You Think Is the Future of Content Creation
डू यू थिंक इज द फ्यूचर ऑफ कंटेंट क्रिएशन
In our country. You think it keeps growing?
इन आवर कंट्री। यू थिंक इट कीप ग्रोइंग?
Content will always stay, the format might
कंटेंट विल ऑलवेज स्टे, द फॉर्मेट माइट
Differ, the Platform Might
डिफ़र, द प्लेटफार्म माइट
Differ. When there was only newspaper,
डिफ़र। व्हेन देयर वाज़ ओनली न्यूज़पेपर,
TV came, people started consuming there
टीवी केम, पीपल स्टार्टेड कंज्यूमिंग देयर
News from TV. earlier there were only
न्यूज़ फ्रॉम टीवी। अर्लियर देयर वर ओनली
Books, Mobiles Came, People Started
बुक्स, मोबाइल्स केम, पीपल स्टार्टेड
Consuming their books from mobiles.
कंस्यूमिंग देयर बुक्स फ्रॉम मोबाइल्स।
We are in a very interesting space in the format
फॉर्मेट बहुत इंटरेस्टिंग स्पेस में हम
People should look at the content on Instagram
लोग कंटेंट तो यार तुम देख लो Instagram
The algorithm itself changes every month
का ही एल्गोरििदम हर एक महीने में बदलता
It remains, it will keep on changing
रहता है वो तो चेंज होता ही रहेगा वो तो
Smart Creators Know How to Evolve
स्मार्ट क्रिएटर्स नो हाउ टू अ इवॉल्व
change their hooks change their personality
चेंज देयर हुक्स चेंज देयर पर्सनालिटी
change their way of speaking going slow
चेंज देयर वे ऑफ़ स्पीकिंग गोइंग स्लो
going fast telling about life telling
गोइंग फास्ट टेलिंग अबाउट लाइफ टेलिंग
about business
अबाउट बिज़नेस
But Creators Will Evolve to What It Is
बट क्रिएटर्स विल इवॉल्व टू व्हाट इट इज़
That the audience wants smart creators
दैट द ऑडियंस वांट्स स्मार्ट क्रिएटर्स
Those will evolve to that. I genuinely think
र्स विल इवॉल्व टू दैट। आई जेनुइनली थिंक
My personal belief is that regional local
माय पर्सनल बिलीफ इज़ दैट रीजनल लोकल
Creators will grow a lot. i see that with
क्रिएटर्स विल ग्रो अ लॉट। आई सी दैट विद
The series that OTTs are offering. For
द सीरीज दैट ओटीटीज़ आर ऑफरिंग। फॉर
Example Black Warren type which is a series
एग्जांपल ब्लैक वारेन टाइप जो सीरीज है
The actors in it, the stories in it
उसमें जो एक्टर्स हैं उसमें जो स्टोरीज
it is being told or it is of the double paisa type which
बताई जा रही है या फिर दुपैया टाइप की जो
This is a series that tells very local stories
सीरीज है जो कि बहुत ही लोकल स्टोरीज बताई
Are going. Or you can look at this
जा रही हैं। या फिर तुम ये देखो कि
YouTube is offering dubbing feature.
YouTube जो है डबिंग फीचर ऑफर कर रहा है।
It's a small thing. But still the kind of growth
छोटी चीज है। बट फिर भी द काइंड ऑफ़ ग्रोथ
That it will see is massive. mr beast joe
दैट इट विल सी इज़ मैसिव। मिस्टर बीस्ट जो
Now those are our own videos, those are 15
है वो अब हमारी अपनी वीडियोस जो है वो 15
It is being dubbed in 16 languages. My
16 लैंग्वेजेस में डब करवा रहा है। मेरे
Whenever I see the video of Mr. Beast
को तो जब भी मिस्टर बीस्ट की वीडियो दिखती
is it plays in hindi. so and that has been seen
है इट प्लेज़ इन हिंदी। सो एंड दैट हैज़ सीन
A 10% 10% increase in his viewership. So
अ 10% 10% इंक्रीज इन हिज़ व्यूअरशिप। सो
Local Regional Stories Formats Content Will
लोकल रीजनल स्टोरीज़ फॉर्मेट्स कंटेंट विल
Grow is what I think. also because of
ग्रो इज व्हाट आई थिंक। आल्सो बिकॉज़ ऑफ़
AI dubbing. Yes. let me ask you a very
एआई डबिंग। यस। लेट मी आस्क यू अ वेरी
Like a straight question. Feel Free to Answer
लाइक स्ट्रेट क्वेश्चन। फील फ्री टू आंसर
However you want. Why is your YouTube
हाउएवर यू वांट। व्हाई इज योर YouTube
Channel Working So Well in 2025? because i
चैनल वर्किंग सो वेल इन 2025? बिकॉज़ आई
Think a lot, people don't attempt it for long
थिंक अ लॉट पीपल डोंट अटेम्प्ट लॉन्ग
Form thinking that there is no more future
फॉर्म थिंकिंग दैट देयर इज नो मोर फ्यूचर
In long form. and then you see kavya r
इन लॉन्ग फॉर्म। एंड देन यू सी काव्या आर
Getting 10 million views on videos. So
गेटिंग 10 मिलियन व्यूज ऑन वीडियोस। सो
What do you think you are doing right. Hmm.
व्हाट डू यू थिंक यू आर डूइंग राइट। हम्म।
A I am doing what no one else is doing.
ए आई एम डूइंग व्हाट नो वन एल्स इज़ डूइंग।
be i am doing something which is
बी आई एम डूइंग समथिंग व्हिच इज
Well it makes no sense. Sustainability Makes It
वै इट मेक्स नो सेंस। सस्टेनेबली इट मेक्स
No sense. Financially it makes no sense.
नो सेंस। फाइनेंसियली इट मेक्स नो सेंस।
Safety wise it makes no sense. so it's
सेफ्टी वाइज इट मेक्स नो सेंस। सो इट्स
Very difficult to do what I am doing.
वेरी डिफिकल्ट टू डू व्हाट आई एम डूइंग।
It's not easy being a woman to go to
इट्स नॉट इजी बीइंग अ वूमेन टू गो टू
India's Hottest Place, Wettest Place,
इंडियास हॉटेस्ट प्लेस, वेटेस्ट प्लेस,
Biggest dumping ground, it's not easy. So
बिगेस्ट डंपिंग ग्राउंड, इट्स नॉट इजी। सो
it's just very different from what the
इट्स जस्ट वेरी डिफरेंट फ्रॉम व्हाट द
The kind of content that YouTube has. seconds,
काइंड ऑफ़ कंटेंट दैट YouTube हैड। सेकंड,
I am doing it very-very systematically.
आई एम डूइंग इट वेरी-वेरी सिस्टमैटिकली।
Like I have studied all the Ranveer, you
लाइक आई हैव स्टडीड ऑल द रणवीर, तुमने
All the studio tours, all the content,
जितने भी स्टूडियो टूर्स, ऑल द कंटेंट,
Creator, Podcast You Had I Studied
क्रिएटर, पॉडकास्ट यू हैड आई हैव स्टडीड
Them all. I literally have notes from all the
देम ऑल। आई लिटरली हैव नोट्स फ्रॉम ऑल द
Podcast That You Have Done. and i have done it
पॉडकास्ट दैट यू हैव डन। एंड आई हैव डन
This is for all foreign creators. I have done it
दिस फॉर ऑल फॉरेन क्रिएटर्स। आई हैव डन
This is for all Indian creators.
दिस फॉर ऑल इंडियन क्रिएटर्स।
Third, I work a lot with data. Till From
थर्ड, आई वर्क अ लॉट विद डेटा। टिल फ्रॉम
Day one till today, I have noted myself
डे वन टिल टुडे, आई हैव माइसेल्फ नोटेड
Down number of views, number of likes, number
डाउन नंबर ऑफ़ व्यूज, नंबर ऑफ़ लाइक्स, नंबर
of comments, etsetra. Fourth, I have a
ऑफ़ कमेंट्स, एटसेट्रा। फोर्थ, आई हैव अ
Very strong team. like even do you only
वेरी स्ट्रांग टीम। लाइक इवन दो यू ओनली
see me on screen my fiancée is the one who
सी मी ऑन स्क्रीन माय फियनसे इज द वन हु
make sure that everyone is safe we ​​have the best
मेक श्योर दैट एवरीवन सेफ वी हैव द बेस्ट
Talents My Best Friend Is The One Who Makes
टैलेंट्स माय बेस्ट फ्रेंड इज द वन हु मेक
Sure that I don't have to talk to any brand
श्योर दैट आई डोंट हैव टॉक टू एनी ब्रांड
that our finances are taken care of I
दैट आवर फाइनेंससेस आर टेकन केयर ऑफ आई
I only worry about creative creativity
ओनली वरी अबाउट क्रिएटिव क्रिएटिविटी आई
only worry about videos so to have a
ओनली वरी अबाउट वीडियोस सो टू हैव अ
Strong team is very fifth eye also
स्ट्रांग टीम इज़ वेरीेंट फिफ्थ आई आल्सो
think i did it at the right time when the need was there
थिंक आई डिड इट एट अ राइट टाइम वेयर द नीड
The Need Was More Than Positive Content
फॉर पॉजिटिव कंटेंट से ज्यादा द नीड वाज़
of complex next content like depth
ऑफ़ कॉम्प्लेक्स नेक्स्ट कंटेंट लाइक डेप्थ
depth very in depth talking to people showing
डेप्थ वेरी इन डेप्थ टॉकिंग टू पीपल शोइंग
Realities Which Have Not Been Seen I Also
रियलिटीज व्हिच हैव नॉट बीन शोन आई आल्सो
think that people think that this is an overnight
थिंक दैट पीपल थिंक दैट दिस इज़ एन ओवरनाइट
Success
सक्सेस
but in some way or the other I have been working
बट इन सम वे ओर दी अदर आई हैव बीन वर्किंग
with the format of media and video and
विथ द फॉर्मेट ऑफ मीडिया एंड वीडियो एंड
Optimization for Very Long Like In
ऑप्टिमाइजेशन फॉर वेरी लॉन्ग लाइक इन
School I did National School of Drama then
स्कूल आई डिड नेशनल स्कूल ऑफ ड्रामा देन
I did theater in college then I was working
आई डिड थिएटर इन कॉलेज देन आई वाज वर्किंग
For a lot of internships just writing
फॉर अ लॉट ऑफ इंटर्नशिप्स जस्ट राइटिंग
Vlogs handling seos. I New
व्लॉग्स हैंडलिंग एसइओस। आई न्यू
The There Is No One Video Editing
द दे देयर इज नॉट वन वीडियो एडिटिंग
software which i have
सॉफ्टवेयर व्हिच आई हैव
Not practiced on myself. and above all
नॉट प्रैक्टिस्ड ऑन मायसेल्फ। एंड अबव ऑल
Of this I think I love making videos.
ऑफ़ दिस आई थिंक आई लव मेकिंग वीडियोस।
like videos at the end of the day, if i have
लाइक वीडियोस एट द एंड ऑफ़ द डे, इफ आई हैव
to tell you ranvir that this is how you get the
टू टेल यू रणवीर दैट दिस इज़ हाउ यू गेट द
Maximum CTR. this is how you obtain
मैक्सिमम सीटीआर। दिस इज़ हाउ यू ऑब्टेन
For retention, this is what thumbnail works,
फॉर रिटेंशन, दिस इज़ व्हाट थंबनेल वर्क्स,
This Is What the Title Works. nothing will
दिस इज़ व्हाट द टाइटल वर्क्स। नथिंग विल
Matter if you don't love videos. like i just
मैटर इफ यू डोंट लव वीडियोस। लाइक आई जस्ट
Want stories to be told. for years
वांट स्टोरीज टू बी टोल्ड। फॉर इयर्स
Years. like even today tomorrow if i retire
इयर्स। लाइक इवन टुडे टुमारो इफ आई रिटायर
I will still be clicking nice videos of
आई विल स्टिल बी क्लिकिंग नाइस वीडियोस ऑफ़
My partner putting them out. I love
माय पार्टनर पुटिंग देम आउट। आई लव
Videos. I'm gonna recap everything you
वीडियोस। आई एम गोना रिककैप एवरीथिंग यू
Sed. Ok? first and foremost
सेड। ठीक है? फर्स्ट एंड फॉरमोस्ट
Originality Creating Content That's YouTube
ओरिजिनलिटी क्रिएटिंग कंटेंट दैट YouTube
Not seen yet. which is a very very
नॉट सीन येट। व्हिच इज अ वेरी वेरी
Difficult skill because this is built out of
डिफिकल्ट स्किल बिकॉज़ दिस इज़ बिल्ट आउट ऑफ़
Observational skills. you have to be very
ऑब्जरवेशनल स्किल्स। यू हैव टू बी वेरी
Observe to understand this. Second, you are
ऑब्जर्व टू अंडरस्टैंड दिस। सेकंड, यू आर
Studying Other Content Creators Who Have Been
स्टडिंग अदर कंटेंट क्रिएटर्स हु हैव बीन
Around before you in detail. so you can learn
अराउंड बिफोर यू इन डिटेल। सो यू कैन लर्न
From the experiences and mistakes. I slept
फ्रॉम द एक्सपीरियंस एंड मिस्टेक्स। सो आई
Think it's a very active part of content
थिंक इट्स अ वैरी एक्टिव पार्ट ऑफ़ कंटेंट
Creation. Next, give is the saying that the
क्रिएशन। नेक्स्ट, दिए इस द सेइंग दैट द
The best kind of content is the one where the
बेस्ट काइंड ऑफ़ कंटेंट इज़ द वन वेयर द
Content creator is taking up the efforts
कॉन्टेंट क्रिएटर इज़ टेकिंग अप दी एफर्ट्स
In the place of the audience. i also want to
इन प्लेस ऑफ़ दी ऑडियंस। आई आल्सो वांट टु
No what Dharavi ends with dumping round.
नो व्हाट धारावी एंड दवारा डंपिंग राउंड।
But I am nimble, let me go. Yeah. and i am seeing
बट आई एम नम गो दे। याह। एंड आई ऍम सीइंग
It is through your efforts. ah so i think you
इट थ्रू योर एफर्ट्स। अह सो आई थिंक यू
Putting in the diet one extra act of
पुटिंग इन द ड्यात वन एक्स्ट्रा अेक्ट ऑफ़
Effort as well as risk. Yes. putting that
एफर्ट एज वेल एज़ रिस्क। यस। पुटिंग द्याट
Risk in the content. next you head
रिस्क इन द कंटेंट। नेक्स्ट यू हैड
Education related to media. you understand
एजुकेशन रिलेटेड टू मीडिया। यू अंडरस्टैंड
Documentary Film Making. You
डॉक्यूमेंट्री फिल्म मेकिंग। यू
Understand the theory of content creation.
अंडरस्टैंड द थिअरी ऑफ़ कॉन्टेंट क्रिएशन।
people do this over a three year course but in
पीपल डू दिस ओवर अ थ्री ईयर कोर्स बट इन
Truth. only learn it through practical
ट्रुथ। ओनली लर्न इट थ्रू प्रैक्टिकल
Exposure. Ah and finally, I think of you
एक्सपोज़र। अह एंड फाइनली, आई थिंक यू
Enjoy it, right? Yeah. then also the team
एन्जॉय इट, राइट? याह। देन आल्सो द टीम
also the time being right yes team number se
आल्सो द टाइम बीइंग राइट यस टीम नंबर से
like playing a team game having a vision yes
लाइक प्लेइंग अ टीम गेम हैविंग अ विज़न यस
So treating it with a little business angle
सो ट्रीटिंग इट अ विथ अ लिटिल बिज़नेस एंगल
at least yes yes I also ask my team
एट लीस्ट यस यस आई आल्सो आस्क माय टीम
members before coming here what is our
मेंबर्स बिफोर कमिंग हियर व्हाट इज आवर
mote what is it that is our USP what
मोट व्हाट इज इट दैट इज आवर यूएसपी व्हाट
makes a stand apart my teammate shyamvi
मेक्स अ स्टैंड अपार्ट माय टीममेट श्यामवी
said that a lot of the times when her cousins
सेड दैट अ लॉट ऑफ़ द टाइम्स व्हेन हर कजिंस
come back home they are tired they are cribbing
कम बैक होम दे आर टायर्ड दे आर क्रिबिंग
About their company. she said that for her it
अबाउट देयर कंपनी। शी सेड दैट फॉर हर इट
Feels like the work she is doing is hers.
फील्स लाइक द वर्क शी इज़ डूइंग इज़ हर्स।
Like she is doing it for herself. It
लाइक शी इज़ डूइंग इट फॉर हरसेल्फ। इट
Feels personal. it feels like what she is
फील्स पर्सनल। इट फील्स लाइक व्हाट शी इज़
Doing is making a difference to this entire
डूइंग इज़ मेकिंग अ डिफरेंस टू दिस एंटायर
World. even two she is not even in front of
वर्ल्ड। इवन दो शी इज़ नॉट इवन इन फ्रंट ऑफ़
The Camera. She is not even going on ground,
द कैमरा। शी इज़ नॉट इवन गोइंग ऑन ग्राउंड,
She is a community manager. she is just
शी इज़ अ कम्युनिटी मैनेजर। शी इज़ जस्ट
Answering 200, 300 comments a day. and if she
आंसरिंग 200, 300 कमेंट्स अ डे। एंड इफ शी
Said that's what it means, yah.
सेड दैट दैट मींस, याह।
something is happening which people feel
समथिंग हैप्पेनिंग व्हिच पीपल फील
connected to hmm my reading this is as a
कनेक्टेड टु हम्म माय रीडिंग दिस इज एज अ
Content Creator I Feel You Can Go To A
कॉन्टेंट क्रिएटर अ आई फील यू कैन गो टू अ
Place and capture the essence very well and
प्लेस एंड कैप्चर दी एसेंस वेरी वेल एंड
translate it into screen now i don't
ट्रांसलेट इट इंटू स्क्रीन नाउ आई डोंट
what to call this skin i will tell you
व्हाट टू कॉल दिस स्किन आई आई विल टेल यू
What to call this script before going
व्हाट टू कॉल दिस स्क्रिप्ट बिफोर गोइंग
too like i was saying making one video
टू लाइक आई वास सेइंग मेकिंग वन वीडियो
takes us a month and a half 45 days to make
टेक्स अस अ मंथ एंड अ हाफ 45 डेज टू मेक
One Video We Allocate 1.5 Lakh Per Video One
वन वीडियो वी एलोकेट 1.5 लाख पर वीडियो एक
It costs Rs 1.5 lakh to make the video.
वीडियो को बनाने का 1.5 लाख लगता है।
Accept Salaries, Accept Equipments,
एक्सेप्ट सैलरीज, एक्सेप्ट इक्विपमेंट्स,
Accept any other thing. Ok? Now we the people
एक्सेप्ट एनी अदर थिंग। ठीक है? अब हम लोग
20 Days Is Just Prey Before Going There
वहां जाने से पहले 20 डेज इज़ जस्ट प्री
work. Research Yes Research Where People
वर्क। रिसर्च यस रिसर्च वेयर व्हेन पीपल
think about video no the problem that came
थिंक अबाउट वीडियो ना, द प्रॉब्लम दैट आई
have with most creators is that they only
हैव विद मोस्ट क्रिएटर्स इज़ दैट दे ओनली
Think about data, innovation etcetera. i have a
थिंक अबाउट डेटा, इनेशन एटसेटरा। आई हैव अ
Strong Mentality if you are on YouTube
स्ट्रांग मेंटालिटी इफ यू आर ऑन YouTube
Think Visually. so we already have 50
थिंक विजुअली। सो वी ऑलरेडी हैव 50
Visuals in Mind. Story Boarding
विजुअल्स इन माइंड। स्टोरी बोर्डिंग
Story Boarding Which We Want to Take and End
स्टोरी बोर्डिंग व्हिच वी वांट टू टेक एंड
Out of those 50 visuals if five are my
आउट ऑफ दोज़ 50 विजुअल्स इफ फाइव आर माय
must have i tell my producers that
मस्ट हैव्स आई टेल माय प्रोड्यूसर्स दैट
If These Five Visuals Are Not There We Are
इफ दीज़ फाइव विजुअल्स आर नॉट देयर वी आर
not doing this video so my producer
नॉट डूइंग दिस वीडियो सो माय प्रोड्यूसर
who has now spent 20 days in just writing
हु हैज़ नाउ स्पेंड 20 डेज इन जस्ट राइटिंग
Writing the Perfect Title the Perfect
द परफेक्ट टाइटल राइटिंग द परफेक्ट
Introduction Writing the P Giving Me the
इंट्रोडक्शन राइटिंग द प गिविंग मी द
Best Visuals Writing The Perfect We Even
बेस्ट विजुअल्स राइटिंग द परफेक्ट वी इवन
Right, who are the people that we can interview?
राइट हु आर द पीपल दैट वी कैन इंटरव्यू
What are the kinds of questions that we can ask
व्हाट आर द काइंड ऑफ़ क्वेश्चंस दैट वी कैन
ask dum so like before the podcast you
आस्क दम तो जैसे पडकास्ट से पहले आप
You do research on that thing in every video, right?
रिसर्च करते हो ना हम वो चीज हर वीडियो से
We have done it before as well. then after that we
पहले भी करते हैं। तो फिर हम फिर उसके बाद
The producer talks to all the NGOs who are
द प्रोड्यूसर टॉक्स टू ऑल द एनजीओस हु आर
Working on the ground. all the ngos that
वर्किंग ऑन द ग्राउंड। ऑल द एनजीओस दैट
have worked in dharavi we have talked to end
हैव वर्क्ड इन धारावी वी हैव टॉक टू एंड
then when we are on the ground we are on the
देन व्हेन वी आर ऑन द ग्राउंड वी आर ऑन द
Ground for not one day Ranveer we are not on
ग्राउंड फॉर नॉट वन डे रणवीर वी आर नॉट ऑन
The Ground for Two Days. we are on the ground
द ग्राउंड फॉर टू डेज़। वी आर ऑन द ग्राउंड
For Seven Days and Entire Week at 12 Hours
फॉर सेवन डेज़ एंड एंटायर वीक 12 ऑवर्स पर
Day we are on the ground. just three people but
डे वी आर ऑन द ग्राउंड। जस्ट थ्री पीपल बट
12 Hours on the Ground is a Lot. Specially
12 आवर्स ऑन द ग्राउंड इज़ अ लॉट। स्पेशली
Imagine we are doing a video. Indian i
इमेजिन हमने वीडियो कर रहे हैं। इंडियास
Making a video of the biggest desert.
बिगेस्ट डेजर्ट की वीडियो कर रहे हैं।
literally the temperature said 50 degrees and we
लिटरली द टेंपरेचर सेड 50 डिग्रीज एंड वी
War on the ground. we worked on videos
वर ऑन द ग्राउंड। वी वर्क्ड ऑन वीडियोस
Which are like the wettest place. let it Rain
व्हिच आर लाइक वेटेस्ट प्लेस। बारिश हो
It is complete. Nothing is visible
रही है पूरी। कुछ दिख ही नहीं रहा है
Front. Still we are on the ground. Hour
सामने। स्टिल वी आर ऑन द ग्राउंड। आवर
Cameras R
कैमराज़ आर
Rolling. I would love to tell you about it. V
रोलिंग। आई वुड लव टू टेल यू अबाउट। वी
Will do that in the Hindi segment
विल डू दैट इन द हिंदी वाला सेगमेंट
Where We Talk About the Stories That Have Come
व्हेयर वी टॉक अबाउट द स्टोरीज दैट हैव कम
On from the ground. but what you said that
ऑन फ्रॉम ग्राउंड। बट व्हाट यू सेड दैट
you said that I have the art of translating
यू सेड दैट आई हैव द आर्ट ऑफ ट्रांसलेटिंग
Stories from Ground to Video Its
स्टोरीज फ्रॉम ग्राउंड टू वीडियो इट्स
Meticulously plucked soul of the place soul of
मैटिक्युलसली प्लंड सोल ऑफ द प्लेस सोल ऑफ
the place yes and and very very small
द प्लेस यस एंड एंड वेरी वेरी स्मॉल
things that will be the visual what
थिंग्स दैट व्हाट विल बी द विजुअल व्हाट
will be the angle we plan that also like
विल बी द एंगल वी प्लान दैट आल्सो लाइक
angle in the sense that if you want to make that
एंगल इन द सेंस दैट इफ यू वांट टू मेक दैट
person feel small we will shoot from top if
पर्सन फील स्मॉल वी विल शूट फ्रॉम टॉप इफ
you want to make them feel big we will shoot
यू वांट टू मेक देम फील बिग वी विल शूट
from the bottom so all of those things are
फ्रॉम द बॉटम सो ऑल ऑफ दोज़ थिंग्स आर
Matic Sully Plunged Out and Then We Came Back
मैटिक ुलसली प्लंड आउट एंड देन वी कम बैक
We make four versions of the same video and
वी मेक फोर वर्जनंस ऑफ़ द सेम वीडियो एंड
then i sit with it my teammates think i
देन आई सीट विद इट माय टीममेट्स थिंक आई
I'm crazy they're not sustainable at all
एम क्रेजी दे इट्स नॉट सस्टेनेबल एट आल
It's just crazy to be working with me
इट्स जस्ट क्रेजीनेस टू बी वर्किंग विद मी
hmm but yes it's good it you need to be
हम्म बट यस इट्स गुड इट्स यू नीड टू बी
It's a good idea to grow a little crazy
लिटिल क्रेजी टू ग्रो इट्स अ गुड एज अ
Content Creator I'll tell you my end
कंटेंट क्रिएटर आई विल टेल यू माई एंड आई
love my teams you know we are right now a team
लव माय टीम्स यू नो वी आर राइट नाउ अ टीम
of 15 full time employees four of them took
ऑफ 15 फुल टाइम एम्प्लोएस फोर ऑफ़ देम टूक
their first flight in life because of ours
देयर फर्स्ट फ्लाइट इन लाइफ बिकॉज़ ऑफ़ आवर
Videos. there is a
वीडियोस। देयर इज़ अ
Person who sits in Rajasthan. she is one of
पर्सन हु सीट्स इन राजस्थान। शी इज़ वन ऑफ़
The Best Thumbnail Makers in India. she is
द बेस्ट थंबनेल मेकर्स इन इंडिया। शी इज़
One of the people I work with Sri Ganganagar
वन ऑफ़ द पीपल आई वर्क वि श्रीगंगानगर करके
There is a place. Sitting there he is my prisoner.
एक जगह है। वहां पे बैठ के वो बंदी अपनी।
He is now forming a team of four people. End
उसने अब टीम बना रही है चार लोगों की। एंड
She is the one who is making thumbnails for us.
शी इज़ द वन हु इज़ मेकिंग थंबनेल्स फॉर अस।
Third Eye had a deep mental breakdown. I
थर्ड आई हैड अ डीप मेंटल ब्रेकडाउन। आई
said to one of my producers, he
सेड टू वन ऑफ़ माय प्रोड्यूसर्स, हे
Listen, after being beaten I don't think we
लिसन, आफ्टर बीइंग बीटन आई डोंट थिंक वी
should be continuing this. i don't want my
शुड बी कंटिन्यूइंग दिस। आई डोंट वांट माय
Teammates to be at risk. She Said to Me,
टीममेट्स टू बी एट रिस्क। शी सेड टू मी,
Kavya give me one day, I will figure out a solution
काव्या गिव मी वन डे, आई विल फिगर अ सलूशन
Out. and she got me the number of the NGOs
आउट। एंड शी गॉट मी द नंबर ऑफ़ द एनजीओस
And then we went again. We were able to go
एंड देन वी वेंट अगेन। वी वर एबल टू गो
Again because of the talent that she had. The People
अगेन बिकॉज़ ऑफ द टैलेंट दैट शी हड। द पीपल
that she could contact and get us on the
दैट शी कुड कांटेक्ट एंड गेट अस ऑन द
Ground. Protection. And we speak
ग्राउंड। प्रोटेक्शन। और हम बोलते हैं
Boys protect. hey our brother
लड़के प्रोटेक्ट करते हैं। अरे भाई हमारी
Meet the girls. He is nothing less
लड़कियों से मिलो। वो कुछ कम नहीं है
your boys
तुम्हारे लड़कों
From. End
से। एंड
like one day someone shared a handbook that
लाइक वन डे समवन शेयर्ड अ हैंडबोकुक दैट
Mr. Beast has been created. Ok? this is a
मिस्टर बीस्ट हैज़ क्रिएटेड। ओके? दिस इज़ अ
hand one of my producer has worked with
हैंड वन ऑफ़ माय प्रोड्यूसर हैज़ वर्क्ड विद
mr beast in some of the in some capacity
मिस्टर बीस्ट इन सम ऑफ़ द इन सम कैपासिटी
and he had the hand that mister
एंड ही हैड द हैड अ हैंडब दैट मिस्टर
Beast gives to every new joinee. So, he
बीस्ट गिव्स टू एव्री न्यू जॉइनी। सो, ही
Shared that on the group. the next day
शेयर्ड दैट ऑन द ग्रुप। द नेक्स्ट डे
every member of that of our team had come
एव्री मेंबर ऑफ दैट ऑफ आवर टीम हैड कम
After reading it. no one had told them to
आफ्टर रीडिंग इट। नो वन हैड टोल्ड देम टू
Read it. no one but they had come they red it end
रीड इट। नो वन बट दे हैड कम दे रेड इट एंड
Then they came. r videographer got beaten for
देन दे केम। आर वीडियोग्राफर गॉट बीटन फॉर
As a friend. what will you take? And what else will you take? Any
अस यार। क्या लोगे तुम? और क्या लोगे? कोई
Does he give his beating, who comes, friend?
देता है क्या अपना पिटके कौन आता है यार?
Is it the same guy was outside? no this is a
इज इट द सेम गाय वाज़ आउटसाइड? नो दिस इज़ अ
Freelancer we have taken. but the person is
फ्रीलांसर वी हैव टेकन। बट द पर्सन इज़
Ankit Bishad. He is also a hill
अंकित बिश्ड। वो भी पहाड़ी
Is. So
है। सो
but and i think it's the magic that when you
बट एंड आई थिंक इट्स द मैजिक दैट व्हेन यू
Are a small team that gets the vision
आर अ स्माल टीम दैट विज़न गेट्स
translated that
ट्रांसलेटेड दैट
Energy Energy Gets Translated a Lot to You
एनर्जी एनर्जी गेट्स ट्रांसलेटेड अ लॉट यू
Learn from each other a lot. Very Key
लर्न फ्रॉम ईच अदर अ लॉट। वेरी की
Question. Ok? before you move on into the
क्वेश्चन। ठीक है? बिफोर यू मूव ऑन इंटू द
Next conversation with me.
नेक्स्ट कॉन्वर्सेशन विथ मी।
The
द
Question
क्वेश्चन
is what makes a great title in thumbnail
इज व्हाट मेक्स अ ग्रेट टाइटल इन थंबनेल
In 2025 I Love That Question I Can Talk
इन 2025 आई लव दैट क्वेश्चन आई कैन टॉक
about that question so many thumbnails and
अबाउट दैट क्वेश्चन सो मच थंबनेल्स एंड
titles change with time so what's what
टाइटल्स चेंज विथ टाइम सो व्हाट्स व्हाट्स
The Best Kind of Thumbnails and Titles
द बेस्ट काइंड ऑफ़ थंबनेल्स एंड टाइटल्स
now got it so I would say that for me I
नाउ गॉट इट सो आई वुड से दैट फॉर मी आय
can you talk about me i can't talk about
कैन टॉक अबाउट मी आय कैन नॉट टॉक अबाउट
Any Other Category 2.5 Million Views in 24
एनी अदर कैटेगरी 2.5 मिलियन व्यूज इन 24
Hours 24 Hours 2.5 Million Views Yes
आवर्स 24 आवर्स 2.5 मिलियन व्यूज हां
How I Look at Thumbnails is to Study
हाउ आई लुक एट थंबनेल्स इज टू स्टडी
Outliers. what do we mean by
आउटलाइयर्स। व्हाट डू वी मीन बाय
Outliers? this is a very technical term but
आउटलाइयर्स? दिस वेरी टेक्निकल टर्म बट
this is a very very important term for
दिस इज अ वेरी वेरी इम्पोर्टेन्ट टर्म फॉर
anybody who is now going to become a
एनीवन हु इज नाउ गोइंग टू बिकम अ
Youtuber. Whenever you're scrolling through
यूट्यूबर। व्हेनएवर यू आर स्क्रोलिंग थ्रू
your feed and you find a video by a
योर फीड एंड यू फाइंड अ वीडियो बाय अ
Creator who you usually don't follow. and yet
क्रिएटर हु यू यूजुअली डोंट फॉलो। एंड येट
that has more views than their average number of
दैट हैज़ मोर व्यूज देन देयर एवरेज नंबर ऑफ़
Views. Just Screenshot That Thumbnail and
व्यूज। जस्ट स्क्रीनशॉट दैट थंबनेल एंड
Keep it.
कीप इट।
As Your Inspirational What I Call It Is It
एज योर इंस्पिरेशनल व्हाट आई कॉल इट इज इट
as an inspirational database because something
एज एन इंस्पिरेशनल डेटाबेस बिकॉज़ समथिंग
happened in that video where usually a
हैपेंड इन दैट वीडियो वेयर यूजुअली अ
Creator Would Get 2000 Views But That Gave Them
क्रिएटर वुड गेट 2000 व्यूज बट दैट गव देम
100k views that's an outlier video so
100 के व्यूज दैट्स एन आउटलाइयर वीडियो सो
something happened in their title or thumbnail
समथिंग हैपेंड इन देयर टाइटल ऑर थंबनेल
that work so i have a huge bank of just
दैट वर्क सो आई हैव अ ह्यूज बैंक ऑफ जस्ट
Inspirational Board Now From My
इंस्पिरेशनल बोर्ड नाउ फ्रॉम माय
Inspirational Board What I Have Noticed
इंस्पिरेशनल बोर्ड व्हाट आई हैव नोटिस्ड
is in titles keep it 50 words max 50
इज़ इन टाइटल्स कीप इट 50 वर्ड्स मैक्स 50
Characters Max Doesn't Try To Be
कैरेक्टर्स मैक्स डू नॉट ट्राई टू बी
Clickbaity Do Not Try To Be Following Anyone
क्लिकबेटी डू नॉट ट्राई टू बी फॉलोइंग एनी
sort of format give them what that
सॉर्ट ऑफ फॉर्मेट गिव देम व्हाट दैट
The video is genuinely about which you can be
वीडियो इज जेनुइनली अबाउट व्हिच यू कैन बी
able to which you will be able to do justice
एबल टू व्हिच यू विल बी एबल टू डू जस्टिस
to and do that justice within the first 30
टू एंड डू दैट जस्टिस विथिन द फर्स्ट 30
Seconds for example if I say that I am
सेकंड्स फॉर एग्जांपल इफ आई से दैट आई एम
Going to the hottest place in the first
गोइंग टू द हॉटेस्ट प्लेस इन द फर्स्ट
frame it myself i'll show the temperature the heat
फ्रेम इटसेल्फ आई विल शो द टेंपरेचर द हीट
my shoe is melting the moment some animal dies
माय शू मेल्टिंग द सम एनिमल डाइड सम आई
Will show it in the first. So Be Truthful In
विल शो इट इन द फर्स्ट। सो बी ट्रुथफुल इन
What the title and the thumbnail is. Thumbnails
व्हाट द टाइटल एंड द थंबनेल इज़। थंबनेल
I think that for me what
में मेरे को लगता है कि फॉर मी व्हाट
works is when i show myself in that
वर्क्स इज़ व्हेन आई शो मसेल्फ इन दैट
Space. only three aspects should be only
स्पेस। ओनली थ्री एस्पेक्ट शुड बी ओनली
Three components should be in your thumbnail. Do
थ्री कॉम्पोनेंट शुड बी इन योर थंबनेल। डू
Not over crowded it. think about
नॉट ओवर क्राउडेड इट। थिंक अबाउट
Contrast, Think About
कंट्रास्ट, थिंक अबाउट
colors. A Lot of Times Creators Make This
कलर्स। अ लॉट ऑफ़ टाइम्स क्रिएटर्स मेक दिस
The Mistake That They Want to Templatize
मिस्टेक दैट दे वांट टू टेंपलेटाइज़
Things. Yes, sure that makes your job easy.
थिंग्स। यस, श्योर दैट मेक्स योर जॉब इजी।
so just keep it as simple and as
तो जस्ट कीप इट एज सिंपल एंड एज
As Impactful as Possible. Study I
इंपैक्टफुल एज पॉसिबल। स्टडी आई
can a lot of creators have already made
कैन अ लॉट ऑफ़ क्रिएटर्स हैव ऑलरेडी मेड
Courses have done a lot of YouTube videos
कोर्सेज हैव डन अ लॉट ऑफ़ YouTube वीडियोस
Are out on what makes a great title,
आर आउट ऑन व्हाट मेक्स अ ग्रेट टाइटल,
What makes a great thumbnail. there are a
व्हाट मेक्स अ ग्रेट थंबनेल। देयर आर अ
Lots of also strategies like Paddy Galloway
लॉट ऑफ़ आल्सो स्ट्रेटजीस लाइक पैडी गैलोवे
is the one who works with mr beast and
इज़ द वन हु वर्क्स विद मिस्टर बीस्ट एंड
Who Works With Ryan Rehn. he talks a lot
हू वर्क्स विथ रायन रेहान। ही टॉक्स अ लॉट
About This on His Twitter. there is also
अबाउट दिस ऑन हिज़ ट्विटर। देयर इज़ आल्सो
Colin and Samir who do a lot of podcasts
कॉलिन एंड समीर हु डू अ लॉट ऑफ़ पॉडकास्ट
With very-very famous creators to follow
विथ वेरी-वेरी फेमस क्रिएटर्स टू फॉलो
Them. am john yusufi is a channel name who is a
देम। अम जॉन यूसुफी इज़ अ चैनल नेम हु इज़ अ
Person who worked with YouTube for 15 years.
पर्सन हु वर्कड विद YouTube फॉर 15 इयर्स।
And now he has become a full time creator
एंड नाउ हैज़ बिकम अ फुल टाइम क्रिएटर हु
Makes content for creators. so follow
मेक्स कंटेंट फॉर क्रिएटर्स। सो फॉलो
Creators like that. and it's a very sad
क्रिएटर्स लाइक दैट। एंड इट्स अ वेरी सैड
Reality to say but 30% of your time should be
रियलिटी टू से बट 30% ऑफ़ योर टाइम शुड बी
Spend just the title and thumbnail in a
स्पेंड इन जस्ट द टाइटल एंड थंबनेल इन अ
Video. No matter how beautiful that story is
वीडियो। नो मैटर हाउ ब्यूटीफुल दट स्टोरी
is, if people don't click it, what's the
इज, इफ पीपल डोंट क्लिक इट, व्हाट्स द
Point. we have too many documentaries in
पॉइंट। वी हैव टू मेनी डॉक्युमेंट्रीज इन
India, which are not accessible. and they
इंडिया, व्हिच आर नॉट एक्सेसिबल। एंड दे
Good documentaries. Great
गुड डॉक्यूमेंट्रीज। ग्रेट
Documentaries, Amazing Stories
डॉक्यूमेंट्रीज़, अमेजिंग स्टोरीज़
But people do not sell themselves, yes.
बट पीपल डोंट नॉट सेल देमसेल्व्स, यस।
The pizza box matters as much as a pizza.
पिज़्ज़ा बॉक्स मैटर्स एज़ मच एज अ पिज़्ज़ा।
Agree, Agree the Packaging Matters as Much
अग्रीड, अग्रीड द पैकेजिंग म्याटर्स एस मच
S the thing inside it. At the end of the day,
एस द थिंग इनसाइड इट। एट द एंड ऑफ़ द डे,
what i am doing here right now is
व्हाट आई ऍम डूइंग हियर राइट नाउ इज
Telling Myself. no one can predict
टेलिंग माइसेल्फ। नो वन कैन प्रिडिक्ट
What will happen in the next five years.
व्हाट विल हैपन इन द नेक्स्ट फाइव इयर्स।
but i think you can predict what happens
बट आई थिंक यू कैन प्रिडिक्ट व्हाट हैपन
In the next six to 12 months. Yes. So
इन द नेक्स्ट सिक्स टू 12 मंथ्स। यस। सो
What will happen in the next six to 12
व्हाट विल हैपन इन द नेक्स्ट सिक्स टू 12
Month. Interesting. On Instagram? All three.
मंथ। इंटरेस्टिंग। ऑन Instagram? आल थ्री।
Let's, let's take one at a time. Yes.
लेट्स, लेट्स टेक वन एट अट अ टाइम। यस।
Let's take one at a time. On
लेट्स टेक वन एट अ टाइम। ऑन
Instagram. here is what i think what
Instagram. हियर इज व्हाट आई थिंक व्हाट
will it happen on
विल हैपन ऑन
Instagram? Relatability will always be the
Instagram? रिलेटिबिलिटी विल ऑलवेज बी द
The Key for Instagram Relatability is the key.
की फॉर Instagram रिलेटिबिलिटी इज़ द की।
now i don't mean that relatability has to
नाउ आई डोंट मीन दैट रिलेटिबिलिटी हैज़ टू
Have a set form format. Relatability
हैव अ सेट फॉर्म फॉर्मेट। रिलेटिबिलिटी
Can
कैन
B Very Meta Conversation. but i will tell you
बी वेरी मेटा कन्वर्सेशन। बट आई विल टेल
you in the any time we have had content in
यू इन द एनी टाइम वी हैव हैड कंटेंट इन
This country. there are some things that have
दिस कंट्री। देयर आर सम थिंग्स दैट हैव
Always worked. I will tell you why.
ऑलवेज वर्क्ड। आई विल टेल यू व्हाई।
we play with nostalgia it's always on
नस्टाल्जिया में खेलते हैं वो हमेशा चलता
Is. Why are Cred ads trending these days?
है। क्रेड के एड्स आजकल क्यों चल रहे हैं?
Because he said Alka
क्योंकि उन्होंने अलका
He brought Yaganek along. Ok? So
यागनेक को लेके आए वो। ठीक है? तो
The nostalgia will always last. Nostalgia Cain
नस्टाल्जिया हमेशा चलेगा। नस्टाल्जिया कैन
Be when you talk about things which you
बी व्हेन यू टॉक अबाउट थिंग्स व्हिच यू
Had in your childhood. for example i
हैड इन योर चाइल्डहुड। फॉर एग्जांपल आई
had lunch break at xxx
हैड लंच ब्रेक एट एक्स एक्स
Time. And that is a shared relatable
टाइम। एंड दैट इज़ अ शेयरर्ड रिलेटेबल
The Experience That We Have and Also Has
एक्सपीरियंस दैट वी हैव एंड आल्सो हैज़
Nostalgia attached to it. Ok?
नस्टाल्जिया अटैच्ड टू इट। ठीक है?
Second state pride will last forever because
सेकंडली स्टेट प्राइड हमेशा चलेगी क्योंकि
of the people who connect to their nation and
लोगों की जो कनेक्ट टू देयर नेशन एंड
connect to their state and connect to
कनेक्ट टू देयर स्टेट एंड कनेक्ट टू
whatever dal baati chokha if you say so
व्हाटएवर कि दाल बाटी चोखा अगर तुम कह दो
So Bihari people will come friend. If you
तो बिहारी लोग आएंगे यार। अगर तुम
If you say Bangalore then people will say Bangalore instead of Bengaluru
बेंगलुरु कह दो बेंगलुरु की जगह तो लोग
will come
आएंगे
Buddy. If you say Kannada, people will come, friend. So
यार। कन्नाडा कह दो तो लोग आएंगे यार। तो
Your Nostalgia One Format Which Also
योर नॉस्टाल्जिया वन फॉर्मेट व्हिच आल्सो
The works is mythbreaking. For
वर्क्स इज़ मिथब्रेकिंग। फॉर
For example, South Indians only eat Idly
एग्जांपल कि साउथ इंडियंस ओनली ईड इडली
Dosa. Break that myth. tell me something else
डोसा। ब्रेक दैट मिथ। टेल मी सम अदर
story. All of these are relatable. This
स्टोरी। ऑल ऑफ़ दीज़ आर रिलेटिबल। इसको
How will you make it relatable? Do this. to me this
रिलेटेबल कैसे बनाओगे? यह करो। मेरे को यह
Looks like these buckets will last. these buckets
लगता है कि ये बकेट्स चलेंगी। ये बकेट्स
Are the ones that you talk about. Your Shed
आर द वंस दैट यू टॉक अबाउट। योर शेड
The Identity of Being a Submissive Boyfriend.
आइडेंटिटी ऑफ़ बीइंग अ सबमिसिव बॉयफ्रेंड।
or your identity of being a woman with shot
ओर योर आइडेंटिटी ऑफ़ बीइंग अ वूमन विथ शॉट
Hair. or your identity of being the elder
हेयर। ओर योर आइडेंटिटी ऑफ़ बीइंग दी एल्डर
sister. that elder sisters are crazy
सिस्टर। दैट एल्डर सिस्टर्स आर क्रेजी
About their younger siblings, elder
अबाउट देयर यंगर सिबलिंग्स, एल्डर
Sisters are parents. and you talk about
सिस्टर्स आर पेरेंट्स। ओर यू टॉक अबाउट
Being an army kid. you dids shared
बीइंग एन आर्मी किड। यू दोज़ शेयर्ड
Realities You Have to Figure Out and Make That Happen
रियलिटीज़ यू टू फिगर आउट एंड मेक दैट
Relatable content etcetera. So these shared
रिलेटेबल कंटेंट एटसेट्रा। तो ये शेयरर्ड
Figure out the realities. Inside him I
रियलिटीज़ फिगर आउट करो। उसके अंदर मैंने
Gave five-six buckets. go play with it
पांच छह बकेट्स दे दी। उसमें से खेल लो चल
Will go. Ok? Second, I think that
जाएगा। ठीक है? दूसरा मेरे को लगता है कि
Very good short form films will come out
वेरी गुड शॉर्ट फॉर्म फिल्म्स विल कम आउट
Off Instagram. Have you seen the soham d yes.
ऑफ Instagram। हैव यू सीन द सोहम डी यस।
I love him. He does that brilliantly. Like,
आई लव हिम। ही डस दैट ब्रिलियंटली। लाइक,
I would call them proper films. Or, or.
आई वुड कॉल देम प्रॉपर फिल्म्स। या, या।
Right? he is the most talented young
राइट? ही इज द मोस्ट टैलेंटेड यंग
Director We Have in the Country. Agreed.
डायरेक्टर वी हैव इन द कंट्री। अग्रीड।
And I have seen some professional film
एंड आई हैव सीन सम प्रोफेशनल फिल्म
Directors and he is better than them. Yes.
डायरेक्टर्स एंड ही इज़ बेटर देन देम। यस।
Guys like that need to be given a chance.
गाइज़ लाइक दैट नीड टू बी गिवेन अ चांस।
Agreed. Bollywood will save itself. The Soham
एग्रीड। बॉलीवुड विल सेव इटसेल्फ। द सोहम
Is given a chance. i also think like a
इस गिवेन अ चांस। आई आल्सो थिंक लाइक अ
lot of these rj, harshi,princy,what
लॉट ऑफ दीज़ आरजे, हर्षि, प्रिंसी, व्हाट
they are doing with just one camera are telling
दे आर डूइंग विथ जस्ट वन कैमरा आर टेलिंग
Full all. It feels like you are watching a movie
फुल ऑल। ऐसा लग रहा है मूवी देख के आ रही
I am there in 1 minute. so, even if it will
हूं मैं 1 मिनट में। सो, इवन दो इट विल
Continue to be Continue to stay short
कंटिन्यू टू बी कंटिन्यू टू स्टे शॉर्ट
form and it will continue to be done at a
फॉर्म एंड इट विल कंटिन्यू टू बी डन एट अ
Much lower budget and much more frequency. but the
मच लोअर बजट एंड मच मोर फ्रीक्वेंसी। बट द
The quality will be so refined on Instagram.
क्वालिटी विल बी सो रिफाइंड ऑन Instagram।
I genuinely think so. Third I think
आई जेनुइनली थिंक सो। थर्ड मेरे को लगता
Yes the pace will come down a bit. Like Slower
है पेस थोड़ी नीचे आएगी। जैसे स्लोअर
Content slower content means like
कॉन्टेंट स्लोअर कंटेंट मतलब कि जैसे
Content with feels Content with feels
फील्स वाला कॉन्टेंट फील्स वाला कॉन्टेंट
I will feel connected, that means that once upon a time
मेरे को कनेक्ट फील होगा मतलब वो एक टाइम
when there were subtitles
था जब सबटाइटल्स
This is how those times used to come, people wanted it
ऐसे आते थे दैट टाइम्स गॉन पीपल वांट
pasta not mail puri yes now they have them in my
पास्ता नॉट मेल पूरी हां अब उनको मेरे
Papa says cook food on low flame
पापा कहते हैं खाने को धीमी आंच में पकाना
so that's what we are going to do now
चाहिए सो दैट्स व्हाट्स गोइंग टू नाउ वी
we will move towards i also think on
वी विल मूव टुवर्ड्स आई आल्सो थिंक ऑन
Instagram Monetarily Brands Won't Work
Instagram मोनेटेरियली ब्रांड्स वोंट वर्क
So much with bigger creators as much as they
सो मच विद बिगगर क्रिएटर्स एज़ मच एज़ दे
Will work with Nano creators with very
विल वर्क विद नैनो क्रिएटर्स विद वैरी
Specific niche. or my reading and this is
स्पेसिफिक निश। या माई रीडिंग एंड दिस इज़
A From Conversation I Had With The Boys
अ फ्रॉम कन्वर्सेशन आई हैवड विथ द बॉयज
and monkey
एंड मंकी
ah i think people at the absolute top,
ah आई थिंक पीपल एट दी अबब्सोल्यूट टॉप,
Bindwai will always get work. Second run,
बिंदवाइय विल ऑलवेज गेट वर्क। सेकंड रन,
It's gonna be a little difficult. Agreed End
इट्स गोना बी लिटिल डिफिकल्ट। अग्रीड एंड
Then it goes get democratised. because
देन इट्स गो गेट डेमोक्रेटाइज्ड। बिकॉज़
Everyone becomes a content creator. Agreed. But
एवरीवन बिकम अ कंटेंट क्रिएटर। अग्रीड। बट
you still need to be of a certain quality
यू स्टिल नीड टू बी ऑफ अ सर्टेन क्वालिटी
Even if democratized. I look at it this
इवन इफ डेमोक्रेटाइज्ड। आई लुक एट इट दिस
like either you are the top
लाइक इदर यू आर द टॉप
0.1% and you are great anything below you will
0.1% एंड यू आर ग्रेट एनीथिंग बिलो यू विल
be struggling and the once below will find
बी स्ट्रगलिंग एंड द वंस बिलो विल फाइंड
Some and the other sort of work. what is
सम और दी अदर सॉर्ट ऑफ़ वर्क। व्हाट इज
0.1% now? Neel Mohan The Guy of YouTube
0.1% नाउ? नील मोहन द गाय ऑफ़ YouTube
CEO himself gave this data in one of his
सीईओ ही गव दिस डाटा इन वन ऑफ़ हिज
Releases 1% of yours get a million views
रिलीजेस 1% ऑफ यूर्स गेट अ मिलियन व्यूज
in a month in life time oh so imagine like
इन अ मंथ इन लाइफ टाइम ओ सो इमेजिन लाइक
anyone has a profile right even
एनीवन हैज़ एनीवन हैज़ अ प्रोफाइल राइट इवन
the people who are commenting have a profile to
द पीपल हु आर कमेंटिंग हैव अ प्रोफाइल तो
So many people are claiming to be creators.
कितने सारे लोग तो क्रिएटर बने बैठे हैं।
Out of that, one million people
उसमें से इतने ही लोगों के एक मिलियन आ
have been. 0.1% Ranveer who are the 1% I think
रहे हैं। 0.1% रणवीर हु आर द 1% आई थिंक
0.1% are the ones who have been in this game for
0.1% आर द वंस हु हैव बीन इन दिस गेम फॉर
a certain amount of years who have been in
अ सर्टेन अमाउंट ऑफ इयर्स हु हैव बीन इन
this game for at least three four
दिस गेम फॉर एट लीस्ट थ्री फोर
Years. point 1% are also those who have been
इयर्स। पॉइंट 1% आर आल्सो दोज़ हु हैव बीन
True to their morals. like they haven't
ट्रू टू देयर मोरल्स। लाइक दे हैव नॉट
Worked with waiting apps and they haven't
वर्क्ड विद वेटिंग एप्स और दे हैव नॉट
Worked with scams, schemes. Sense Of
वर्क्ड विद स्कैम्स, स्कीम्स। सेंस ऑफ़
Long term branding yes. a sense of longing
लॉन्ग टर्म ब्रांडिंग यस। अ सेंस ऑफ़ लॉन्ग
Term branding. Third is people who are
टर्म ब्रांडिंग। थर्ड इज़ पीपल हु आर
Conscientiously Innovating
कॉन्सेंटली इनोवेटिंग
Like I think Tanmay Bhat
लाइक आई थिंक तन्मय भट्ट
is god in the indian
इज़ गॉड इन द इंडियन
The ecosystem where he was, he had this IP
इकोसिस्टम व्हेयर ही वाज़ ही हैज़ दिस आईपी
which is so low effort high rewarding will
व्हिच इज़ सो लो एफर्ट हाई रिवॉर्डिंग विल
he will get
ही विल गेट
funny friends of his and just do a live
फनी फ्रेंड्स ऑफ़ हिज़ एंड जस्ट डू अ लाइव
Stream reacting to memes. Convert That
स्ट्रीम रिएक्टिंग टू मीम्स। कन्वर्ट दैट
into a video.
इंटू अ वीडियो।
The perfect amazing format that he has
परफेक्ट अमेजिंग फॉर्मेट दैट ही हैज़
Cracked. he also did vogs he also did
क्रैक्ड। ही आल्सो डीड वॉग्स ही आल्सो डिड
AI stuff with Varun Maya he also head
एआई स्टफ विद वरुण माया ही आल्सो हैड
Some I Think Podcast with Big Basket
सम आई थिंक पॉडकास्ट विद बिग बास्केट
etsetra and he also has moonshine which
एटसेट्रा एंड ही आल्सो हैज़ मूनशाइन व्हिच
is the agency which produces a lot of the
इज़ द एजेंसी व्हिच प्रोड्यूसेस अ लॉट ऑफ़ द
AIDS That We Now See on TV. So Innovation
एड्स दैट वी नाउ सी ऑन टीवी। सो इनोवेशन
In so many levels this has happened. and we
इन सो मेनी लेवल्स हैव हैपेंड। एंड वी
also need creators who know when to say
आल्सो नीड क्रिएटर्स हु नो व्हेन टू से
No. because as soon as you are 100 type
नो। क्योंकि ना जैसे ही तुम 100 के टाइप
what do you become in this field of yours
का बन जाते हो ना इन दिस फील्ड तुम्हारे
So many opportunities come your way.
पास इतनी सारी अपॉर्चुनिटीज़ आती हैं।
Make a course, make merchandise. Hour
कोर्स बना दो, मर्चेंडाइज बना दो। आवर
Focus. yes, you need to be focused on what
फोकस। यस, यू नीड टू बी फोकस्ड ऑन व्हाट
Is it that you want to do? and the other
इज इट दैट यू वांट टू डू? एंड दी अदर
Things How You Can Delegate and Build Up
थिंग्स हाउ कैन यू डेलीगेट और बिल्ड अप
Systems which can do this for you without you
सिस्टम्स व्हिच कैन डू दिस फॉर यू विदाउट
You having to take that earn. Hmm. where
यू हैविंग टू टेक दैट अर्न। हम्म। व्हेयर
Where is the future of YouTube going? YouTube,
इस द फ्यूचर ऑफ़ YouTube गोइंग? YouTube,
S, let's talk about YouTube. what do you
एस, लेट्स टॉक अबाउट YouTube। व्हाट डू यू
Think you've been in this for so long. how
थिंक यू हैव बीन इन दिस फॉर सो लॉन्ग। हाउ
Persia does YouTube change? how has it changed
फारस डस YouTube चेंज? हाउ हैस इट चेंज्ड
Over the years? I think YouTube had become a
ओवर द इयर्स? आई थिंक YouTube हैड बिकम अ
Podcasting Platform for the Last Two
पॉडकास्टिंग प्लेटफॉर्म फॉर द लास्ट टू
Three years. so and you are one of the first
थ्री इयर्स। सो एंड यू आर वन ऑफ़ द फर्स्ट
people who are breaking
पीपल हु ब्रेकिंग
That. The other alternative to podcast was
दैट। दी अदर अल्टरनेटिव टू पडकास्ट वाज़
Dhruvarati charming Mars. That genre.
ध्रुवराटी मोहक मंगल। दैट जॉनर।
I think it's going to be this two Jonas.
आई थिंक इट्स गोइंग टू बी दीज़ टू जॉनस।
Deep Infotainment and Deep Experiential
डीप इंफोटेनमेंट एंड डीप एक्सपीरियंशियल
Content that will grow a lot.
कंटेंट दैट विल ग्रो अ लॉट।
but i do think that both require a lot of
बट आई डू थिंक दैट बोथ रिक्वायर अ लॉट ऑफ
Skills. so if someone wants to crack the
स्किल्स। सो इफ समवन वांट्स टू क्रैक द
The YouTube game they're going to have to upskill you
YouTube गेम दे गोइंग हैव टू अपस्किल अ
Lot. Like you need to know writing. you need
लॉट। लाइक यू नीड टू नो राइटिंग। यू नीड
The Editing You Need to Know How to Use AI
टू एडिटिंग यू नीड नीड टू हाउ टू यूज़ एआई
Tools Efficiently. ah too many things that
टूल्स एफिशिएंटली। अह टू मेनी थिंग्स दैट
Play. so i think it is going to be hard
प्ले। सो आई थिंक इट इज़ गोइंग टू बी हार्ड
But for people who are skilled. it's going to
बट फॉर पीपल हु आर स्किल्ड। इट्स गोइंग टू
Be a smooth process. if they are willing to
बी अ स्मूथ प्रोसेस। इफ दे आर विलिंग टू
put themself in the diet position and I
पुट देमसेल्व इन द ड्याट पोजीशन एंड आई
Feel that you need originality. now like like
फील कि यू नीड ओरिजिनलिटी। नाउ लाइक लाइक
In the podcasting space we see that a lot of
इन द पॉडकास्टिंग स्पेस वी सी कि अ लॉट ऑफ
people copy each other because there is that man that
पीपल कॉपी ईच अदर बिकॉज़ देयर दैट मैन दैट
Happens to any YouTube space but in
हैप्पेंस टू एनी YouTube स्पेस बट इन
what's going to happen now
वॉट्स गोइंग टू हैपन नाउ
ah i think copying wont be possible i think
अह आई थिंक कॉपींग वोंट बी पॉसिबल आई थिंक
I Completely Agree or I Completely Agree
आई कंप्लीटली अग्री या आई कंप्लीटली अग्री
I think what the next future of
आई थिंक व्हाट द नेक्स्ट फ्यूचर ऑफ़
YouTube is there it is going to be the
YouTube इज़ देयर इज गोइंग टू बी द
Creators who stand out are going to be
क्रिएटर्स हु स्टैंड आउट आर गोइंग टू बी
So different in one thing. either it is
सो डिफरेंट इन वन वन थिंग। इदर इट इज़
Research, whether it's the way they're editing,
रिसर्च, इदर इट इज़ द वे दे आर एडिटिंग,
Here It's the Way That They're Going On
इदर इट इज़ द वे दैट दे आर गोइंग ऑन
Ground, or else it is the camera skills
ग्राउंड, ओर इदर इट इज़ द कैमरा स्किल्स
That they have. out of all these things something
दैट दे हैव। आउट ऑफ़ आल दिज़ थिंग्स समथिंग
they are going to master so much that it's not
दे आर गोइंग टू मास्टर सो मच डट इट्स नॉट
Replicable et al. and only when you are
रेप्लिकेबल एट अल। एंड ओनली व्हेन यू आर
with in
विद इन
doz, set highest of doz creators is
दोज़, सेट हाईएस्ट ऑफ़ दोज़ क्रिएटर्स इज़
When you will be able to be the benchmark,
व्हेन यू विल बी एबल टू बी द बेंचमार्क,
otherwise you are lost in the midst of
अदरवाइज़ यू आर लॉस्ट इन द मिड्स ऑफ़
Everything. Yeah. I feel like not just for
एवरीथिंग। याह। आई फील लाइक नॉट जस्ट फॉर
podcast. The over saturation has happened in
पॉडकास्ट। द ओवर सैचुरेशन हैज़ हैपेंड इन
All Categories. Weather It Is Vlogging, Weather
ऑल कैटेगरीज़। वेदर इट इज़ व्लॉगिंग, वेदर
It is entertainment, weather it is news,
इट इज़ एंटरटेनमेंट, वेदर इट इज़ न्यूज़,
Wether it is geopolitics, do you remember
वेदर इट इज़ जिओपॉलिटिक्स, डू यू रिमेंबर
Three years ago when Covid hit.
थ्री इयर्स एगो व्हेन कोविड हैड हिट।
Geopolitics was really a buzzword. End
जिओपॉलिटिक्स वाज़ सच अ बज़वर्ड। एंड
Finance and finance was such a buzzword. For
फाइनेंस एंड फाइनेंस वाज़ सच अ बज़वर्ड। फॉर
Short form finance so much. we saw so many
शार्ट फॉर्म फाइनेंस सो मच। वी सॉ सो मेनी
Finance Creators Coming Up and Then SEBI
फाइनेंस क्रिएटर्स कमिंग अप एंड देन सेबी
did whatever they had to do and then
डिड व्हाटएवर दे हैड टू डू एंड देन
Finance Creators Found It Very Difficult
फाइनेंस क्रिएटर्स फाउंड इट वेरी डिफिकल्ट
Two
टू
Sustain. I Feel Like What I Do Is Not
सस्टेन। आई फील लाइक व्हाट आई डू इज़ नॉट
It's all replicable. because it requires
इट आल रेप्लिककेबल। बिकॉज़ ए इट रिक्वायर्स
A lot of time. be it requires a lot of
अ लॉट ऑफ टाइम। बी इट रिक्वायर्स अ लॉट ऑफ
Economical sustainability to do. see it
इकोनॉमिकल सस्टेनेंस टू डू। सी इट
Requirements
रिक्वायर्स
Your own mental, physical, emotional
योर माय ओन मेंटल, फिजिकल, इमोशनल
Presence. how long am I going to do it
प्रेजेंस। हाउ लॉन्ग एम आई गोइंग टू डू इट
for god knows but to replicate that I think
फॉर गॉड नोस बट टू रेप्लिकेट दैट आई थिंक
is very difficult and that's why it
इज वैरी डिफिकल्ट एंड दैट्स व्हाई इट
also stands out till little bit or i
आल्सो स्टैंड्स आउट टिल लिटिल बिट या आई
Think I had this conversation with Ganesh
थिंक आई हैड दिस कन्वर्सेशन विथ गणेश
from thing school and some version of this
फ्रॉम थिंग स्कूल एंड सम वर्जन ऑफ़ दिस
conversation with nitish bhai as well nitish
कन्वर्सेशन विथ नितीश भाई एस वेल नितीश
Rajput basically uncomprehending content is what
राजपूत बेसिकली अनकपीएबल कंटेंट इज़ व्हाट
will flourish in the next face yes because
विल फ्लरिश इन द नेक्स्ट फेस यस बिकॉज़
YouTube has seen so much I also think
YouTube हैज़ सीन सो मच आई आल्सो थिंक
Audiences Use YouTube from a Perspective
ऑडियंसेस यूज़ YouTube फ्रॉम अ पर्सपेक्टिव
of wanting something different and wanting to
ऑफ़ वांटिंग समथिंग डिफरेंट एंड वांटिंग टू
Be Challenged Internally. i think up till now
बी चैलेंज्ड इंटरनली। आई थिंक अप टिल नाउन
The Last 10 Years It Was Mainly, He Let Me
द लास्ट 10 इयर्स इट वास मेनली, हे लेट मी
Gather Information. which ended in this hole
गैदर इनफार्मेशन। व्हिच एन्डेड इन दिस होल
Podcasting Wave. now there is so much
पॉडकास्टिंग वेव। नाउ देअर सो मच
Information in everyone's heads is what people want
इनफार्मेशन इन एव्रीवंस हेड्स पीपल वांट
To be challenged now. they don't just want to
टू बी चैलेंज्ड नाउ। दे डोंट जस्ट वांट टू
Absorb. A I think your content is very
अब्सोर्ब। अ आई थिंक योर कॉन्टेंट इज़ वैरी
Challenging content. it challenges you to think
चैलेंजिंग कंटेंट। इट चैलेंजज़ यू टू थिंक
About your life. Yes. i also think that
अबाउट योर लाइफ। यस। आई आल्सो थिंक दैट
For a long time, Indian creators thought
फॉर अ लॉन्ग टाइम, इंडियन क्रिएटर्स थॉट
Of their audience dumb. like they thought of them as
ऑफ देयर ऑडियंस डम। लाइक दे थॉट ऑफ देम एज
an audience that needs to be spoon fed and
एन ऑडियंस वि नीड्स टू बी स्पून फेड और वि
needs to be talked about in the words we are
नीड्स टू बी टॉक्ड अबाउट इन वर्ड्स वि आर
very important for either by hyperbole tell
वेरी मेंट फॉर या तो हाइपरबोली करके बता
Or will you treat me like a child and talk to me?
देंगे या फिर बच्चे की तरह ट्रीट करके बात
I will over explain everything to them
करेंगे उनसे हर चीज को ओवर एक्सप्लेन
I think our audience is now very
करेंगे आई थिंक आवर ऑडियंस इज़ नाउ वेरी
smart like they know the basics of what is
स्मार्ट लाइक दे नो द बेसिक्स ऑफ व्हाट इज़
Happening in the country they can get that
हैपनिंग इन द कंट्री दे कैन गेट दैट
Infection from Twitter because Twitter has
इनफेशन फ्रॉम Twitter बिकॉज़ Twitter हैज़
also became a news platform they also
आल्सो बिकम अ न्यूज़ प्लेटफार्म दे आल्सो
Get that information from Instagram because
गेट दैट इनफार्मेशन फ्रॉम Instagram बिकॉज़
Instagram has also become a news
Instagram हाज़ आल्सो बिकम अ न्यूज़
Format. Like, they are getting the news very
फॉर्मेट। लाइक, दे आर गेटिंग द न्यूज़ वैरी
Easily from other formats. so now what
इजीली फ्रॉम अदर फॉर्मेट्स। सो नाउ व्हाट
YouTube Long Form Will Require Is Too
YouTube लॉन्ग फॉर्म विल रिक्वायर इज़ टू
build upon that a layer which is not
बिल्ड अपॉन दैट अ लेयर व्हिच इज नॉट
Available easily in other formats.
अवेलेबल ईजीली इन अदर फॉर्मेट्स।
Perspective Perspective. give them something
पर्सपेक्टिव पर्सपेक्टिव। गिव देम समथिंग
that they can share with them
दैट दे कैन शेयर विद देयर
Friends after words. Like But One
फ्रेंड्स आफ्टर वर्ड्स। लाइक बट वन
the question i was asking from you was how did you
क्वेश्चन आय ह्यड फ्रॉम यू वाज़ हाउ डिड यू
Use short form? how did you use reels,
यूज़ शार्ट फॉर्म? हाउ डिड यू यूज़ रील्स,
Instagram, Shorts to Get People to Watch
Instagram, शॉर्ट्स टू गेट पीपल टू वॉच
Long Format Es Well? the way i look at
लॉन्ग फॉर्मेट एस वेल? द वे आई लुक एट
Short Content Each short content piece has to
शार्ट कंटेंट ईच शॉर्ट कंटेंट पीस हैज़ टू
Be Treated as Its Own Spectacle and You
बी ट्रीटेड एस इट्स ओन स्पेक्टिकल एंड यू
Do the best with that. there four they will get
डू द बेस्ट विथ दैट। देयर फोर दे विल गेट
The Max Algorithmic Reach. and then that
द मैक्स एल्गोरिथमिक रीच। एंड देन दैट
Algorithmic Reach Trans May Be Translates
एल्गोरिथमिक रीच ट्रांस मे बी ट्रांसलेट्स
To your long form. i don't think everyone
टू योर लॉन्ग फॉर्म। आई डोंट थिंक एव्रिवन
Who sees all your short content pieces
हु सीस ऑल योर शार्ट कंटेंट पीसेस
Transitions into Watching the Long Form
ट्रांजिशन्स इनटू वाचिंग द लॉन्ग फॉर्म
Grind. Hmm. ah and i do think that's the man
पीस। हम्म। अह एंड आई डु थिंक दैट द मेन
purpose we are doing podcasting in the
पर्पस वी आर डूइंग पॉडकास्टिंग इन द
Modern Days to Actually Hack Everyone
मॉडर्न डेज टू एक्चुअली हैक एव्रिवनस
Short Content Algorithms. hmm i think
शोर्ट कंटेंट एल्गोरिदम्स। हम् अ आई थिंक
Podcasting as a skill is very difficult
पॉडकास्टिंग एज अ स्किल इज वैरी डिफिकल्ट
To Crack In The Long Term People Think It's
टू क्रैक इन द लॉन्ग टर्म पीपल थिंक इट्स
easy that just sit but when u put al social
ईजी कि जस्ट सीट बट व्हेन यू पुट अल सोशल
Media Logic Intuit It. it's not i think
मीडिया लॉजिक इंटूट इट। इट्स नॉट आई थिंक
Content Always Works on Demand and
कंटेंट ऑलवेज वर्क्स ऑन अ डिमांड एंड
Supply as a situation. Right Now the Supply
सप्लाई एज़ अ सिचुएशन। राइट नाउ द सप्लाई
of podcasts is more than the demand of
ऑफ़ पॉडकास्ट इज़ मोर देन द डिमांड ऑफ़
podcast. so all the top people will keep
पॉडकास्ट। सो ऑल द टॉप पीपल विल कीप
Getting Views and Will Keep
गेटिंग व्यूज एंड विल कीप
Growing. the problem they are facing is that
ग्रोइंग। द प्रॉब्लम दे आर फेसिंग इज दैट
We are running out of guests in India?
वी आर रनिंग आउट ऑफ गेस्ट इन इंडिया?
How Many People Are Actually Podcast
हाउ मेनी पीपल आर एक्चुअली पॉडकास्ट
Material. so many people are getting over
मटेरियल। सो मेनी पीपल आर गेटिंग ओवर
Exposed. So here you go global. and you
एक्सपोज्ड। सो इदर यू गो ग्लोबल। एंड यू
Continue a podcasting game. and you play some
कंटिन्यू अ पडकास्टिंग गेम। ओर यू प्ले सम
Another game. and at least what I have seen
अदर गेम। एंड एटलीस्ट व्हाट आई हैव सीन
Over the last decade of YouTube being. I
ओवर द लास्ट डेकेड ऑफ़ YouTube बीइंग। आई
always think it's place of more play a new
ऑलवेज थिंक इट प्लेस ऑफ मोर प्ले अ न्यू
game. like it's just what they're keeping
गेम। लाइक इट जस्ट व्हाट दे कीपिंग की
Reinvention is too important in the long run
रीइनेंशन इज टू इम्पोर्टेन्ट इन द लॉन्ग
Term. So that's just what I think. Got
टर्म। सो दैट्स जस्ट व्हाट आई थिंक। गॉट
It. and i am curious to see what
इट। एंड आई एम क्यूरियस टू सी कि व्हाट
What happens in the next phase? Got it. Now
हप्पेंस इन द नेक्स्ट फेस? गॉट इट। नाउ
how do you build
हाउ डू यू बिल्ड
Fathom? In the Next Year, How Do You Build
फैटम? इन द नेक्स्ट ईयर, हाउ डू यू बिल्ड
Fathom? I was talking to the YouTube partner
फैटम? आई वास टॉकिंग टू द YouTube पार्टनर
manager and she gave me an inside which made
मैनेजर एंड शी गव मी एन इनसाइड व्हिच मेड
I am very sad.
मी वैरी सैड।
it is like the views that we only get some 10
इट इज़ लाइक द व्यूज दैट वी गेट ओनली सम 10
15% off it are recurring views. so even two
15% ऑफ़ इट आर रेकरिंग व्यूज। सो इवन दो
there are great views the recurringness of it
देयर आर ग्रेट व्यूज द रेकरिंगनेस ऑफ़ इट
It is very less. and i think that's that number
इज़ वेरी लेस। एंड आई थिंक दैट दैट नंबर
Needs to increase. People Need to Keep Coming
नीड्स टू इंक्रीस। पीपल नीड टू कीप कमिंग
Back. Keep coming back, keep coming back. But
बैक। कीप कमिंग बैक, कीप कमिंग बैक। बट
for a category like ours it's very
फॉर अ कैटेगरी लाइक आउर्स इट्स वेरी
Difficult because to a large extent people
डिफिकल्ट बिकॉज़ टु अ लार्ज एक्सटेंट पीपल
are watching what i am creating basis the
आर वाचिंग व्हाट आई ऍम क्रिएटिंग बेसिस द
topic like they are interest they are very
टॉपिक लाइक दे आर इंटरेस्ट दे आर वैरी
Clickbaited by that intriguing thumbnail
क्लिकबेटेड बाई दैट थंबनेल इंट्रिगिंग
the image in that thumbnail that title the
इमेज इन दैट थंबनेल दैट टाइटल द
Introduction Versus When People Are Watching
इंट्रोडक्शन वर्सेस व्हेन पीपल आर वाचिंग
Vlogs they are so deeply involved that
व्लॉग्स दे आर सो डीपली इनवॉल्वड दैट
Everyday they will just watch us for 15 minutes
एवरीडे दे विल जस्ट वॉच हम 15 मिनट्स ऑफ
what happened in her life what happened in
व्हाट हैपेंड इन हर लाइफ व्हाट हैपेंड इन
His Life Is the Same When It's Just a Talk
हिज लाइफ सेम विद व्हेन इट्स जस्ट अ टॉक
show where people are talking about it or else
शो वेयर पीपल आर टॉकिंग अबाउट इट या फिर
react videos if or if
रिएक्ट वीडियोस अगर होती हैं या फिर अगर
If gaming happens then there is very little effort in it
गेमिंग होता है तो उसमें बहुत एफर्ट कम
it seems you are doing this with the intention of loving it
पड़ता है तुम उसको चाह के कर रहे हो इसमें
Most of the views I am getting are from
मेरे जो व्यूज आ रहे हैं वो ज्यादातर
The views are coming
व्यूज आ रहे
are from new
हैं फ्रॉम न्यूर
audiences and I think what changes that is
ऑडियंसेस एंड आई थिंक व्हाट चेंजेस दैट इज़
When I Build a Community Where I Am
व्हेन आई बिल्ड अ कम्युनिटी व्हेयर आई एम
also talking to them like what i will
आल्सो टॉकिंग टू देम लाइक व्हाट आई विल
what to try to do in the coming one year is i will
ट्राई टू डू इन द कमिंग वन ईयर इज़ आई विल
try to take up topics which are being
ट्राई टू टेक अप टॉपिक्स व्हिच आर बीइंग
Suggested by my comments section. I will
सजेस्टेड बाय माय कमेंट्स सेक्शन। आई विल
Give them a shout out in the video itself. I
गिव देम शाउट आउट इन द वीडियो इटसेल्फ। आई
Will there be some people on the ground.
विल मे बी गेट सम ऑफ़ द पीपल ऑन ग्राउंड।
By the way we have amazing people we work with
बाइ द वे वी हैव अमेजिंग पीपल वी वर्क विथ
On ground. like most of the people that
ऑन ग्राउंड। लाइक मोस्ट ऑफ़ द पीपल दैट
Follow us we reached out to them only. Give
फॉलो अस वी रीच्ड आउट टू देम ओनली। दे
Become our on ground producers. so to
बिकम आवर ऑन ग्राउंड प्रोड्यूसर्स। सो टू
Build up a human connection like that. And
बिल्ड अप अ ह्यूमन कनेक्शन लाइक दैट। और
To come on more lives, to be just more
टू कम ऑन मोर लाइफ्स, टू बी जस्ट मोर
Authentic like to just be more present,
ऑथेंटिक लाइक टू जस्ट बी मोर प्रेजेंट,
Real, Authentic That's What I Think Needs to Be
रियल, ऑथेंटिक दैट आई थिंक नीड्स टू बी
Figure it out. For example, what I mean by
फिगर आउट। फॉर एग्जांपल, व्हाट आई मीन बाय
that is in a way whatever you are creating
दैट इज़ इन अ वे व्हाटएवर यू आर क्रिएटिंग
It needs to have a vlog element into it.
इट नीड्स टू हैव अ व्लॉग एलिमेंट इंटू इट।
Even like a podcast doesn't have a vlog.
इवन लाइक अ पॉडकास्ट डज़ंट हैव अ व्लॉग।
like a
लाइक अ
unscripted you are not being put into a
अनस्क्रिप्टेड यू आर नॉट बीइंग पुट इंटू अ
Raw situation. Which is out of your control.
रॉ सिचुएशन। व्हिच इज़ आउट ऑफ़ योर कंट्रोल।
This is a very controlled environment.
दिस इज़ वेरी कंट्रोलोल्ड एनवायरमेंट।
That is where the vulgarity of it comes. So
दैट दैट इज वेयर द वॉगनेस ऑफ इट कम्स। सो
You need to bring some runes, some reality into you
यू नीड टू ब्रिंग सम रनेस, सम रियलिटी इनू
Your content to build fandom. I feel you
योर कंटेंट टू बिल्ड फेंडम। आई फील यू
Think Vlogs Will Survive Long Term? No
थिंक व्लॉग्स विल सर्वाइव लॉन्ग टर्म? नो
No? no i think vlog style
नो? नो आई थिंक व्लॉग स्टाइल
Documentary Might Self. Yes. I think
डॉक्यूमेंट्री माइट सेल्फ। यस। आई थिंक
That's the new genre. but you know, there is
दैट्स द न्यू जॉनर। बट यू नो, देयर इज़
Lots of channels which analyse. Yes. So,
लॉट्स ऑफ़ चैनल्स व्हिच एनालाइज। यस। सो,
I think this is just an attempt. I C
आई थिंक दिस इज जस्ट आर, अटेम्प्ट। आई सी
sony channels have 200k and 100k
सोनी चैनल्स हैव 200 के ओर 100 के
Analyzing why a YouTuber had a
एनालाइजिंग व्हाई अ YouTuber हैड अ
The Downfall Why Bollywood Is Falling Or You Need To
डाउनफॉल व्हाई बॉलीवुड इजिंग या यू नीड टू
be in a position of authority to put that out
बी इन अ पोजीशन ऑफ़ अथॉरिटी टू पुट आउट दैट
Kind of Content and Those Are Just Opinions
काइंड ऑफ कंटेंट एंड दोज़ आर जस्ट ओपिनियंस
That is what you feel that is not the gospel
दैट इज व्हाट यू फील दैट इज नॉट द गोस्पेल
truths yes i think that there needs to be
ट्रू्स यस आई थिंक दैट देयर नीड्स टू बी
Sum Sort
सम सॉर्ट
Off
ऑफ़
ingenuity greatness uniqueness rawness that
इनजेनुनिटी ग्रेटनेस यूनिकनेस रॉनेस दैट
you need to bring whatever it is through to
यू नीड टू ब्रिंग वेदर इट इज़ थ्रू टू
yours how you are handling the camera how you are
योर हाउ यू आर हैंडलिंग द कैमरा हाउ यू आर
Telling the Story How You're Putting the
टेलिंग द स्टोरी हाउ यू आर पुटिंग द
thumbnail whatever there are so many things
थंबनेल व्हाटएवर देयर आर सो मेनी थिंग्स
That goes into making a YouTube video
दैट गोज़ इनटू मेकिंग अ YouTube वीडियो
Grab one of those things and use it your way
उनमें से एक चीज़ पकड़ लो उसको अपने तरीके
do it differently and do it the best
से अलग तरीके से कर लो एंड डू इट द बेस्ट
It's possible that I think I'll survive in a way
पॉसिबल दैट विल आई थिंक इन अ वे सर्वाइव
Like for example if we have to say we see
लाइक फॉर एग्जांपल इफ वी हैव टू से वी सी
Apuvaa growing so much right there is
अपूवा ग्रोइंग सो मच राइट देयर इज़
No genius videography in it there is no
नो जीनियस वीडियोग्राफी इन इट देयर इज़ नो
Genius Thumbnail and Title No Retention
जीनियस थंबनेल और टाइटल नो रिटेंशन
Technics Etcetra She is Just Cracked
टेक्निक्स एटसेट्रा शी इज़ जस्ट क्रैक्ड
How to Tell a Relatable Story in a Funny Story
हाउ टू टेल अ रिलेटेबल स्टोरी इन अ फनी
Manor and Keep Retaining Keep Retaining Till
मैनर एंड कीप रिटेनिंग कीप रिटेनिंग टिल
the end that story has to be told in a way
दी एंड दैट स्टोरी टू बी टोल्ड इन अ वे
that people get written till the end and then she
दैट पीपल गेट रिटेन टिल दी एंड सो शी
Crack That vs There Are a Lot
क्रैक दैट वर्सेस देयर आर अ लॉट
Of Ranveer Singh there are 40-40 million views on
ऑफ़ रणवीर देर आर 40-40 मिलियन व्यूज ऑन
The videos that people from the South are making
वीडियोस दैट पीपल फ्रॉम द साउथ आर मेकिंग
And there are full-fledged films they feel like
एंड देयर फुल फ्लेजेड फिल्म्स दे फील लाइक
Films on YouTube and They Have Cracked
फिल्म्स ऑन YouTube एंड दे हैव क्रैक्ड
Cinema Dev Cracked The Story Telling. So
सिनेमा देव क्रैक्ड द स्टोरी टेलिंग। सो
That works. What we have cracked is an
दैट वर्क्स। व्हाट वी हैव क्रैक्ड इज़ एन
on ground journalistic on ground
ऑन ग्राउंड जर्नलिस्टिक ऑन ग्राउंड
Vlogging is a sort of category which might
व्लॉगिंग सॉर्ट ऑफ़ अ कैटेगरी व्हिच माइट
work. on ground documentary which
वर्क। ऑन ग्राउंड डॉक्यूमेंट्री व्हिच
Might work. so, whatever you can fit into
माइट वर्क। सो, व्हाटएवर यू कैन फिट इनटू
In that narrative will work.
इन दैट नैरेटिव विल वर्क।
Little random question. Please tell. are in touch
लिटिल रैंडम क्वेश्चन। बोलो ना। आर इन टच
With your college friends? Yes. yes, i am in
विथ योर कॉलेज फ्रेंड्स? यस। यस, आई एम इन
Touch With. And you are 97 all, right. So 27
टच विद। एंड यू आर 97 ऑल, राइट। सो 27
Years old. 27. So When You Meet Yours
इयर्स ओल्ड। 27. सो व्हेन यू मीट योर
College friends, do they understand how much
कॉलेज फ्रेंड्स, डु दे अंडरस्टैंड हाउ मच
Are you changing? and the second question is
यू आर चेंजिंग? एंड द सेकंड क्वेश्चन इज़
what are the changes because of all this
व्हाट आर द चेंजेस बिकॉज़ ऑफ़ ऑल दिस
Experience. Like on a human level,
एक्सपीरियंस। लाइक ऑन अ ह्यूमन लेवल,
When you are going to Dharavi, when you
व्हेन यू आर गोइंग टू धारावी, व्हेन यू
going to that -60 degrees place in the
गोइंग टू दैट -60 डिग्रीज़ प्लेस इन द
Hills, wherever, ah how have you
हिल्स, व्हेन जहां भी, अह हाउ हैव यू
Changed on a human level? every video
चेंज्ड ऑन अ ह्यूमन लेवल? एव्री वीडियो
changes me, when I come back from a
चेंजेस मी, व्हेन आई कम बैक फ्रॉम अ
Shoot, I'm a different person, every time.
शूट, आई एम अ डिफरेंट पर्सन, एवरी टाइम।
I feel that it gives me the strength to not
आई फील दैट इट गिव्स मी द स्ट्रेंथ टू नॉट
worry about my worries because my worries are
वरी अबाउट माय वरीस बिकॉज़ माय वरीस आर
nothing. hum we live in a country ranveer ware
नथिंग। हम वी लिव इन अ कंट्री रणवीर वेयर
The Reality Is Very
द रियलिटी इज वेरी
Bad. I do get comments. We people
बैड। मेरे तो कमेंट्स आ जाते हैं। हम लोग
a video whenever we release any video the
एक वीडियो व्हेनएवर वी रिलीज़ एनी वीडियो द
Majority of the comments we get is I used
मेजोरिटी ऑफ़ द कमेंट्स वी गेट इज़ आई यूज्ड
to think my life is difficult but this is
टू थिंक माय लाइफ इज डिफिकल्ट बट दिस इज
Crazy. Perspective Building Content.
क्रेजी। पर्सपेक्टिव बिल्डिंग कंटेंट।
changes your reality completely shifts all
चेंजेस योर रियलिटी कंप्लीटली शिफ्ट्स ऑल
together but to answer your question of when
टुगेदर बट टू आंसर योर क्वेश्चन ऑफ व्हेन
i meet my friends what do they think
आई मीट माय फ्रेंड्स व्हाट डू दे थिंक
recently i met a school
रिसेंटली आई मेट अ स्कूल
friend and she was saying to me that if
फ्रेंड एंड शी वास सेइंग टू मी दैट इफ
anyone from our school could be doing this
एनीवन फ्रॉम आवर स्कूल कुड बी डूइंग दिस
we knew it was
वी न्यू इट वाज़
you because you know these over achiever kids in
यू बिकॉज़ यू नो दीज़ ओवर अचीवर किड्स इन
Schools who would be participating be
स्कूलज़ हु वुड बी पार्टिसिपेटिंग बी
Everywhere I Was
एवरीवेयर आई वाज़
that even in my college i got the best in
ड्यात इवन इन माय कॉलेज आई गॉट द बेस्ट इन
Dramatics Award. I was the topper in my
ड्रामेटिक्स अवार्ड। आई वाज़ द टॉपर इन माय
Class while doing dramatics. even in
क्लास व्हाइल डूइंग ड्रामेटिक्स। इवन इन
My Masters I was the best student.
माय मास्टर्स आई वाज़ द बेस्ट स्टूडेंट।
and so people new i just fear that there
एंड सो पीपल न्यू आई जस्ट फियर दैट देयर
there will be a day where everything will break
विल बी अ डे व्हेयर एवरीथिंग विल ब्रेक
Down. in the sense i fear that i will have a
डाउन। इन द सेंस आई फियर दैट आई विल हैव अ
Massive breakdown. and then i will be
मैसिव ब्रेकडाउन। एंड देन आई विल बी
Paralyzed to not work at all. and that's
पैरालाइज्ड टू नॉट वर्क एट ऑल। एंड दैट्स
a deep fear i have because i drive a lot
अ डीप फियर आई हैव बिकॉज़ आई डिराइव अ लॉट
of my sense of identity from my work
ऑफ माय सेंस ऑफ आइडेंटिटी फ्रॉम माय वर्क
and it's a bad thing to say but I derive a
एंड इट्स अ बैड थिंग टू से बट आई डिराइव अ
Lots of dopamine from the views I get |
लॉट ऑफ डोपामिन फ्रॉम द व्यूज आई गेट |
From the comments that I get | and its
फ्रॉम द कमेंट्स दैट आई गेट | एंड इट्स
Not bad friend, it's fine. yes i mean
बैड नहीं यार इट्स फाइन | हां मतलब मेरे
who feels it is necessary or you know when this
को लगता है जरूरी है | या यू नो व्हेन दिस
controversy when i could not create
कंट्रोवर्सी व्हेन आई कुड नोट क्रिएट
content because sc head told not to
कॉन्ट्रेंट बिकॉज़ एस सी हेड टोल्ड नॉट टू
Create what? I was what would you do? I
क्रिएट व्हाट? आई वाज व्हाट विल यू डू? आई
Vaj take some sleep. I was so low not because we
वाज सो लो। आई वाज सो लो नॉट बिकॉज़ वी
creating vert just because i wasn't
वर्ट क्रिएटिंग जस्ट बिकॉज़ आई वाजंट
Working. I'm very used to being at
वर्किंग। आई एम वैरी यूज्ड टू बीइंग एट
work. Keeping my mind active. Yes. I
वर्क। कीपिंग माई माइंड एक्टिव। यस। आई
think that was the saddest i've been in 10
थिंक दैट वाज द सैडेस्ट है आईव बीन इन 10
Years. Because I have my hands towards you. Eye Kudnant
इयर्स। बिकॉज़ आई माई हैंड्स ओर। आय कुडनंट
Release Anything Couldn't Work. and also
रिलीज़ एनीथिंग कुड नॉट्ट वर्क। एंड आल्सो
When You're Not Releasing Things, You're Not
व्हेन यू नॉट रिलीजिंग थिंग्स, यू आर नॉट
In touch with where your audience is. so i felt
इन टच विथ वेर योर ऑडियंस इस। सो आई फेल्ट
like as an island alone and some plane head to
लाइक आस् आइलैंड अलोन एंड सम प्लेन हेड टू
Come in like rescue. That was the feel. how
कम इन लाइक रेस्क्यू। दैट वाज द फील। हाउ
did you feel when you put that first
डिड यू फील व्हेन यू पुट दैट फर्स्ट
Video out after the controversy? it's
वीडियो आउट आफ्टर द कंट्रोवर्सी? इट्स
Thinking about the second video.
थिंकिंग अबाउट द सेकंड वीडियो।
I get that. Putting Intensity Ends Two
आई गेट द्याट। पुटिंग इंटेंसिटी एंड टू
thinking because also it was true it was true
थिंकिंग बिकॉज़ अल्सो इट वाज सच अ इट सच अ
Weird situation, man. you know like, we are
वियर्ड सिचुएशन, यार। यू नो लाइक, वी आर
Not PR professionals. I am N
नॉट पीआर प्रोफेशनल्स। आई एम एन
Engineering Grad. I live life like an
इंजीनियरिंग ग्रैड। आई लिव लाइफ लाइक एन
Engineer. So I had to engineer the situation.
इंजीनियर। सो आई टू इंजीनियर द सिचुएशन।
and honestly it was a bill back like so much
एंड ऑनेस्टली इट वाज अ बिल बैक लाइक सो मच
has been lost. Feels very tough and dry
हैज़ बीन लॉस्ट। फील वैरी टफ एंड ड्राई
Now. now i'm just going to create the
नाउ। नाउ आई एम जस्ट गोइंग टू क्रिएट द
Content That I Really Really Want How Do You
कंटेंट दैट आई रियली रियली वांट हाउ डू यू
What do you think journalists feel about you? I I have a
थिंक जर्नलिस्ट फील अबाउट यू? आई आई हैव अ
Lots to Say Likes About How Journalists Feel
लॉट टू से लाइक अबाउट हाउ जर्नलिस्ट फील
about me which I got to know at last
अबाउट मी व्हिच हेव गट टू नो इन द लास्ट
Three Months and I Think People Who Can Read
थ्री मंथ्स एंड आई थिंक पीपल हु कैन रीड
Between the lines understand what happened.
बिटवीन द लाइंस अंडरस्टैंड व्हाट हपेंड।
Yes. I know no matter how correct I am. Annie
यस। आई नो नो मैटर हाउ करेक्ट आई एम। एनी
Day can come where I'll become a headline. Gate
डे कैन कम वेर आई विल बिकम अ हेडलाइन। गेट
tossed around my image will be in all the
टॉस्ड अराउंड माय इमेज विल बी इन ऑल द
News Memes Pages Etc No Matter How
न्यूज़ मीम्स पेजेस एटसेट्रा नो मैटर हाउ
correct i am you ready for that reality
करेक्ट आई एम आर यू रेडी फॉर दैट रियलिटी
yes and if I'm in this field I have to
यस एंड इफ आई एम इन दिस फील्ड आई हैव टू
be mentally anybody who is in this field ranvir
बी मेंटली एनीवन हु इज इन दिस फील्ड रणवीर
you will know this has to have
यू विल नो दिस हैस टू हैव
That Very Strong Army Mama Mindset
दैट वेरी स्ट्रांग आर्मी मामा माइंडसेट
that come at me bro come at me what people
दैट कम एट मी ब्रो कम एट मी व्हाट पीपल
don't understand come at me but having said
डोंट अंडरस्टैंड कम एट मी बट हैविंग सेड
that's that i also do a lot of background
दैट दैट आई आल्सो डु अ लॉट ऑफ़ बैकग्राउंड
Work on Any Sentence That We Say Have to Have
वर्क ऑन एनी सेंटेंस दैट वी से हैज़ टू हैव
Three fact check sources. any information
थ्री फैक्ट चेक सोर्सेस। एनी इनफार्मेशन
that we put out has to cross certain
दैट वी पुट आउट हाज़ टू क्रॉस सर्टेन
Systems and Procedures and I Can't
सिस्टम्स एंड प्रोसीजर्स एंड आई कैन नॉट
be untrue and unauthentic to the audience that
बी अनट्रू और अनऑथेंटिक टू द ऑडियंस दैट
I am talking to you. we have very strong
आई एम टॉकिंग टू। वी हैव वेरी स्ट्रांग
Systems to ensure that. a lot of the time
सिस्टम्स टू एनश्योर दैट। अ लॉट ऑफ़ द टाइम
We get a lot of sponsorship deals by
वी गेट अ लॉट ऑफ स्पॉन्सरशिप डील्स बाय
very big business houses and then that nay
वेरी बिग बिज़नेस हाउसेस एंड देन दैट नै
And we have worked also but then the narrative
एंड वी हैव वर्क्ड आल्सो बट देन द नैरेटिव
has to be there way we have to tell the story
हैज़ टू बी देयर वे वी हैव टू टेल स्टोरी
That they have to tell I love YouTube I think
दैट दे हैव टू टेल आई लव YouTube आई थिंक
YouTube is the way forward for any format
YouTube इज द वे फॉरवर्ड फॉर एनी फॉर्मेट
of Content Weather It Is Podcast Weather It Is
ऑफ कंटेंट वेदर इट इज़ पॉडकास्ट वेदर इट इज़
Radio Weather It Is TV There Is I Think
रेडियो वेदर इट इज़ टीवी देअर इज आई थिंक
Now in the US there is 50% off YouTube
नाउ इन द यूएस देअर इज़ 50% ऑफ YouTube इज़
Being consumed on television isn't that
बीइंग कंज्यूूम्ड ऑन टेलीविज़न इजंट दैट
beautiful like we have seen when we make
ब्यूटीफुल लाइक वी हैव सीन व्हेन वी मेक
Beautiful Videos of the Ones That Have Drones
ब्यूटीफुल वीडियोस द वंस दैट हैव ड्रोन
Shots and Talks About Positivity
शॉट्स एंड टॉक्स अबाउट पॉजिटिविटी
Viewership is more on TV than on mobile
व्यूअरशिप इज मोर ऑन टीवी देन ऑन मोबाइल
phones and that was unbelievable for me but
फोन्स एंड दैट वाज़ अनबिलीवेबल फॉर मी बट
now it is true i also think that people you
नाउ इट इज ट्रू आई आल्सो थिंक दैट पीपल यू
no why i am
नो व्हाई आई एम
saying journalists should learn from
सेइंग जर्नलिस्ट शुड लर्न फ्रॉम
me is
मी इज
because people will pay me in our last video
बिकॉज़ पीपल विल पे मी इन आवर लास्ट वीडियो
we got ₹1 lakh just super thanks us
वी गॉट ₹1 लाख जस्ट एस सुपर थैंक्स हम
People gave ₹40 each but which other creator
₹40-40 दिए लोगों ने बट व्हिच अदर क्रिएटर
in india is getting direct pay for there
इन इंडिया इज गेटिंग डायरेक्ट पे फॉर देयर
Content Accept Kunal Kambra When When
कंटेंट एक्सेप्ट कुणाल कांबरा व्हेन व्हेन
he puts stuff on youtube again what you
ही पुट्स स्टफ ऑन YouTube अगेन व्हाट यू
said no that you need a little mamba mentality
सेड नो कि यू नीड अ लिटिल मांबा मेंटालिटी
Tiger Mentality in Content I Think Most
टाइगर मेंटालिटी इन कंटेंट आई थिंक मोस्ट
Content creators have it that's how they do it
कॉन्टेंट क्रिएटर्स हैव इट दैट्स हाउ दे
Reach that point. Family Usually Don't
रीच दैट पॉइंट। फैमिली यूजुअली डोंट
Understand. The family get very scared.
अंडरस्टेंस। फैमिली गेट वैरी स्केयर्ड।
Yes. I think that we are at this junction in
यस। आई थिंक दैट वी आर एट दिस जंक्चर इन
Content creation where any media other than
कंटेंट क्रिएशन वेयर एनी मीडिया अदर देन
YouTube, Instagram are against content
YouTube, Instagram इज़ अगेंस्ट कंटेंट
Creators. I am jealous. Content Creators
क्रिएटर्स। जेलसी है। कंटेंट क्रिएटर्स
How are you getting so many views? Utters
कैसे इतने व्यूज लेके आ रहे हैं? यूटर्स
How are you getting these views? so one one
कैसे व्यूज लेके आ रहे हैं। तो एक एक
there is jealousy and there is a there is like
जेलसी है एंड देयर इज़ अ देयर इज़ लाइक
Traditional Media Is Looking for Ways to
ट्रेडिशनल मीडिया इज़ लुकिंग फॉर वेज़ टू
Jump on Any Controversy That Happens For
जंप ऑन एनी कंट्रोवर्सी दैट हैपेंस फॉर
Any Sort of Content Creator and the Minute
एनी सॉर्ट ऑफ़ कंटेंट क्रिएटर एंड द मिनट
anything happens all of them will use the faces
एनीथिंग हैपेंस ऑल ऑफ़ देम विल यूज़ द फेसेस
of the content creators and will try there
ऑफ़ द कंटेंट क्रिएटर्स एंड विल ट्राई देयर
TRAI wants their TRP to increase. Whether he
ट्राई कि उनकी टीआरपी आगे बढ़े। चाहे वो
The smallest thing will become the biggest thing
छोटी से छोटी चीज होगी बड़ी से बड़ी चीज
It will be. do you think it's a combination of
होगी। डू यू थिंक इट्स अ कॉम्बिनेशन ऑफ़
Jealousy as well as a clickbait. because when
जेलेसी एज वेल एज अ क्लिकबेट। बिकॉज़ व्हेन
You have a famous content face, yes. you just
यू हैव अ फेमस कंटेंट फेस, यस। यू जस्ट
Get More Click. I think there are three things.
गेट मोर क्लिक। आई थिंक थ्री थिंग्स हैं।
One is jealousy, one is clickbait and
एक तो जेलसी है, एक तो क्लिकबेट है और
The third thing is that now the creators are so
तीसरा चीज यह भी है कि अब क्रिएटर्स इतने
It has become important, right? what does that mean?
इम्पोर्टेन्ट हो गए ना। व्हाट डस दैट मीन?
what that means is my video is getting
व्हाट दैट मीन्स इज़ माय वीडियो इज़ गेटिंग
More Views Than Any News Traditional News
मोर व्यूज देन एनी न्यूज़ ट्रेडिशनल न्यूज़
Channel. what that means is there was before
चैनल। व्हाट दैट मीन्स इज़ देयर वाज़ बिफोर
Dec. It happened only once when with AIB
दिस। सिर्फ एक बार हुआ था जब एआईबी के साथ
The scene happened. Isn't it? when they
सीन हुआ था। है ना? जब उनको
It was sent to the legal court. Before this
लीगल कोर्ट में भेज दिया था। इससे पहले
Content creators are not that relevant
कंटेंट क्रिएटर तो इतने रेलेवेंट ही नहीं
Were. what is happening now that you
थे। अब क्या हो रहा है कि अब तुम्हारे
all
सारे
which if your prime minister is going to a
जो इफ योर प्राइम मिनिस्टर इज़ गोइंग टू अ
Content Creator and Giving a Podcast That
कंटेंट क्रिएटर एंड गिविंग अ पॉडकास्ट दैट
Means something. that means this is the form
मींस समथिंग। दैट मींस दैट दिस इज़ द फॉर्म
Of distribution that people are wanting.
ऑफ़ डिस्ट्रीब्यूशन दैट पीपल आर वांटिंग।
your idolizing earlier the idols were your
योर आइडलाइजिंग अर्लियर दी आइडल्स वर योर
Shahrukh Khan, Your Salman Khan, Big Screen
शाहरुख खान, योर सलमान खान, बिग स्क्रीन
People and your Virat Kohli and your
पीपल और योर विराट कोहली और योर
Cricketers they are there but a second level of
क्रिकेटर्स दे आर देयर बट अ सेकंड लेवल ऑफ
worshiping has also begun which is your
वरशिपिंग हैज़ आल्सो बिगेन व्हिच इज़ योर
Content creators. They are accessible content
कंटेंट क्रिएटर्स। दे आर एक्सेसिबल कंटेंट
Creators. Like I can be like him. I
क्रिएटर्स। लाइक आई कैन बी लाइक हिम। आई
Feel like this is very good till the time. I
फील लाइक दिस इस वैरी गुड टिल द टाइम। आई
Am seeing you in a particular way. you are
एम सीइंग यू इन अ पर्टिकुलर वे। यू आर
Dressing the Way. The way I want you to dress
ड्रेसिंग द वे। वे आई वांट यू टू ड्रेसिंग
The Things I Want You To Say. The Minute You Say
द थिंग्स आई वांट यू टू से। द मिनट यू से
something which doesn't really match what they
समथिंग व्हिच डजंट रियली मैच व्हाट दी
The general sentiment of the public is they will hate
जनरल सेंटीमेंट ऑफ द पब्लिक इज दे विल हेट
on you they will spit on you they will leave anyone
ऑन यू दे विल स्पिट ऑन यू दे विल लीव एनी
and that can happen any time hmmm so
एंड दैट कैन हैपन एनी टाइम हम्म इतना
Content creation has become important
इम्पोर्टेन्ट बन गया है कंटेंट क्रिएशन कि
Now people come to attack him. Do
अब उसको अटैक करने के लिए लोग आते हैं। डू
you look at yourself as one of the countries
यू लुक एट योरसेल्फ एस वन ऑफ द कंट्रीज
best journalist because that's how a lot of
बेस्ट जर्नलिस्ट बिकॉज़ दैट्स हाउ अ लॉट ऑफ़
People are looking at you. journalism is a
पीपल आर लुकिंग एट यू। जर्नलिज़्म इज अ
Very heavy word. but don't you think what you
वैरी हैवी वर्ड। बट डोंट यू थिंक व्हाट यू
Doing is journalism? Ok. here is what
डूइंग इज जर्नलिज्म? ओके। हियर इज व्हाट
I think. When you study in a media
आई थिंक। व्हेन यू स्टडी इन अ मीडिया
school i studied in a media school we were
स्कूल आई स्टडीड इन अ मीडिया स्कूल वी वर
That's a particular definition of journalism.
टॉट अ पर्टिकुलर डेफिनिशन ऑफ़ जर्नलिज्म।
What It Means to Be a Journalist Is
व्हाट इट मीन्स टू बी अ जर्नलिस्ट इज़
When You're Not Putting Your Reality, Your
व्हेन यू आर नॉट पुटिंग योर रियलिटी, योर
experiences, your truths in to the
एक्सपीरियंसेस, योर ट्रुथ्स इन टू द
The stories you are telling. but that's not
स्टोरीज़ यू आर टेलिंग। बट दैट्स नॉट
Possible. That's not possible. Exactly,
पॉसिबल। दैट्स नॉट पॉसिबल। एक्जेक्टली,
That's not possible. So, in the conventional
दैट्स नॉट पॉसिबल। सो, इन द कन्वेंशनल
Definition of what journalism means, what
डेफिनेशन ऑफ व्हाट जर्नलिज्म मीन्स, व्हाट
Documentary Means, I'm Not That
डॉक्यूमेंट्री मीन्स, आई एम नॉट दैट
conventional i do not match those conventional
कन्वेंशनल आई डू नॉट मैच दोज़ कन्वेंशनल
Definitions of journalism and of
डेफिनेशंस ऑफ जर्नलिज्म एंड ऑफ
Documentary. but a new form
डॉक्यूमेंट्री। बट अ न्यू फॉर्म
Documentary, New New Age Journalism.
डॉक्यूमेंट्री, न्यू न्यू एज जर्नलिज्म।
yes i think that is what i am doing
यस आय थिंक दैट आई एम डूइंग व्हाट आर
Journalist should be doing. what are media
जर्नलिस्ट शुड बी डूइंग। व्हाट आर मीडिया
Houses should be doing. i am doing it in a
हाउसेस शुड बी डूइंग। आय एम डूइंग इट इन अ
Much Smarter Way. many more people are watching
मच स्मार्टर वे। मेनी मोर पीपल आर वाचिंग
what i am doing then most of the
व्हाट आय एम डूइंग देन मोस्ट ऑफ़ द
Journalist in this country. I think your
जर्नलिस्ट इन दिस कंट्री। आय थिंक योर
Works Actually Impacting the Country. I
वर्क्स एक्चुअली इम्पैक्टिंग द कंट्री। आई
Agree Its
एग्री इट्स
Impacting a Young Girl in Class Third Hus
इंपैक्टिंग अ यंग गर्ल इन क्लास थर्ड हुस
Parents are behind her to leave education
पेरेंट्स आर बिहाइंड हर टू लीव एजुकेशन
Get married. I am inspiring that girl.
गेट मैरिड। आई एम इंस्पायरिंग दैट गर्ल।
I am inspiring an aspirant who is
आई एम इंस्पायरिंग एन एस्पिरेंट हु इज
About to give up on his journey of SSC.
अबाउट टू गिव अप ऑन हिज़ जर्नी ऑफ़ एसएससी।
I am inspiring any MBA female
आई एम इंस्पायरिंग एनी एमबीए फीमेल
Graduate who wants to take up business. hh
ग्रेजुएट हु वांट्स टू टेक अप बिज़नेस। हु
is thinking of being a female solo
इज़ थिंकिंग ऑफ़ बीइंग अ फीमेल सोलो
the entrepreneur who does not come from
एंटरप्रेन्योर हु डजंट कम फ्रॉम
Entrepreneur.
एंटरप्रेन्योर।
Background I'm inspiring a lot of
बैकग्राउंड आई एम इंस्पायरिंग अ लॉट ऑफ़
people and my existence is very
पीपल एंड माय एकिस्टेंस इज वेरी
Inspiring. I do think that.
इंस्पायरिंग। आई डू थिंक दैट।
i also think that you said that my content
आई आल्सो थिंक दैट यू सेड दैट माय कंटेंट
Feels Like Journalism. i also look at
फील्स लाइक जर्नलिज्म। आई आल्सो लुक एट
My content s on ground podcast. or or
माय कंटेंट एस ऑन ग्राउंड पॉडकास्ट। या या
In the sense that human stories yes. Like
इन द सेंस दैट ह्यूमन स्टोरीज यस। लाइक
What you ask your guess in a room. My
व्हाट यू आस्क योर गेस इन अ रूम। माय
Guests are on the ground. Yeah. and my
गेस्ट्स आर ऑन द ग्राउंड। याह। एंड माय
Guess might not be the biggest CEOs, biggest
गेस माइट नॉट बी द बिगेस्ट सीईओस, बिगेस्ट
Creators, the biggest brand builders. But
क्रिएटर्स, बिगेस्ट ब्रांड बिल्डर्स। बट
they have stories of their own that they are
दे हैव स्टोरीज़ ऑफ़ देयर ओन दैट दे आर
Waiting to tell. And you love it Ranveer. when
वेटिंग टू टेल। एंड यू लव इट रणवीर। व्हेन
you go on ground, the minute you just put a
यू गो ऑन ग्राउंड, द मिनट यू जस्ट पुट अ
mic in front of people
माइक इन फ्रंट ऑफ पीपल
You will very nice stories. yes, very nice
यू विल वैरी नाइस स्टोरीज। यस, वैरी नाइस
story.
स्टोरी।
hmm ya, this if I'm saying, you know, I
हम्म या, दिस इफ आई एम सेइंग, यू नो, आई
I want to make you sit down and just learn
आई वांट टू मेक यू सिट डाउन एंड जस्ट लर्न
From you. Hmm. a i also feel that more
फ्रॉम यू। हम्म। अ आई आल्सो फील दैट मोर
People Need to Take Up Long Form Content in
पीपल नीड टू टेक अप लॉन्ग फॉर्म कंटेंट इन
The Country. This Is Where You Can Actually
द कंट्री। दिस इज़ व्हेयर यू कैन एक्चुअली
Create an impact. Yes. like some numbers i
क्रिएट एन इंपैक्ट। यस। लाइक सम नंबर्स आई
would want to share we released a video on
वुड वांट टू शेयर वी रिलीज्ड अ वीडियो ऑन
The Biggest Dumping Ground. in one day it
द बिगेस्ट डंपिंग ग्राउंड। इन वन डे इट
Had 2.5 million views. A 20 minute video.
हैड 2.5 मिलियन व्यूज। अ 20 मिनट वीडियो।
Who would have imagined? so the point that there
हु वुड हैव इमेजिंड? सो द पॉइंट दैट देयर
is an audience if you are able to find an ish
इज एन ऑडियंस इफ यू आर एबल टू फाइंड एन ईश
Which is different and find the smart way
व्हिच इज डिफरेंट एंड फाइंड द स्मार्ट वे
of doing it there is an audience and i would
ऑफ़ डूइंग इट देयर इज़ एन ऑडियंस एंड आई वुड
Let's find out less than you've ever studied
से कम लेट्स फाइंड हैव यू एवर स्टडीड
Apuwas Content Yes She Is A Great Writer
अपूवास कंटेंट यस शी शी इज़ अ ग्रेट राइटर
yes and her audience is a lot younger
यस एंड हर ऑडियंस इज अ लॉट ऑफ यंगर
Girls what is your audience on YouTube or
गर्ल्स व्हाट इज योर ऑडियंस ऑन YouTube ओर
Instagram both overall very different on both
Instagram बोथ ओवरऑल वैरी डिफरेंट ऑन बोथ
The Platforms on Instagram I Have Five
द प्लेटफॉर्म्स ऑन Instagram आई हैव फाइव
The states that are watching me is Karnataka,
स्टेट्स दैट आर वाचिंग मी इज़ कर्नाटका,
Maharashtra, Gujarat, Rajasthan
महाराष्ट्र, गुजरात, राजस्थान
and Andhra Pradesh. So very tier one sort
एंड आंध्र प्रदेश। सो वेरी टियर वन सॉर्ट
of audiences of Bangalore, Hyderabad, Mumbai,
ऑफ़ ऑडियंस ऑफ़ बैंगलोर, हैदराबाद, मुंबई,
Delhi and one more which I am forgetting,
दिल्ली एंड वन मोर व्हिच आई फॉरगेटिंग,
Very tier one audience. Instagram is this
वैरी टियर वन ऑडियंस। Instagram इज़ दिस
Premiere Wants to Watch the Best Quality
प्रीमियर वांट्स टू वॉच द बेस्ट क्वालिटी
and will only watch things which they can
एंड विल ओनली वॉच थिंग्स व्हिच दे कैन
Share easily. We are YouTube is your auto
शेयर इजीली। हम YouTube इज योर ऑटो
Drivers, Rickshaw Drivers, Students
ड्राइवर्स, रिक्शा ड्राइवर्स, स्टूडेंट्स
Watching from their parents fuss. so on
वाचिंग फ्रॉम देयर पेरेंट्स फ़स। सो ऑन
YouTube The City That Is The The City That Is The
YouTube द सिटी इज़ दैट द सिटी दैट इज द
Highest Is
हाईएस्ट इज़
Patna. even two the content is the same we have
पटना। इवन दो द कंटेंट इज़ द सेम वी हैव
Long Format on YouTube not on
लॉन्ग फॉर्मेट ऑन YouTube नॉट ऑन
Instagram. I love to talk about this.
Instagram। आई लव टू टॉक अबाउट दिस।
Instagram in general is a page which is a
Instagram इन जनरल इज़ अ पेज व्हिच इज़ अ
Share page. like right you watch something on
शेयर पेज। लाइक राइट यू वॉच समथिंग ऑन
Instagram You Instantly Send It To A
Instagram यू इंस्टेंटली सेंड इट टू अ
Friend because you relate to it. you think oh
फ्रेंड बिकॉज़ यू रिलेट टू इट। यू थिंक ओह
he is a there some joke that you had running
ही इज अ देयर सम जोक दैट यू हाड रनिंग
Between the two of you. will be able to relate
बिटवीन द टू ऑफ़ यू। विल बी एबल टू रिलेट
To it. I will share. I will share I will
टू इट। आई विल शेयर। आई विल शेयर आइ विल
share. On YouTube you can't share stuff. You
शेयर। ऑन YouTube यू कांट शेयर स्टफ। यू
Have to click share, copy that link, go to
हैव टू क्लिक शेयर, कॉपी दैट लिंक, गो टू
WhatsApp, paste that link. Not happening.
WhatsApp, पेस्ट दैट लिंक। नॉट हैपनिंग।
Instagram is also a social media
Instagram इज आल्सो अ सोशल मीडिया
The Platform Where You Are Connecting With
प्लेटफार्म वेर यू आर कनेक्टिंग विद
Friends, people who you are talking to
फ्रेंड्स, पीपल हू यू आर टॉकिंग टू
Everyday. YouTube is not that. YouTube is
एवरीडे। YouTube इज नॉट दैट। YouTube इज
More of a search engine platform. a so you
मोर ऑफ अ सर्च इंजन प्लेटफार्म। अ सो यू
Have to tailor the content on YouTube from a
हैव टू टेलर दी कंटेंट ऑन YouTube फ्रॉम अ
Retention point of view. means that you have to
रिटेंशन पॉइंट ऑफ व्यू। मतलब कि यू हैव टू
make sure that you get the people you make them
मेक श्योर दैट यू गेट द पीपल यू मेक देम
Stick Versus On Instagram It's More Like
स्टिक वर्सेस ऑन Instagram इट्स मोर लाइक
what you do. Personal Stories, Relatable
व्हाट यू डू। पर्सनल स्टोरीज, रिलेटिवल
Content, Emotional Content, Getting the Hook Right
कंटेंट, इमोशनल कंटेंट, गेटिंग द हुक राइट
And then ah being true, authentic etcetera.
एंड देन अह बीइंग ट्रू, ऑथेंटिक एटसेट्रा।
Ah yes. i also think
अह यस। आई आल्सो थिंक
what apuva does brilliantly she doesn't just
व्हाट अपूवा डस ब्रिलियंटली शी डजंट जस्ट
She Has Viewers She Has Fans
हैव व्यूअर्स शी हैस फैंस
like everybody will know her catch phrases hello
लाइक एवरीवन विल नो हर कैच फ्रेजेस हेलो
Little red flags is something that I will
लिटिल रेड फ्लैग्स इज समथिंग दैट आई विल
feel proud of in associating with or
फील प्राउड ऑफ इन असोसिएटिंग विद या फिर
Kalishi is a word that she will keep on
कलीशी इज अ वर्ड दैट शी विल कीप ऑन
repeating | so that's one layer deeper right
रिपीटिंग | सो दैट्स वन लेयर डीपर राइट
Where You Are Not Just the Building Views You Are
वेयर यू आर नॉट जस्ट बिल्डिंग व्यूज यू आर
Also Building Fandom | hum hum how do you
आल्सो बिल्डिंग फैंडम | हम् हम हाउ डू यू
Build fandom? how do we do
बिल्ड फैंड? हम हाउ डू
Yes good question. I
यस गुड क्वेश्चन। आई
think there is a type of content which will
थिंक देयर इज अ टाइप ऑफ कंटेंट व्हिच विल
get you views and i think 70% off your
गेट यू व्यूज एंड आई थिंक 70% ऑफ योर
The content has to be that. but then 30% is for
कंटेंट हैस टू बी दैट। बट देन 30% इज फॉर
Two things. either you build your brand through
टू थिंग्स। इदर यू बिल्ड योर ब्रांड थ्रू
It. Like you talk about how to get views?
इट। लाइक यू टॉक अबाउट हाउ टू गेट व्यूज?
How can you become the next best editor?
हाउ कैन यू बिकम द नेक्स्ट बेस्ट एडिटर?
How can you become the next best
हाउ कैन यू बिकम द नेक्स्ट बेस्ट
Youtuber? and then 10 20% is also yours
यूट्यूबर? एंड देन 10 20% इज़ आल्सो योर
Personal story. believe me ranveer every time
पर्सनल स्टोरी। बिलीव मी रणवीर एवरी टाइम
I don't do educational stuff I do stuff like
आई डोंट डू एजुकेशनल स्टफ आई डू स्टफ लाइक
Why is my hair short? this my guy
मेरे बाल क्यों छोटे हैं? यह मेरा बंदा
Is. This is my best friend. this is my team
है। यह मेरा बेस्ट फ्रेंड है। ये मेरा टीम
Going to do. that works even more than indian
वाला है। दैट वर्क्स इवन मोर देन इंडियन
The audience is more realistic in the truest sense.
ऑडियंस इज़ मोरस्टिक टू द ट्रूएस्ट सेंस।
Everything Bigg Boss. Yes. everything is big
एवरीथिंग बिग बॉस। यस। एवरीथिंग इज बिग
Boss. That's why vlogs work. thats
बॉस। दैट्स व्हाई व्लोग्स वर्क। दैट्स
Why Ah Reality TV Works. because give
व्हाई अह रियलिटी टीवी वर्क्स। बिकॉज़ दे
Want to know what do I eat? what do i
वांट टू नो व्हाट डू आई ईट? व्हाट डू आई
Drink? Who am I sleeping with? who am I
ड्रिंक? हु एम आई स्लीपिंग विद? हु आई हू
are you my friends? And that's important.
आर माय फ्रेंड्स? एंड दैट्स इम्पोर्टेन्ट।
because if you don't show that then those people will
बिकॉज़ इफ यू डोंट शो दैट देन दोज़ पीपल विल
get that same content from someone else
गेट दैट सेम कंटेंट फ्रॉम समवन एल्स एस
well. but if you have got them through your 70%
वेल। बट इफ यू हाव गॉटन देम थ्रू योर 70%
Of the content which you have made. you have now
ऑफ़ द कंटेंट व्हिच यू हैव मेड। यू हैव नाउ
Gotta get them. But to retain them. to tell them
गॉटन देम। बट टू रिटेन देम। टू टेल देम
Your human side also. which i also
योर ह्यूमन साइड आल्सो। व्हिच आय आल्सो
Think is the barrier to entry for a lot of
थिंक इज़ द बैरियर टू एंट्री फॉर अ लॉट ऑफ़
Women because doing what isn't easy. Hmm
वीमेन बिकॉज़ डूइंग दैट इज़ नॉट इज़। हम्म
telling about your family, telling about
टेलिंग अबाउट योर फॅमिली, टेलिंग अबाउट
Your Relationship, Telling About Your Team
योर रिलेशनशिप, टेलिंग अबाउट योर टीम
takes a level of comfort which is not
टेक्स अ लेवल ऑफ़ कंफर्ट व्हिच इज नॉट
Which Not a Lot of Creators Are Okay With
व्हिच नॉट अ लॉट ऑफ़ क्रिएटर्स आर ओके विद
then you know there is this
फिर यू नो देयर इज़ दिस
There's a problem in our country and it's been a
प्रॉब्लम इन आवर कंट्री एंड इट्स बीन अ
problem for the last 10 years for sure
प्रॉब्लम फॉर द लास्ट 10 इयर्स फॉर श्योर
Because 10 years is how long I've been
बिकॉज़ 10 इयर्स इज़ हाउ लॉन्ग आई हैव बीन
Around? But content creation is kind of
अराउंड? बट कंटेंट क्रिएशन काइंड ऑफ़
Started five years before me. so for the
स्टार्टेड फाइव इयर्स बिफोर मी। सो फॉर द
The problems in the country in the last 15 years
लास्ट 15 इयर्स इन द कंट्री द प्रॉब्लम्स
Been That Only Men Take Up Content Creation
बीन दैट ओनली मेन टेक अप कंटेंट क्रिएशन
in the long term and I've had so many
इन द लॉन्ग टर्म एंड आई हैव हैड सो मेनी
Conversations with Guys Where They'd Like Why
कन्वर्सेशन विथ गायज वेयर वेर लाइक व्हाई
arent girls doing it i also want to know
आरंट गर्ल्स डूइंग इट आई आल्सो वांट टू नो
this from a girl's perspective of course i
दिस फ्रॉम अ गर्ल्स पर्सपेक्ट ऑफकोर्स आई
love to talk about that i think from a
लव टू टॉक अबाउट दैट आई थिंक फ्रॉम अ
Business Stands But There Is a Lot More Money
बिज़नेस स्टैंड बट देयर इज अ लॉट मोर मनी
To be made if you are a female content
टू बी मेड इफ यू आर अ फीमेल कॉन्टेंट
Creator because there are many more females
क्रिएटर बिकॉज़ देयर दैट मेनी मोर फीमेल
Friendly Brands But I've Never Seen One
फ्रेंडली ब्रांड्स बट आई हैव नेवर
Understood Why the Girl Content Creators
अंडरस्टुड व्हाई द गर्ल कंटेंट क्रिएटर्स
in our country don't take up youtube full
इन आवर कंट्री डोंट टेक अप YouTube फुल
The time is the way you have done it and you are adding
टाइम द वे यू हैव डन इट एंड यू आर एडिंग
That feminine touch to all your videos. What
दैट फेमिनिन टच टू ऑल योर वीडियोज़। व्हाट
My question to the bigger audience is would you
माय क्वेश्चन टू द बिगगर ऑडियंस इज़ विल यू
Consume female content creators? Like
कंज्यूम फीमेल कंटेंट क्रिएटर्स? लाइक
it's been across industries
इट्स बीन अक्रोस इंडस्ट्रीज़
Always, will you consume a missing lady's age
ऑलवेज, विल यू कंज्यूम अ लापता लेडीज़ एज़
Much as you consume a Salman Khan film. Will
मच एज़ यू कंस्यूम अ सलमान खान फिल्म। विल
You should be as comfortable flying in a flight
यू बी एज़ कम्फर्टेबल फ्लाइंग इन अ फ्लाइट
Where the female is a pilot versus a male is
वेयर द फीमेल इज़ अ पायलट वर्सेस अ मेल इज़
A pilot. you have to be okay with listening to
अ पायलट। यू हैव टू बी ओके विथ लिसनिंग टू
R stories also. so, you have to be okay
आर स्टोरीज़ आल्सो। सो, यू हैव टू बी ओके
with letting go of some of the traditional
विथ लेटिंग गो ऑफ़ सम ऑफ़ द ट्रेडिशनल
Stories That Have Been Told Again and Again
स्टोरीज़ दैट हैव बीन टोल्ड अगेन एंड अगेन
and again and listen to a perspective
एंड अगेन एंड लिसेन टू अ पर्सपेक्टिव
which is
व्हिच इज़
Different. when you say that there is much more
डिफरेंट। व्हेन यू से दैट देयर इज़ मच मोर
To Earn for a Female Content Creator. Income
टू अर्न फॉर अ फीमेल कंटेंट क्रिएटर। आय
wouldn't you also say that there is much more to lose
वुड आल्सो से दैट देयर इज़ मच मोर टू लूज़
For a female content creator. The Scrutiny
फॉर अ फीमेल कंटेंट क्रिएटर। द स्क्रूटनी
That we face in our common section is much higher
दैट वी फेस इन आवर कॉमन सेक्शन इज़ मच हायर
Then what. in my opinion is much higher than
देन व्हाट। इन माय ओपिनियन इज़ मच हायर देन
What a man Bill. If I were mine if the neck
व्हाट अ मैन बिल। इफ आई इफ माई इफ द नेक
The line of my clothes is a little deeper i
लाइन ऑफ़ माय क्लोथ्स इज अ लिटिल डीपर आई
Will get 10 comments on that. if i look at
विल गेट 10 कमेंट्स ऑन दैट। इफ आई लुक अ
little fatter in a video i will get 10
लिटिल फैटर इन अ वीडियो आई विल गेट 10
Comments on that. If I See My Tattoos Show Me
कॉमेंट्स ऑन दैट। इफ आई माय टैटूस शो आई
Will get 10 comments on that. and then that
विल गेट 10 कॉमेंट्स ऑन दैट। एंड देन दैट
makes me feel he even do i am making
मेक्स मी फील हे इवन दो आई एम मेकिंग
Content which is much more educational in nature
कंटेंट व्हिच इज़ मच मोर एजुकेशनल इन नेचर
and yet that is what is what you are
एंड येट दैट इज व्हाट इज व्हाट यू आर
Seeing I'll be more fine than I won't
सीइंग आई विल बी लाइक फाइन देन आई विल नॉट
Be comfortable in putting that on. but my
बी कम्फर्टेबल इन पुटिंग दैट ऑन। बट माय
Dream My overall dream is to create regional
ड्रीम माय ओवरऑल ड्रीम इज टू क्रिएट रीजनल
Female creators who bring out stories of
फीमेल क्रिएटर्स हु ब्रिंग आउट स्टोरीज ऑफ
there places of their experiences that
देयर प्लेसेस ऑफ देयर एक्सपीरियंसेस दैट
Will be amazing | I feel that you all are the
विल बी अमेजिंग | आई फील कि यू ऑल आर द
Flag Bearers of New Age Long Form
फ्लैग बैरर्स ऑफ़ न्यू एज लॉन्ग फॉर्म
Content Creation. I remember telling a lot
कंटेंट क्रिएशन। आई रिमेंबर टेलिंग अ लॉट
Of my female content creator friends
ऑफ़ माय फीमेल कंटेंट क्रिएटर फ्रेंड्स
that's a very hotspace to be in
डट्याट इट्स अ वैरी हॉटस्पेस टू बी इन
Three years ago. but i didn't see people
थ्री इयर्स एगो। बट आई डिडन्ट सी पीपल
Executing in such direction. Butt Do
एक्सक्यूटिंग इन देतयात डायरेक्शन। बट डू
You think what I am saying is correct? And
यू थिंक व्हाट आय एम सेइंग इज करेक्ट? और
I do think what you are saying is correct? I
आई डू थिंक व्हाट यू सेइंग इज करेक्ट? आई
also think that to advise anyone and
आल्सो थिंक दैट टू एडवाइस एनीवन एंड
Everyone wants to be a content creator
एवरीवन टू बी अ कंटेंट क्रिएटर वोंट बी अ
very just advice to take because you don't
वैरी जस्ट एडवाइस टू टेक बिकॉज़ डोंट यू
think ranvir that content creation is very
थिंक रणवीर दैट कंटेंट क्रिएशन इज़ वेरी
Physically, Mentally, Emotionally Demanding Age
फिजिकली, मेंटली, इमोशनली डिमांडिंग एज एज
A profession. It's like Liborius. Yes. End
अ प्रोफेशन। इट्स लाइक लिबोरियस। यस। एंड
It's not short term. like if you have to
इट्स नॉट शार्ट टर्म। लाइक इफ यू हैव टू
Do it, you have to do it for 20 years.
डू इट, यू हैव टू डू इट फॉर 20 इयर्स।
Like to be a name and face in that category
लाइक टू बी अ नेम एंड फेस इन दैट कैटेगरी
You have to do it for 10 15 20 years. it's
यू हैव टू डू इट फॉर 10 15 20 इयर्स। इट्स
not like ek reel nikla di 10 million views
नॉट लाइक एक रील निकाल दी 10 मिलियन व्यूज
Have come. Great. No it's not that. so do we
आ गए। ग्रेट। नो इट्स नॉट दैट। सो डू वी
Want women to take that up? I don't know.
वांट वीमेन टू टेक दैट अप? आई डोंट नो।
Like tell me this. Yes. tell me tell me the
लाइक टेल मी दिस। यस। टेल मी टेल मी द
Girl perspective on this. Yes. I think
गर्ल पर्सेपेक्टिव ऑन दिस। यस। आई थिंक
What I face as a female very small thing.
व्हाट आई फेस एज अ फीमेल वैरी स्माल थिंग।
I like colouring my hair but I have done that
आई लाइक कलरिंग माय हेयर बट आई हैव डन दैट
Because when I go on the field people will feel
बिकॉज़ व्हेन आई गो ऑन फील्ड पीपल विल फील
Alienated by it.
एलियनेटेड बाय इट।
as it is the presence of a woman in most
एज इट इज द प्रेज़ेंस ऑफ अ वूमन इन मोस्ट
Fields on ground are very threatening.
फील्ड्स ऑन ग्राउंड इज़ वेरी थ्रेटनिंग।
Secondarily short hair again threatening. in that
सेकंडली छोटे बाल अगेन थ्रेटनिंग। उसमें
If you colour it too then it will be even more threatening
कलर भी कर लोगे तो तो और थ्रेटनिंग हो
Will go. A Lot of Times When We Go On
जाएगा। अ लॉट ऑफ़ द टाइम्स व्हेन वी गो ऑन
Field, people will look at my producers
फील्ड, पीपल विल लुक एट माई प्रोडूसर्स
Eyes not my eyes. it's a cow it's a cow
आईज नॉट माय आईज। इट्स अ गाय इट्स अ गाय
And women men in our country only are not
एंड वीमेन मेन इन आवर कंट्री ओनली आर नॉट
Very Comfortable Talking to Women Eye to Eye
वेरी कम्फर्टेबल टॉकिंग टू वीमेन आई टू आई
, or i mean you know as a guy when you
| या आई मीन यू नो एज अ गाय व्हेन यू
Growing up, especially in our country, you don't
ग्रोइंग अप स्पेशली इन आवर कंट्री यू डोंट
think of a girl's reality unless you have a
थिंक ऑफ अ गर्ल्स रियलिटी अनलेस यू हैव अ
sister you understand a little bit but then
सिस्टर यू अंडरस्टैंड अ लिटिल बिट बट देन
When You Have a Serious Relationship in Your
व्हेन यू हैव अ सीरियस रिलेशनशिप इन योर
20s and You Have Intellectual Conversation
20ज एंड यू हैव इंटेलेक्चुअल कन्वर्सेशन
and break down things then you realise as
एंड ब्रेक डाउन थिंग्स देन यू रियलाइज एज
a guy in our country that guy it's not the
अ गाय इन आवर कंट्री दैट यार इट्स नॉट द
Same for girls and guys agrade a lot of
सेम फॉर गर्ल्स एंड गाइस अग्रेड अ लॉट ऑफ
The Times You've Gone on the Field and People Have
द टाइम्स यू गॉन ऑन फील्ड एंड पीपल हैव
face to face said to us don't record the
फेस टू फेस सेड टू अस डोंट रिकॉर्ड द
women don't record our women don't
वीमेन डोंट रिकॉर्ड आवर वीमेन डोंट
Record them without their pallu on don't
रिकॉर्ड देम विदाउट देयर पल्लूज ऑन डोंट
record our female kid is that also i
रिकॉर्ड आवर फीमेल किड इज़ दैट आल्सो आई
think this field requires a lot of
थिंक दिस फील्ड रिक्वायर्स अ लॉट ऑफ़
Networking Where I Can't Do This Alone
नेटवर्किंग व्हेयर आई कांट डू दिस अलोन
Being a Content Creator is After All Certain
बीइंग अ कंटेंट क्रिएटर इज़ आफ्टर अ सर्टेन
The point is there is no solo system. you need a
पॉइंट इज़ नॉट नॉट सोलो सिस्टम। यू नीड अ
Team, you need a great team. to build a
टीम, यू नीड अ ग्रेट टीम। टू बिल्ड अ
Great team, you need some core
ग्रेट टीम, यू नीड सम कोर
Supporters. for that to happen, you need a
सपोर्टर्स। फॉर दैट टू हैपन, यू नीड अ
A Little Bit of Masculine Energy Around You
लिटिल बिट ऑफ़ मैस्कुलिन एनर्जी अराउंड यू
And you need men to get that job done. it's
एंड यू नीड मेन टू गेट दैट जॉब डन। इट्स
Not when we think of content, we think of
नॉट व्हेन वी थिंक ऑफ़ कंटेंट, वी थिंक ऑफ़
Most people. I know you don't think about it.
मोस्ट पीपल। आई नो यू डोंट थिंक अबाउट इट।
Because you have so much experience. You Know
बिकॉज़ यू हैव सो मच एक्सपीरियंस। यू नो
This already. people think that being a
दिस ऑलरेडी। पीपल थिंक दैट बीइंग अ
Creator is about creativity. I Wood Se
क्रिएटर इज़ अबाउट क्रिएटिविटी। आई वुड से
It's only 20% creativity. it's so many
इट्स ओनली 20% क्रिएटिविटी। इट्स सो मेनी
More things. It's so many more things. It
मोर थिंग्स। इट्स सो मेनी मोर थिंग्स। इट
Has time has to match. Your core team has to
हैज़ टाइम हैज़ टू मैच। योर कोर टीम हैज़ टू
have someone who is the goonda of
हैव समवन हु इज द गुंडा ऑफ़
Your thing. Your strategies should match. So
योर थिंग। योर स्ट्रेटेजीस शुड मैच। सो
Even when there is lack of women content
इवन व्हेन दीज़ लैक ऑफ वु वीमेन कंटेंट
Creator Conversations Are Happening, It
क्रिएटर कन्वर्सेशन आर हप्पेनिंग, इट
Happens in one of two ways. There will be a cow here
हप्पेंस इन वन ऑफ़ टू वेज़। इदर दे बी अ गाय
Sitting in front of me. who is kind of
सिटींग इन फ्रंट ऑफ़ मी। हु इज़ काइंड ऑफ़
Anti women. Yes. but there also guys who are
एंटी वीमेन। यस। बट देयर आल्सो गाइस हु आर
Just if Ganesh and me are city it's always
जस्ट इफ गणेश एंड मी आर सिटी इट्स ऑलवेज
in a place of what can we do to further
इन अ प्लेस ऑफ़ व्हाट कैन वी डू टू फर्दर
That change hires more female creators in your
दैट चेंज हायर मोर फीमेल क्रिएटर्स इन योर
Team That's It Like Representation Comes
टीम दैट्स इट लाइक रेप्रेजेंटेशन कम्स
From within I think skill house has a
फ्रॉम विदिन आई थिंक स्किल हाउस हैज़ अ
female lead right | Mahima Mahima is amazing
फीमेल लीड राइट | महिमा महिमा इज़ अमेजिंग
, mahima i have seen most of mahimas
| महिमा आई हैव सीन मोस्ट ऑफ़ महिमास
videos and she is doing a great work and
वीडियोस एंड शी इज़ डूइंग अ ग्रेट वर्क एंड
That I am sure will motivate more females
दैट आई ऍम श्योर विल मोटिवेट मोर फीमेल
editors to also apply to this
एडिटर्स टू आल्सो अप्लाई टु दिस
position i also think creation in general r
पोजीशन आई आल्सो थिंक क्रिएशन इन जनरल आर
Tasks Require Fields Like Editor
टास्क्स रिक्वायर फील्ड्स लाइक एडिटर
we need videographer we need all of
चाहिए हमको वीडियोग्राफर चाहिए हमको ऑल ऑफ़
These are traditionally looked at as male jobs
दीज़ ट्रेडिशनली आर लुक्ड एट एज मेल जॉब्स
right is that really
राइट इज़ इज़ दैट रियली
Wrong may not be an editor but with videography
रोंग मे बी नॉट एडिटर बट विथ वीडियोग्राफी
Considering our country and the dangers that
कंसिडरिंग आवर कंट्री एंड द डेंजरस दैट
like i'm sure you want sometimes you need
लाइक आई एम श्योर यू वांट समटाइम्स यू नीड
that guy onset
दैट गाई ऑनसेट
to just be the warden of other men bro i will
टू जस्ट वार्डन ऑफ़ अदर मेन ब्रो आई विल
Share an Instance With
शेयर एन इंस्टेंस विद
you and this is a long instance so bare
यू एंड दिस इज अ लॉन्ग इंस्टेंस सो बेयर
With me a little bit okay all of Delhis
विद मी अ लिटिल बिट ओके ऑल ऑफ दिल्लीस
Waste is dumped in three dumping grounds
वेस्ट इज डम्प्ड इन थ्री डंपिंग ग्राउंड्स
One of them we visited for a video 600
वन ऑफ़ देम वी विजिटेड फॉर अ वीडियो 600
Trucks of waste is dumped in that single
ट्रक्स ऑफ वेस्ट इज डम्प्ड इन दैट सिंगल
place it's as tall as 20 floors
प्लेस इट्स एज़ टॉल एज़ 20 फ्लोर का
Building is ok and there are lack of people
बिल्डिंग ओके एंड देयर आर लैक्स ऑफ़ पीपल
Living Around Here Around There and Then
लिविंग अराउंड हियर अराउंड देयर एंड एंड
that is the place which is delhi's biggest
दैट इज द प्लेस व्हिच इज़ दिल्लीस बिगेस्ट
Vegetable Market, Delhi's Biggest Flower Mandi,
सब्जी मंडी, दिल्लीस बिगेस्ट फ्लावर मंडी,
The Delhi is the biggest vegetable market and
द दिल्ली इज़ बिगेस्ट वेजिटेबल मंडी एंड
Delhi is biggest dairy farm. Ok? so all
दिल्ली इज़ बिगेस्ट डेरी फार्म। ओके? सो ऑल
Or milk in Delhi is coming from there.
आर मिल्क इन दिल्ली इज़ कमिंग फ्रॉम देयर।
We didn't know that. we just went and we
वी डिडट नो दैट। वी जस्ट वेंट एंड वी
shooting started in the dairy wala
स्टार्टेड शूटिंग इन द डेयरी वाला
Area. five men came to the phone from my
एरिया। फाइव मेन केम टूक द फोन फ्रॉम माई
Hand. started deleting all the videos
हैंड। स्टार्टेड डिलीटिंग ऑल द वीडियोस
and started beating the shoot out of my
एंड स्टार्टेड बीटिंग द शूट आउट ऑफ़ माय
Videographer. This is really a sheath. when did you do it
वीडियोग्राफर। ही वास् अ म्यान। व्हेन डीड
This happen? This happened 2 months ago
दिस हैपन? दिस हैप्पेंडें 2 मंथ्स अगो
garbage mafia yes this was the dairy mafia
कचरा माफिया यस दिस वास द डेरी माफी ऑफ
Delhi we have that audio recorded you can
दिल्ली वी हैव दैट ऑडियो रिकॉर्डेड यू कैन
pull that out and i was shouting
पुल देट आउट एंड आई वाज शाउटिंग
screaming asking them to stop they were
स्क्रीमिंग आस्किंग देम टू स्टॉप दे वर
not stopping they beat the shed after coming out of
नॉट स्टॉपिंग दे बीट द शेड आफ्टर आउट ऑफ
that man i had to physically come in the
दैट मैन आई ह्य हैड टू फिजिकली कम इन द
middle of the two and be like that stop it
मिडिल ऑफ द टू एंड बी लाइक कि स्टॉप इट
and they stopped because i was a female if this
एंड दे स्टॉप बिकॉज़ आई वाज अ फीमेल इफ दिस
there were two men it would have
देयर वर टू मेन इट वुड हैव
stopped and head heaped bean a female
स्टॉप्ड एंड हेड हीप बीन अ फीमेल
virographer they wouldn't have hit
वीरग्राफर दे वुडन्ट हैव हिट
So the perspective of a male energy is
सो द पर्सपेक्टिव ऑफ अ मेल एनर्जी इज़
Required to Ward Off Evil if the Female
रिक्वायर्ड टू वार्ड ऑफ इविल इफ द फीमेल
you are smart enough they can and you are right you
आर स्मार्ट इनफ दे कैन एंड यू आर राइट यू
are you right i'm just complicating that
आर राइट आई एम जस्ट कॉम्प्लिकेटिंग दैट
thought a little bit that this was my
थॉट अ लिटिल बिट दैट दिस वाज़ माई
Experience is also what I have learned
एक्सपीरियंस आल्सो व्हाट आई हैव लर्न्ड
Over 10 Years of Team Building in Our
ओवर 10 इयर्स ऑफ़ टीम बिल्डिंग इन आवर
The Industry That You Always Need a Combination
इंडस्ट्री दैट यू ऑलवेज नीड अ कॉम्बिनेशन
Yes of men and women yes for the best
यस ऑफ़ मेन एंड वीमेन यस फॉर द बेस्ट
creative work to come up i was reading this
क्रिएटिव वर्क टू कम अप आई वाज रीडिंग दिस
book the other day which talks about how the
बुक दी अदर डे व्हिच टॉक्स अबाउट हाउ द
Society around us has been different for males.
सोसाइटी अराउंड अस हैज़ बीन डिज़ फॉर मेल्स।
Ok? The seat belts in our cars have only
ओके? द सीट बेल्ट्स इन आवर कार्स हैव ओनली
Bean Tested on Male Dummies.
बीन टेस्टेड ऑन मेल डमीज़।
usually the aces and all are studios will
यूजुअली दी एसीज़ एंड ऑल आर स्टूडियोज़ विल
Be at a temperature which is suitable for you
बी एट अ टेंपरेचर व्हिच इज़ सूटेड फॉर अ
Male body is not for a female body. Design Of
मेल बॉडी नॉट फॉर अ फीमेल बॉडी। डिज़ाइन ऑफ़
the world is true that women are not
द वर्ल्ड इज़ सच दैट द फीमेल्स आर नॉट
Taking like a second class citizen.
टेकिंग लाइक सेकंड क्लास सिटीजन।
Exactly. All over the world. Exactly.
एक्सक्ट्ली। ऑल ओवर द वर्ल्ड। एक्सक्ट्ली।
So ok. And periods are going on brother
सो ओके। और पीरियड्स चल रहे हैं भाई हर
months if men are having periods
महीने अगर आदमियों को पीरियड्स चल रहे
if it were there then by now there must have been a
होते तो अभी तक देयर मस्ट हैव बीन अ
remedy for it and there must have been a
रेमेडी फॉर इट और देयर मस्ट हैव बीन अ
Solve for it? do you you you you you you you
सॉल्व फॉर इट? डू यू यू यू यू यू यू यू
Think things are getting better? of course give
थिंक थिंग्स आर गेटिंग बेटर? ऑफ़ कोर्स दे
R. of course i think representation is
आर। ऑफ़ कोर्स आय थिंक रिप्रेजेंटेशन इज
Your solution to anything and everything. Do
योर सलूशन टू एनीथिंग एंड एव्रीथिंग। डू
You see more KK creates in five years
यू सी मोर केके क्रिएट्स इन फाइव इयर्स
Time? Definitely. I think not five years.
टाइम? डेफिनेटली। आय थिंक नॉट फाइव इयर्स।
I think they are already there. i also
आई थिंक दे आर आलरेडी देयर देयर। आई आल्सो
Think When We Think of Content Creation We
थिंक व्हेन वी थिंक ऑफ कंटेंट क्रिएशन वी
should not be thinking about big creators
शुड नॉट बी थिंकिंग अबाउट बिग क्रिएटर्स
So much. I feel like the future is in Nano
सो मच। आई फील लाइक द फ्यूचर इज इन नैनो
Localized regional authentic creators. Like
लोकलाइज्ड रीजनल ऑथेंटिक क्रिएटर्स। लाइक
Fine how many superstars will you have? You
फाइन हाउ मेनी सुपरस्टार्स विल यू हैव? यू
Also need some artistic stuff. you also
आल्सो नीड सम आर्टिस्टिक स्टफ़। यू आल्सो
Need some indie stuff. you also need some
नीड सम इंडि स्टफ़। यू आल्सो नीड़ सम
Bhojpuri stuff. you also need some hyderabadi
भोजपुरी स्टफ़। यू आल्सो नीड़ सम हैदराबादी
Stuff. so there are so many content
स्टफ़। सो देयर आर सो मेनी कंटेंट
Creators, Females Who Are Making Things
क्रिएटर्स, फीमेल्स हू आर मेकिंग थिंग्स
in their regional language telling their local
इन देयर रीजनल लैंग्वेज टेलिंग देयर लोकल
Stories Which Need to Come Out More Rather Than
स्टोरीज व्हिच नीड टू कम आउट मोर रादर देन
Top superstars in this industry. I
टॉप सुपरस्टार्स इन दिस इंडस्ट्री। आई
here you and i agree with what you are
हियर यू एंड आई एग्री विथ व्हाट यू आर
Saying. but i feel like when you see a kk
सेइंग। बट आई फील लाइक व्हेन यू सी अ केके
Create at that top level that is the superstar
क्रिएट एट दैट टॉप लेवल दैट द सुपरस्टार
The Level It Inspires
लेवल इट इंस्पायर्स
too many girls and its problem
टू मेनी गर्ल्स एंड इट प्रॉबब्ली
Inspires a much larger number of girls
इंस्पायर्स अ मोर अ लार्जर नंबर ऑफ गर्ल्स
Then the artisanal creators. I do I do
देन दी आर्टिजनल क्रिएटर्स। आई डू आई डू
I agree to that. But you know, like people say
अग्री टू दैट। पर पता है जैसे लोग कहते
Isn't it true that behind a successful man there is a woman
हैं ना कि एक कामयाब मर्द के पीछे एक औरत
it occurs. For me it's the opposite. to me
होती है। मेरे लिए उल्टा है। मेरे को
My backbone opinion is always my
हमेशा से मेरी बैकबोन राय है मेरे
Partners are my best friends.
पार्टनर्स मेरे बेस्ट फ्रेंड।
currently the person who is my producer is
करेंटली द पर्सन हु इज माई प्रोड्यूसर इज़
Also my partner in real life. Mother
आल्सो माय पार्टनर इन रियल लाइफ। माई
Fionnasse in real life. so you only see me
फियोंनसे इन रियल लाइफ। सो यू ओनली सी मी
In front of the camera. so, he has given me
इन फ्रंट ऑफ़ द कैमरा। सो, ही हैज़ गिवेन मी
That space. He has made all the provisions. only
दैट स्पेस। ही हैज़ मेड ऑल द प्रोविज़ंस। ही
kept me safe and gave me that camera
केप्ट मी सेफ एंड गिवेन मी दैट कैमरा
Space. so the man also can take a little
स्पेस। सो द मैन आल्सो कैन टेक अ लिटिल
absolutely off a back seat and let the woman in
बिल्कुल ऑफ अ बैक सीट एंड लेट द वुमेन इन
Their Lives, Female Friends in Their Lives
देयर लाइव्स, फीमेल फ्रेंड इन देयर लाइव्स
To support them. the person who looks at
टू सपोर्ट देम। द पर्सन हु लुक्स एट
Monetization for us. Mother
मोनेटाइजेशन फॉर अस। माई
Manager. he joyed us two years ago when i
मैनेजर। ही जॉइ अस टू इयर्स अगो व्हेन आई
Was barely making ₹10,000 a month. No
वास् बेरली मेकिंग ₹10,000 अ मंथ। नो
The brand was coming to us. now he has taken
ब्रांड वास् कमिंग टू अस। नाउ ही हैज़ टेकन
Our business to a place where we are 50%
आवर बिज़नेस टू अ प्लेस वेयर वी आर 50%
Profitable while having a team of 20
प्रॉफिटेबल व्हाइल हैविंग अ टीम ऑफ़ 20
Ficus religiosa. he is ready to leave his government
पीपल। ही इज़ रेडी टू लीव हिज गवर्नमेंट
Job. That man is AIR All India Rank 20
जॉब। दैट मैन इज़ एआईआर ऑल इंडिया रैंक 20
doing a government job, he is going to
डूइंग अ गवर्नमेंट जॉब, ही इज़ गोइंग टू
Leave it for me. hmm so, you need strong
लीव इट फॉर मी। हम्म सो, यू नीड स्ट्रांग
The Supportive Man in Your Life to Be Able to
सपोर्टिव मैन इन योर लाइफ टू बी एबल टू
For the women to also come forward. do you
फॉर द वीमेन टू आल्सो कम फॉरवर्ड। डू यू
you you you you you you think this is aspiring
यू यू यू यू यू यू थिंक दीज एस्पायरिंग
Content Creator Girls Don't Get That? Off
कंटेंट क्रिएटर गर्ल्स डोंट गेट देट? ऑफ़
Of course, they don't. they don't, they get a lot of
कोर्स, दे डोंट। दे डोंट, दे गेट अ लॉट ऑफ
Scrutiny. they get a lot of don't go out
स्क्रूटनी। दे गेट अ लॉट ऑफ डोंट गो आउट
After 7:00 p.m. Don't do this with this guy.
आफ्टर 7:00 p.m. डोंट डू दिस विद दिस गाय।
I also think my parents are to thank
आई आल्सो थिंक माय पेरेंट्स आर टू थैंक
For it. They allowed me to stay out with
फॉर इट। दे दे अलाउड मी टू स्टे आउट विद
Boys. they allow me to you won't believe it
बॉयज। दे अलाउड मी टू यू वोंट बिलीव इट
Right now. our living condition is really bad
राइट नाउ। आर लिविंग कंडीशन इज़ सच ड्यात
Me my finance and my business lead. I
मी माई फयंनसे एंड माय बिज़नेस लीड। आई
stay with to
स्टे विथ टू
Main. That's so rare. who wood how wood
मेन। दैट सो रेयर। हु वुड हाउ वुड
Do parents allow that? now now I've got
पेरेंट्स अलाउ दैट? नाउ नाउ आई हैव गॉट
My answer. Ya KK Creates was fun. On
माय आंसर। या केके क्रिएट्स मज़ा आ गया। ऑन
To the next one. Ok? we will conclude
टू द नेक्स्ट वन। ठीक है? वी विल कंक्लूड
it's in a more heart felt way in the next
इट इन अ मोर हार्ट फेल्ट वे इन द नेक्स्ट
Episode Because I'm Very Hungry Too
एपिसोड बिकॉज़ आई एम वैरी हंग्री टू
Actually have the hindi conversation with you.
एक्चुअली हैव द हिंदी कन्वर्सेशन विथ यू।
Will work. Ok. thank you for a fantastic
चलेगा। ओके। थैंक यू फॉर अ फैंटास्टिक
Social media episode. Thank you. that was the
सोशल मीडिया एपिसोड। थैंक यू। दैट वाज़ द
Episode for today. Ladies and gentlemen. A
एपिसोड फॉर टुडे। लेडीज एंड जेंटलमैन। अ
This Entire Episode Was An Opportunity
दिस एंटायर एपिसोड वाज़ एन ओपोरर्चुनिटी
for me to learn about social media once
फॉर मी टू लर्न अबाउट सोशल मीडिया वंस
Again it was an opportunity for me too
अगेन इट वास एन ओपोरर्चुनिटी फॉर मी टू
Understand How Genji Content Creators Go
अंडरस्टैंड हाउ जेंजी कंटेंट क्रिएटर्स गो
about their process how their viewing social
अबाउट देयर प्रोसेस हाउ देयर व्यूइंग सोशल
Media Things Change in My Industry
मीडिया थिंग्स चेंज इन माय इंडस्ट्री
every single year i hope that this particular
एव्री सिंगल ईयर आय होप दैट दिस पर्टिकुलर
Episode Travels
एपिसोड ट्रैवल्स
Globally I mean Instagram is the same here
ग्लोबली आई मीन Instagram इज द सेम हियर
As it is abroad the same goes for YouTube the
एज इट इज अब्रॉड सेम गोज़ फॉर YouTube द
Same goes for Twitter and Lindin this is a
सेम गोज़ फॉर Twitter एंड Lindin दिस इज अ
The Kind of Content That’s Every Successful
काइंड ऑफ़ कंटेंट दैट एव्री सक्सेसफुल
Content creator watches at the beginning or at
कंटेंट क्रिएटर वॉचेस एट द बिगिनिंग ओर एट
There's an intermediate stage. remember even if
देयर ओन इंटरमीडिएट स्टेज। रिमेंबर इवन इफ
you are disenchanted with the process of social
यू आर डिसइचंटेड विथ द प्रोसेस ऑफ़ सोशल
Media. Social media is one of two
मीडिया। सोशल मीडिया इज़ वन ऑफ दोज़
Ecosystems and Environments Where You Are
इकोसिस्टम्स एंड एनवायरमेंट्स व्हेयर यू
Get to decide your own faith. you get to
गेट टू डिसाइड योर ओन फेथ। यू गेट टू
Decide your own results. and it will
डिसाइड युवर ओन रिजल्ट्स। एंड इट विल
always boiled down to your own effort and
ऑलवेज बॉइल्ड डाउन टू युवर ओन एफर्ट एंड
Your own sense of learning. that's why we
युवर ओन सेंस ऑफ़ लर्निंग। दैट्स व्हाई वी
Created this episode. I have celebrated
क्रिएटेड दिस एपिसोड। आई हैव सेलिब्रेटेड
Kavya at the start of this episode
काव्या एट द स्टार्ट ऑफ दिस एपिसोड
During the podcast and I celebrate her
ड्यूरिंग द पॉडकास्ट एंड आई सेलिब्रेट हर
At the end as well. She is here to stay.
एट द एंड एज वेल। शी इज हियर टू स्टे।
really do you meet someone who's dissociated
रेली डू यू मीट समवन हुज डिसोटिवेटेड
About the subject of social media. that was
अबाउट द सब्जेक्ट ऑफ सोशल मीडिया। दैट वास
The Theme of Today. I Hope Content Creators
द थीम ऑफ टुडे। आई होप कंटेंट क्रिएटर्स
Gain a lot from this one? and i hope that
गेन अ लॉट फ्रॉम दिस वन? एंड आई होप दैट
Entrepreneurs Gain a Lot from This One Age
एंटरप्रेन्योर गेन अ लॉट फ्रॉम दिस वन एज
well. He is wishing Kavya even more luck, even
वेल। ही इज विशिंग काव्या इवन मोर लक, इवन
More success on her journey. TRS will be
मोर सक्सेस ऑन हर जर्नी। टीआरएस विल बी
Back very soon. thank you so much for listening
बैक वैरी सून। थैंक यू सो मच फॉर लिसनिंग
in.
इन।
[music]
[संगीत]